<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="zh-cn"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://firo.org/firo-site/pr-preview/pr-518/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://firo.org/firo-site/pr-preview/pr-518/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="zh-cn" /><updated>2025-10-02T04:31:45+00:00</updated><id>https://firo.org/firo-site/pr-preview/pr-518/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Firo</title><subtitle>Firo is a cryptocurrency that focuses on privacy and fungibility.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Firo Turns 9!</title><link href="https://firo.org/firo-site/pr-preview/pr-518/2025/09/28/Firo-turns-9.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Firo Turns 9!" /><published>2025-09-28T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-09-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://firo.org/firo-site/pr-preview/pr-518/2025/09/28/Firo-turns-9</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://firo.org/firo-site/pr-preview/pr-518/2025/09/28/Firo-turns-9.html"><![CDATA[<p>As Firo turns 9 years old, we’re not just celebrating a birthday, we’re celebrating the dedication of the community, the resilience of the project, and the progress we’ve made together. From our early days as Zcoin to becoming Firo, we’ve stayed true to one mission: empowering people with financial privacy and building tools that put control back in their hands.</p>

<h2 id="looking-back-at-the-past-year">Looking Back at the Past Year</h2>

<p>This past year has been filled with milestones, innovations, and community-driven growth.</p>

<p><img src="/blog/assets/firo9/sparkname-activated.png" alt="Spark Name" /></p>

<p><strong><a href="/firo-site/pr-preview/pr-518/zh-cn/2025/05/28/sparknames-activated.html">Spark Names</a></strong> - One of the most exciting milestones this past year was the launch of Spark Names. This feature makes it easier for users to interact with Firo’s privacy ecosystem by allowing them to register simple, human-readable identifiers instead of relying on long, complex Spark addresses. Much like usernames, Spark Names improve accessibility and usability while still inheriting the full privacy protections of Lelantus Spark. By lowering the barrier for everyday use, Spark Names are helping to bridge the gap between powerful privacy technology and user-friendly digital cash.</p>

<p><img src="/blog/assets/firo9/pupdonation.png" alt="Power Up Privacy" /></p>

<p><strong><a href="/firo-site/pr-preview/pr-518/zh-cn/2025/04/10/firo-receive-574-xmr-donation-power-up-privacy.html">Power Up Privacy donated 574 XMR</a></strong> to the Firo Team to support our mission and is continuing to donate further funds. These funds will go directly towards strengthening Firo’s development, advancing privacy research, and driving awareness initiatives in the broader ecosystem. A heartfelt thank you to Power Up Privacy for believing in our work and contributing to the growth of privacy technologies. It is the commitment of supporters like you, along with the tireless efforts of the Firofam, that keeps us moving forward.</p>

<p><img src="/blog/assets/firo9/wizardswap-spark.png" alt="WizardSwap Spark Address" /></p>

<p><a href="https://www.wizardswap.io/"><strong>WizardSwap</strong></a> became the first swap provider to integrate Spark addresses and also Instant-Send. This means users can now swap privately and almost instantly with WizardSwap, enjoying Firo’s full privacy protections without needing extra steps. We are seeing strong swap volumes primarily people swapping from XMR into FIRO.</p>

<p><img src="/blog/assets/firo9/confidential-layer.png" alt="confidential layer" /></p>

<p>The partnership with <strong>Confidential Layer</strong>, a non-custodial bridge that enables seamless asset transfers between public blockchains and privacy-preserving blockchains, allows users to move assets securely across chains while retaining the option of privacy when they need it. This is significant because it opens the door to greater interoperability. By connecting Firo’s privacy layer with the broader blockchain ecosystem, this partnership strengthens our vision of making privacy not just a feature, but a standard. It bridges the gap between transparent and private economies, empowering users to choose confidentiality without sacrificing accessibility or usability.</p>

<p><img src="/blog/assets/firo9/firomonerokon2025.jpg" alt="Firo at Monerokon 2025" /></p>

<p>Firo attended <strong>Monerokon 2025 in Prague</strong>, where we were one of the few privacy projects with a dedicated booth. The reception was overwhelmingly positive, with many attendees from the Monero community recognizing Firo as “one of the legit ones.” It was encouraging to see so much interest at our booth, by far one of the most visited. and we look forward to fostering stronger relationships with the Monero community and beyond.</p>

<p>At <strong>ETHDam III</strong>, we explored how privacy coins like Firo can integrate into mainstream adoption without compromising their core values. The talk addressed common myths around privacy coins and highlighted practical solutions for shaping a more private future.
Watch here: <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Ty50kXR--Y8">https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Ty50kXR–Y8</a></p>

<p><strong>Biconomy Exchange listed Firo</strong> with support for Spark address withdrawals. This makes Biconomy the second centralized exchange (first being NonKYC.io with full Spark deposits and withdrawal support)  to enable users to withdraw directly to a Spark address, bringing the benefits of Firo’s cutting-edge privacy protocol to a wider audience.</p>

<p><img src="/blog/assets/firo9/firosyriaoffice.jpg" alt="Syria Firo Office" /></p>

<p>One of the most inspiring milestones this year comes directly from the community. A dedicated member in Syria has begun setting up an <strong>office to educate and onboard people to Firo</strong>, providing hands-on guidance about financial privacy and how to use cryptocurrency in their daily lives. In Syria, citizens are only allowed to withdraw around 500,000 Syrian Pounds (~38 USD) a week from their bank and still face a lot of stigma despite sanctions being lifted. Privacy crypto like Firo provides a practical solution to ease value transfer among ordinary Syrians.</p>

<p><img src="/blog/assets/firo9/Firosyria.png" alt="Syria Firo adoption" /></p>

<p>Beyond education, <strong>real-world adoption is taking shape on the ground</strong>. In Syria, one of the <strong>largest stores in Homs Governorate, Al Dhahik Commercial Complex</strong> that sells essential goods from solar panels to appliances, a <strong>household appliance store, a pharmacy, and a grocery shop</strong> are now accepting FIRO as payment. These businesses are helping to create a practical ecosystem where everyday needs can be met using private digital cash.</p>

<h2 id="a-community-that-makes-it-possible">A Community That Makes It Possible</h2>

<p>At the heart of Firo’s journey is the community. Whether it’s miners securing the network, masternodes operators, serving on the Community Fund Committee, testing new features, helping newcomers, creating Spark Names, or simply spreading the word, every contribution has strengthened the ecosystem. Firo also wouldn’t be here without the support of our partners, who have worked alongside us to advance privacy technology and adoption. To all who have stayed with us, believed in what we do, and contributed in countless ways, old and new, we thank you deeply.</p>

<h2 id="looking-forward">Looking Forward</h2>

<p>As we move into our 10th year, Firo’s mission remains clear: ensuring financial privacy is accessible to all. The road ahead is filled with exciting developments that will push Firo’s technology and usability even further.</p>

<p>Lelantus Spark remains at the core of Firo’s privacy technology, and we will continue to refine and strengthen it. This means ongoing upgrades for performance, security, and usability, ensuring it remains the gold standard in blockchain privacy.</p>

<p><strong>Spark Assets</strong> - Nearing completion, Spark Assets will allow users to issue their own privacy-preserving assets. These assets inherit the same protections as Lelantus Spark, including the ability to hide asset types ensuring full confidentiality. Importantly, all assets - including FIRO itself - contribute to a shared anonymity set, further strengthening privacy for everyone.</p>

<p><strong>Integration into Enkrypt</strong> - a multi-asset Web3 browser extension wallet, with full support for Spark features. This will make it even easier for users to access Firo’s privacy technology without installing or downloading an application.</p>

<p><strong>Curve Trees</strong> - An innovative technique for efficient membership proofs that supports a global anonymity set. This upgrade will substantially improve privacy, scalability, verification speed, and proof size, making Spark even more robust and efficient.</p>

<p>And these are just some of the improvements on the horizon. With community support and ongoing innovation, Firo will continue leading the way in financial privacy while expanding its reach and usability.</p>

<h2 id="closing-thoughts">Closing Thoughts</h2>

<p>Thank you to every member of the Firofam for being part of this journey. Nine years is a huge milestone in crypto, and it’s only possible because of the strength of this community and the vision we share. Here’s to the next chapter, and to building a future where financial privacy is the norm, not the exception.</p>

<p>Happy 9th Birthday, Firo!</p>]]></content><author><name>Augustus Jong</name></author><category term="community" /><category term="news" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[As Firo turns 9 years old, we’re not just celebrating a birthday, we’re celebrating the dedication of the community, the resilience of the project, and the progress we’ve made together. From our early days as Zcoin to becoming Firo, we’ve stayed true to one mission: empowering people with financial privacy and building tools that put control back in their hands. Looking Back at the Past Year This past year has been filled with milestones, innovations, and community-driven growth. Spark Names - One of the most exciting milestones this past year was the launch of Spark Names. This feature makes it easier for users to interact with Firo’s privacy ecosystem by allowing them to register simple, human-readable identifiers instead of relying on long, complex Spark addresses. Much like usernames, Spark Names improve accessibility and usability while still inheriting the full privacy protections of Lelantus Spark. By lowering the barrier for everyday use, Spark Names are helping to bridge the gap between powerful privacy technology and user-friendly digital cash. Power Up Privacy donated 574 XMR to the Firo Team to support our mission and is continuing to donate further funds. These funds will go directly towards strengthening Firo’s development, advancing privacy research, and driving awareness initiatives in the broader ecosystem. A heartfelt thank you to Power Up Privacy for believing in our work and contributing to the growth of privacy technologies. It is the commitment of supporters like you, along with the tireless efforts of the Firofam, that keeps us moving forward. WizardSwap became the first swap provider to integrate Spark addresses and also Instant-Send. This means users can now swap privately and almost instantly with WizardSwap, enjoying Firo’s full privacy protections without needing extra steps. We are seeing strong swap volumes primarily people swapping from XMR into FIRO. The partnership with Confidential Layer, a non-custodial bridge that enables seamless asset transfers between public blockchains and privacy-preserving blockchains, allows users to move assets securely across chains while retaining the option of privacy when they need it. This is significant because it opens the door to greater interoperability. By connecting Firo’s privacy layer with the broader blockchain ecosystem, this partnership strengthens our vision of making privacy not just a feature, but a standard. It bridges the gap between transparent and private economies, empowering users to choose confidentiality without sacrificing accessibility or usability. Firo attended Monerokon 2025 in Prague, where we were one of the few privacy projects with a dedicated booth. The reception was overwhelmingly positive, with many attendees from the Monero community recognizing Firo as “one of the legit ones.” It was encouraging to see so much interest at our booth, by far one of the most visited. and we look forward to fostering stronger relationships with the Monero community and beyond. At ETHDam III, we explored how privacy coins like Firo can integrate into mainstream adoption without compromising their core values. The talk addressed common myths around privacy coins and highlighted practical solutions for shaping a more private future. Watch here: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Ty50kXR–Y8 Biconomy Exchange listed Firo with support for Spark address withdrawals. This makes Biconomy the second centralized exchange (first being NonKYC.io with full Spark deposits and withdrawal support) to enable users to withdraw directly to a Spark address, bringing the benefits of Firo’s cutting-edge privacy protocol to a wider audience. One of the most inspiring milestones this year comes directly from the community. A dedicated member in Syria has begun setting up an office to educate and onboard people to Firo, providing hands-on guidance about financial privacy and how to use cryptocurrency in their daily lives. In Syria, citizens are only allowed to withdraw around 500,000 Syrian Pounds (~38 USD) a week from their bank and still face a lot of stigma despite sanctions being lifted. Privacy crypto like Firo provides a practical solution to ease value transfer among ordinary Syrians. Beyond education, real-world adoption is taking shape on the ground. In Syria, one of the largest stores in Homs Governorate, Al Dhahik Commercial Complex that sells essential goods from solar panels to appliances, a household appliance store, a pharmacy, and a grocery shop are now accepting FIRO as payment. These businesses are helping to create a practical ecosystem where everyday needs can be met using private digital cash. A Community That Makes It Possible At the heart of Firo’s journey is the community. Whether it’s miners securing the network, masternodes operators, serving on the Community Fund Committee, testing new features, helping newcomers, creating Spark Names, or simply spreading the word, every contribution has strengthened the ecosystem. Firo also wouldn’t be here without the support of our partners, who have worked alongside us to advance privacy technology and adoption. To all who have stayed with us, believed in what we do, and contributed in countless ways, old and new, we thank you deeply. Looking Forward As we move into our 10th year, Firo’s mission remains clear: ensuring financial privacy is accessible to all. The road ahead is filled with exciting developments that will push Firo’s technology and usability even further. Lelantus Spark remains at the core of Firo’s privacy technology, and we will continue to refine and strengthen it. This means ongoing upgrades for performance, security, and usability, ensuring it remains the gold standard in blockchain privacy. Spark Assets - Nearing completion, Spark Assets will allow users to issue their own privacy-preserving assets. These assets inherit the same protections as Lelantus Spark, including the ability to hide asset types ensuring full confidentiality. Importantly, all assets - including FIRO itself - contribute to a shared anonymity set, further strengthening privacy for everyone. Integration into Enkrypt - a multi-asset Web3 browser extension wallet, with full support for Spark features. This will make it even easier for users to access Firo’s privacy technology without installing or downloading an application. Curve Trees - An innovative technique for efficient membership proofs that supports a global anonymity set. This upgrade will substantially improve privacy, scalability, verification speed, and proof size, making Spark even more robust and efficient. And these are just some of the improvements on the horizon. With community support and ongoing innovation, Firo will continue leading the way in financial privacy while expanding its reach and usability. Closing Thoughts Thank you to every member of the Firofam for being part of this journey. Nine years is a huge milestone in crypto, and it’s only possible because of the strength of this community and the vision we share. Here’s to the next chapter, and to building a future where financial privacy is the norm, not the exception. Happy 9th Birthday, Firo!]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The 4th term of CFC members are formed!</title><link href="https://firo.org/firo-site/pr-preview/pr-518/2025/09/07/4th-term-cfc-members-formed.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The 4th term of CFC members are formed!" /><published>2025-09-07T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-09-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://firo.org/firo-site/pr-preview/pr-518/2025/09/07/4th-term-cfc-members-formed</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://firo.org/firo-site/pr-preview/pr-518/2025/09/07/4th-term-cfc-members-formed.html"><![CDATA[<p>The 7 member Community Fund Committee (“CFC”) is formed to oversee the Firo Community Fund (“FCF”) has been completed!</p>

<p>The following community members will serve as CFC members for a period of 1 year:</p>

<ul>
  <li>Firofan</li>
  <li>Rehrar</li>
  <li>Jagmot</li>
  <li>Fiendish</li>
  <li>Nrsimha</li>
  <li>Ddadybayo</li>
  <li>Centaurea</li>
</ul>

<p>The newly elected committee brings together long-standing community members, technical experts, and developers who have consistently participated in proposal reviews and guided the allocation of the Firo Community Fund.</p>

<p>We would like to extend our gratitude to the newly elected members for serving on the Firo Community Fund (FCF) and for contributing to the decentralization of funding decisions. We also sincerely thank the outgoing committee members for their dedication and service to the project.</p>

<h2 id="how-to-apply-for-funding-from-the-firo-community-fund">How to apply for funding from the Firo Community Fund</h2>

<p>Anyone is welcome to request funding from the FCF by submitting a proposal through the <a href="https://funding.firo.org/">Firo Crowdfunding System</a> and opening a <a href="https://forum.firo.org/c/fcs-proposals/16">forum thread</a> to invite community discussion. In addition, the Community Fund Committee has the authority to put forward proposals of their own for consideration.</p>

<h2 id="what-are-the-responsibilities-of-the-community-fund-committee">What are the responsibilities of the Community Fund Committee?</h2>

<ol>
  <li>To decide along with taking into account community feedback on how the Firo Community Fund should be utilised.</li>
  <li>To help evaluate community requests for funding, do due diligence of applicants applying for funding and obtain all necessary information to ensure sufficient detail for scope of work.</li>
  <li>To evaluate and approve payment of milestone requests.</li>
  <li>To make all reasonings of the CFC for approval/rejection public.</li>
  <li>CFC can request for the core team’s feedback and opinion on proposals.</li>
  <li>To always conduct themselves with professionalism without resorting to personal attacks or insults.</li>
</ol>

<h2 id="how-will-the-firo-community-fund-fcf-be-utilised">How will the Firo Community Fund (FCF) be utilised?</h2>

<ol>
  <li>FCF funds must always be utilised for the benefit of Firo. Research, development or promotional activities that do not directly benefit Firo should not be undertaken.</li>
  <li>All FCF expenditure has to be disclosed. Any proposal that does not allow this will not be able to be funded from the FCF.</li>
  <li>FCF funds should not be used for giveaways even for the purpose of promoting adoption or participation.</li>
  <li>FCF funds should not be used to host purely social events. Educational or awareness events are acceptable but must be the primary component of the event.</li>
  <li>FCF funds should be used and while there shouldn’t be a pressure to spend funds, the FCF should not be hoarded.</li>
  <li>CFC can choose to use the FCF to employ contractors to embark on specific tasks or roles that will report directly to the CFC.</li>
  <li>Should the CFC deem fit, FCF funds can be burnt by sending it to this <a href="https://explorer.firo.org/address/aFiroBurningAddressDoNotSendrPtjYA">burn address</a>.</li>
  <li>FCF funds address can be viewed <a href="https://explorer.firo.org/address/aFA2TbqG9cnhhzX5Yny2pBJRK5EaEqLCH7">here</a>.</li>
</ol>

<h2 id="where-can-i-see-the-deliberations-of-the-community-fund-committee">Where can I see the deliberations of the Community Fund Committee?</h2>

<p>All discussions of the CFC can be seen in our <a href="https://discord.gg/TGZPRbRT3Y">Discord</a> in the channel #communityfund or The <a href="https://t.me/firocfc">CFC telegram group</a> and is read-only. You will need to have verified status by passing the captcha to view the channel.</p>]]></content><author><name>Augustus Jong</name></author><category term="community" /><category term="news" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The 7 member Community Fund Committee (“CFC”) is formed to oversee the Firo Community Fund (“FCF”) has been completed! The following community members will serve as CFC members for a period of 1 year: Firofan Rehrar Jagmot Fiendish Nrsimha Ddadybayo Centaurea The newly elected committee brings together long-standing community members, technical experts, and developers who have consistently participated in proposal reviews and guided the allocation of the Firo Community Fund. We would like to extend our gratitude to the newly elected members for serving on the Firo Community Fund (FCF) and for contributing to the decentralization of funding decisions. We also sincerely thank the outgoing committee members for their dedication and service to the project. How to apply for funding from the Firo Community Fund Anyone is welcome to request funding from the FCF by submitting a proposal through the Firo Crowdfunding System and opening a forum thread to invite community discussion. In addition, the Community Fund Committee has the authority to put forward proposals of their own for consideration. What are the responsibilities of the Community Fund Committee? To decide along with taking into account community feedback on how the Firo Community Fund should be utilised. To help evaluate community requests for funding, do due diligence of applicants applying for funding and obtain all necessary information to ensure sufficient detail for scope of work. To evaluate and approve payment of milestone requests. To make all reasonings of the CFC for approval/rejection public. CFC can request for the core team’s feedback and opinion on proposals. To always conduct themselves with professionalism without resorting to personal attacks or insults. How will the Firo Community Fund (FCF) be utilised? FCF funds must always be utilised for the benefit of Firo. Research, development or promotional activities that do not directly benefit Firo should not be undertaken. All FCF expenditure has to be disclosed. Any proposal that does not allow this will not be able to be funded from the FCF. FCF funds should not be used for giveaways even for the purpose of promoting adoption or participation. FCF funds should not be used to host purely social events. Educational or awareness events are acceptable but must be the primary component of the event. FCF funds should be used and while there shouldn’t be a pressure to spend funds, the FCF should not be hoarded. CFC can choose to use the FCF to employ contractors to embark on specific tasks or roles that will report directly to the CFC. Should the CFC deem fit, FCF funds can be burnt by sending it to this burn address. FCF funds address can be viewed here. Where can I see the deliberations of the Community Fund Committee? All discussions of the CFC can be seen in our Discord in the channel #communityfund or The CFC telegram group and is read-only. You will need to have verified status by passing the captcha to view the channel.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Nomination Thread for a New Community Fund Committee 2025</title><link href="https://firo.org/firo-site/pr-preview/pr-518/2025/06/04/firo-cfc-nomination-4th-term.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Nomination Thread for a New Community Fund Committee 2025" /><published>2025-06-04T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-06-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://firo.org/firo-site/pr-preview/pr-518/2025/06/04/firo-cfc-nomination-4th-term</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://firo.org/firo-site/pr-preview/pr-518/2025/06/04/firo-cfc-nomination-4th-term.html"><![CDATA[<p>The 3rd CFC Committee has completed its one-year term, and we now invite nominations for the 4th CFC. This elected group plays a vital role in decentralizing Firo’s governance by overseeing the Firo Community Fund (FCF), which supports critical initiatives like ecosystem development, security audits, marketing efforts, and core team resources when needed.</p>

<p>To apply, please introduce yourself in the nomination thread below. Share your background, your reasons for joining the CFC, and your experience within the Firo community. Active participation and a commitment to Firo’s growth are essential—all motivated members, including past committee participants, are encouraged to stand for election.</p>

<p>Nomination Thread: <a href="https://forum.firo.org/t/nominations-for-the-4th-community-fund-committee-cfc-are-now-open/4046">https://forum.firo.org/t/nominations-for-the-4th-community-fund-committee-cfc-are-now-open/4046</a></p>

<p>The CFC’s work ensures transparency and community-driven stewardship of Firo’s resources. We look forward to your applications!</p>

<p>Below is a reminder of the role of the CFC and the Firo Community Fund (FCF) it manages:</p>

<h2 id="brief-summary-of-how-the-cfc-came-to-be">Brief summary of how the CFC came to be</h2>

<p>Firo conducted a series of community votes to adjust its tokenomics and established the Firo Community Fund. This process spanned several months and involved multiple vetted polls to ensure alignment with the community’s wishes. A committee comprising seven elected community members was established to manage fund allocation.</p>

<p>Following the nomination phase, nominees (who are new) undergo a vetting process, including an interview, to assess their eligibility and alignment with the community’s voting objectives. The interview, which can be conducted through text or online meetings, delves into the nominees’ beliefs in Firo, their grasp of Firo’s technology, personal background (without revealing sensitive information), and their vision for the fund’s utilization. Nominees not widely known in the community must provide proof of active participation for at least a year.</p>

<p>Moving on from these specifics, it’s essential to outline the responsibilities and prerequisites expected of a member of the Firo Community Fund Committee (CFC).</p>

<h2 id="responsibilities-of-community-fund-committee-members">Responsibilities of Community Fund Committee members</h2>

<ol>
  <li>To decide along with taking into account community feedback on how the community fund should be utilized.</li>
  <li>To help evaluate community requests for funding, do due diligence on applicants applying for funding, and obtain all necessary information to ensure sufficient detail for the scope of work.</li>
  <li>To evaluate and approve payment of milestone requests</li>
  <li>To make all reasoning of the CFC for approval/rejection public</li>
  <li>CFC can request for core team’s feedback and opinion on proposals.</li>
  <li>To always conduct themselves with professionalism without resorting to personal attacks or insults.</li>
</ol>

<p>Minimum requirements to be eligible to be a committee member</p>

<ol>
  <li>Be a recognized and active community member of Firo for at least a year, OR a recognized industry expert/specialist.</li>
  <li>Solid understanding of Firo’s technology stack and current roadmap and goals</li>
  <li>Cannot be a current full-time member of the Firo core team. Part-time contributors or contractors of Firo’s core team are allowed but must be disclosed.</li>
  <li>Be able to attend a CFC meeting once a month or appoint a proxy to do the same (though proxies should be used sparingly).</li>
  <li>While a technical or development background isn’t required, having a few committee members with some technical background would be helpful in evaluating proposals.</li>
  <li>Be able to read, check and vote on proposals for funding at least once a week.</li>
  <li>Be 18 years old and above.</li>
</ol>

<h2 id="removal-of-cfc-members">Removal of CFC Members</h2>

<ol>
  <li>If a CFC member is suspected or found to have been involved in fraud or scam or other deceitful behavior, the other CFC members can vote to remove them via majority vote.</li>
  <li>If a CFC member has acted in a manner that is an unbecoming or unprofessional manner, the other CFC members can vote to remove them via a majority vote.</li>
  <li>If a CFC member is absent for 2 meetings in a row without due cause, they shall be removed automatically.</li>
  <li>If a CFC member has continuously failed to vote on proposals for funding, a vote shall be held at the next CFC meeting by the other CFC members on whether to remove them.</li>
  <li>If a CFC member is removed, nominations should be open for the spot for the remaining term.</li>
</ol>

<h2 id="meetings-quorums-and-voting">Meetings, Quorums, and Voting</h2>

<ol>
  <li>A meeting should be held at least once a month with CFC members. The purpose of this meeting is to discuss proposals or to choose how to allocate the FCF funds or any other matters arising. Given CFC members may be in different time zones, this should be taken into account when determining the time of the meeting and the opportunity to take turns for amenable timing.</li>
  <li>Core team members or their representatives should always be allowed to observe and attend all CFC meetings, but shall not have a vote unless otherwise specified.</li>
  <li>The minutes of these meetings shall always be publicly available.</li>
  <li>The meeting can be conducted by text or online meetings.</li>
  <li>A quorum should be 5 members. Votes are passed using a majority of votes. In the event of an equality of votes, the core team shall have a casting vote.
6Proposals for funding can be approved without the need for a meeting and shall be voted on in the proposal thread itself.</li>
  <li>When voting for or against a proposal for funding, all CFC members are required to state the reasoning behind their choice.
8Anyone can open a proposal for funding, including CFC members.</li>
  <li>If a CFC member is an applicant for funding, the member cannot vote on that proposal. Also, if a CFC member has a close relationship (e.g. family member, best friend, significant other, spouse) with the applicant for funding, the CFC member should disclose the relationship and put it to the other CFC members to decide whether the member should be allowed to vote or choose to abstain voluntarily.</li>
  <li>If the CFC wishes to make funds available to the core team to assist them (for instance to cover a shortfall or to pay for a specific employee to retain them), a higher vote threshold is required, which is 5 members out of 7 instead of the usual majority of votes.</li>
</ol>

<h2 id="general-guidelines-to-community-fund-usage">General Guidelines to Community Fund Usage</h2>
<ol>
  <li>Trust needs to be earned. While anyone can propose to be funded from the FCF, the person’s track record needs to be evaluated, the necessary due diligence needs to be taken, and milestone payments adjusted appropriately.</li>
  <li>The CFC can choose to employ contractors to embark on specific tasks, but shall seek community feedback. Where it involves core code, the CFC has to consult the core team.</li>
  <li>The CFC should not be used to host parties or purely social events. Educational or awareness events are okay but should be done with appropriate evidence and not paid upfront.</li>
  <li>The CFC is to be used and while there shouldn’t be pressure to spend the CFC funds, the CFC funds shouldn’t be hoarded.
5CFC funds should always be utilized for the benefit of Firo. Research or development that does not directly benefit Firo should not be undertaken.</li>
  <li>CFC funds should not be used for giveaways, even for the purpose of promoting adoption or participation. These have limited effects.</li>
  <li>All CFC expenditure has to be disclosed. Contractors that prohibit this should not be engaged.</li>
  <li>Should the CFC deem fit, FCF funds can be burnt by sending them to this burn address. (https://explorer.firo.org/address/aFiroBurningAddressDoNotSendrPtjYA)</li>
  <li>FCF funds address can be viewed here which are from time to time anonymized.</li>
  <li>Utilization of CFC funds and proposals can always be viewed on the Firo Community Crowdfunding page under the category of CFC.</li>
</ol>

<h2 id="what-the-cfc-is-not">What the CFC is NOT</h2>
<ol>
  <li>The CFC are NOT representatives of the opinion of the Firo Community. They are only tasked with matters to do with the Community Fund and do not replace the usual process of getting feedback from the general community and core team in implementing large changes.</li>
  <li>The CFC shall not represent itself as core team members or as representatives of the project.</li>
</ol>]]></content><author><name>Augustus Jong</name></author><category term="announcement" /><category term="news" /><category term="community" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The 3rd CFC Committee has completed its one-year term, and we now invite nominations for the 4th CFC. This elected group plays a vital role in decentralizing Firo’s governance by overseeing the Firo Community Fund (FCF), which supports critical initiatives like ecosystem development, security audits, marketing efforts, and core team resources when needed. To apply, please introduce yourself in the nomination thread below. Share your background, your reasons for joining the CFC, and your experience within the Firo community. Active participation and a commitment to Firo’s growth are essential—all motivated members, including past committee participants, are encouraged to stand for election. Nomination Thread: https://forum.firo.org/t/nominations-for-the-4th-community-fund-committee-cfc-are-now-open/4046 The CFC’s work ensures transparency and community-driven stewardship of Firo’s resources. We look forward to your applications! Below is a reminder of the role of the CFC and the Firo Community Fund (FCF) it manages: Brief summary of how the CFC came to be Firo conducted a series of community votes to adjust its tokenomics and established the Firo Community Fund. This process spanned several months and involved multiple vetted polls to ensure alignment with the community’s wishes. A committee comprising seven elected community members was established to manage fund allocation. Following the nomination phase, nominees (who are new) undergo a vetting process, including an interview, to assess their eligibility and alignment with the community’s voting objectives. The interview, which can be conducted through text or online meetings, delves into the nominees’ beliefs in Firo, their grasp of Firo’s technology, personal background (without revealing sensitive information), and their vision for the fund’s utilization. Nominees not widely known in the community must provide proof of active participation for at least a year. Moving on from these specifics, it’s essential to outline the responsibilities and prerequisites expected of a member of the Firo Community Fund Committee (CFC). Responsibilities of Community Fund Committee members To decide along with taking into account community feedback on how the community fund should be utilized. To help evaluate community requests for funding, do due diligence on applicants applying for funding, and obtain all necessary information to ensure sufficient detail for the scope of work. To evaluate and approve payment of milestone requests To make all reasoning of the CFC for approval/rejection public CFC can request for core team’s feedback and opinion on proposals. To always conduct themselves with professionalism without resorting to personal attacks or insults. Minimum requirements to be eligible to be a committee member Be a recognized and active community member of Firo for at least a year, OR a recognized industry expert/specialist. Solid understanding of Firo’s technology stack and current roadmap and goals Cannot be a current full-time member of the Firo core team. Part-time contributors or contractors of Firo’s core team are allowed but must be disclosed. Be able to attend a CFC meeting once a month or appoint a proxy to do the same (though proxies should be used sparingly). While a technical or development background isn’t required, having a few committee members with some technical background would be helpful in evaluating proposals. Be able to read, check and vote on proposals for funding at least once a week. Be 18 years old and above. Removal of CFC Members If a CFC member is suspected or found to have been involved in fraud or scam or other deceitful behavior, the other CFC members can vote to remove them via majority vote. If a CFC member has acted in a manner that is an unbecoming or unprofessional manner, the other CFC members can vote to remove them via a majority vote. If a CFC member is absent for 2 meetings in a row without due cause, they shall be removed automatically. If a CFC member has continuously failed to vote on proposals for funding, a vote shall be held at the next CFC meeting by the other CFC members on whether to remove them. If a CFC member is removed, nominations should be open for the spot for the remaining term. Meetings, Quorums, and Voting A meeting should be held at least once a month with CFC members. The purpose of this meeting is to discuss proposals or to choose how to allocate the FCF funds or any other matters arising. Given CFC members may be in different time zones, this should be taken into account when determining the time of the meeting and the opportunity to take turns for amenable timing. Core team members or their representatives should always be allowed to observe and attend all CFC meetings, but shall not have a vote unless otherwise specified. The minutes of these meetings shall always be publicly available. The meeting can be conducted by text or online meetings. A quorum should be 5 members. Votes are passed using a majority of votes. In the event of an equality of votes, the core team shall have a casting vote. 6Proposals for funding can be approved without the need for a meeting and shall be voted on in the proposal thread itself. When voting for or against a proposal for funding, all CFC members are required to state the reasoning behind their choice. 8Anyone can open a proposal for funding, including CFC members. If a CFC member is an applicant for funding, the member cannot vote on that proposal. Also, if a CFC member has a close relationship (e.g. family member, best friend, significant other, spouse) with the applicant for funding, the CFC member should disclose the relationship and put it to the other CFC members to decide whether the member should be allowed to vote or choose to abstain voluntarily. If the CFC wishes to make funds available to the core team to assist them (for instance to cover a shortfall or to pay for a specific employee to retain them), a higher vote threshold is required, which is 5 members out of 7 instead of the usual majority of votes. General Guidelines to Community Fund Usage Trust needs to be earned. While anyone can propose to be funded from the FCF, the person’s track record needs to be evaluated, the necessary due diligence needs to be taken, and milestone payments adjusted appropriately. The CFC can choose to employ contractors to embark on specific tasks, but shall seek community feedback. Where it involves core code, the CFC has to consult the core team. The CFC should not be used to host parties or purely social events. Educational or awareness events are okay but should be done with appropriate evidence and not paid upfront. The CFC is to be used and while there shouldn’t be pressure to spend the CFC funds, the CFC funds shouldn’t be hoarded. 5CFC funds should always be utilized for the benefit of Firo. Research or development that does not directly benefit Firo should not be undertaken. CFC funds should not be used for giveaways, even for the purpose of promoting adoption or participation. These have limited effects. All CFC expenditure has to be disclosed. Contractors that prohibit this should not be engaged. Should the CFC deem fit, FCF funds can be burnt by sending them to this burn address. (https://explorer.firo.org/address/aFiroBurningAddressDoNotSendrPtjYA) FCF funds address can be viewed here which are from time to time anonymized. Utilization of CFC funds and proposals can always be viewed on the Firo Community Crowdfunding page under the category of CFC. What the CFC is NOT The CFC are NOT representatives of the opinion of the Firo Community. They are only tasked with matters to do with the Community Fund and do not replace the usual process of getting feedback from the general community and core team in implementing large changes. The CFC shall not represent itself as core team members or as representatives of the project.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Spark Names Now Live on Mainnet!</title><link href="https://firo.org/firo-site/pr-preview/pr-518/2025/05/28/sparknames-activated.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Spark Names Now Live on Mainnet!" /><published>2025-05-28T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-05-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://firo.org/firo-site/pr-preview/pr-518/2025/05/28/sparknames-activated</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://firo.org/firo-site/pr-preview/pr-518/2025/05/28/sparknames-activated.html"><![CDATA[<p>We’re thrilled to announce that Spark Names have officially activated on Firo’s mainnet!</p>

<p>This highly anticipated upgrade brings human-readable addresses to Firo’s privacy ecosystem, allowing users to send and receive funds with simple aliases like @sparky—all while maintaining the full anonymity of Lelantus Spark.</p>

<h2 id="why-this-matters">Why This Matters</h2>

<ul>
  <li><strong>Easier Transactions</strong>: No more copying long, complex addresses.</li>
  <li><strong>Enhanced Privacy</strong>: Spark Names work seamlessly with Firo’s Spark transactions.</li>
  <li><strong>Fewer Errors</strong>: Reduce mistakes when sharing payment details.</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="how-to-get-started">How to Get Started</h2>

<p>1) Update your QT wallet to the latest version <a href="https://github.com/firoorg/firo/releases/tag/v0.14.14.1">v0.14.14.1.</a> (Campfire on Android and iOS updates are currently rolling out. Please update to the latest on the PlayStore/AppStore)
2) Register your Spark Name and start using it for private transactions.</p>

<h2 id="learn-more">Learn More</h2>

<p>Need more information about Spark Names? Exploring the resources below:</p>

<ul>
  <li><a href="/firo-site/pr-preview/pr-518/zh-cn/2025/01/28/spark-names.html">Introduction to Spark Names</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://forum.firo.org/t/new-proposed-feature-spark-names-aliases/3398">Community Discussion and Feedback</a></li>
</ul>

<h2 id="whats-next">What’s Next?</h2>

<p>We’ll be hosting a community event to celebrate this milestone—stay tuned for details!</p>]]></content><author><name>Augustus Jong</name></author><category term="dev" /><category term="news" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[We’re thrilled to announce that Spark Names have officially activated on Firo’s mainnet! This highly anticipated upgrade brings human-readable addresses to Firo’s privacy ecosystem, allowing users to send and receive funds with simple aliases like @sparky—all while maintaining the full anonymity of Lelantus Spark. Why This Matters Easier Transactions: No more copying long, complex addresses. Enhanced Privacy: Spark Names work seamlessly with Firo’s Spark transactions. Fewer Errors: Reduce mistakes when sharing payment details. How to Get Started 1) Update your QT wallet to the latest version v0.14.14.1. (Campfire on Android and iOS updates are currently rolling out. Please update to the latest on the PlayStore/AppStore) 2) Register your Spark Name and start using it for private transactions. Learn More Need more information about Spark Names? Exploring the resources below: Introduction to Spark Names Community Discussion and Feedback What’s Next? We’ll be hosting a community event to celebrate this milestone—stay tuned for details!]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Firo, Live on Bison Wallet DEX</title><link href="https://firo.org/firo-site/pr-preview/pr-518/2025/05/07/firo-live-on-bison-wallet.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Firo, Live on Bison Wallet DEX" /><published>2025-05-07T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-05-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://firo.org/firo-site/pr-preview/pr-518/2025/05/07/firo-live-on-bison-wallet</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://firo.org/firo-site/pr-preview/pr-518/2025/05/07/firo-live-on-bison-wallet.html"><![CDATA[<p>Firo is now available on Bison Wallet, a community-driven, self-custodial wallet within the Decred ecosystem that enables secure, private, and trustless trading via DCRDEX.</p>

<p>This integration means the Firofam can:</p>
<ul>
  <li><strong>Trade peer-to-peer via atomic swaps</strong> – Trade directly peer-to-peer via atomic swaps. No intermediaries, no custodial risk</li>
  <li><strong>Maintain full self-custody</strong> – Your keys, your coins</li>
  <li><strong>Access enhanced privacy features</strong></li>
  <li><strong>Enjoy cost-effective trading</strong>  – Ultra-low transaction fees on most chains</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="why-this-matters-for-firo">Why This Matters for Firo</h2>

<p>Bison Wallet aligns perfectly with Firo’s values:</p>
<ul>
  <li><strong>Decentralization</strong> – No reliance on centralized exchanges</li>
  <li><strong>Privacy</strong> – Trade without KYC or surveillance</li>
  <li><strong>User sovereignty</strong> – Full control over your assets</li>
</ul>

<p><img src="/blog/assets/firobisonwallet/img1.png" alt="Bison Wallet UI" /></p>

<h2 id="about-bison-wallet">About Bison Wallet</h2>

<p>Bison Wallet is a non-custodial wallet built for:</p>
<ul>
  <li>DCRDEX integration (trustless atomic swaps)</li>
  <li>DeFi &amp; staking (including DCR staking)</li>
  <li>Enhanced privacy in trading</li>
</ul>

<p>By adding Firo, Bison expands its support for privacy-focused assets, reinforcing its commitment to financial privacy.</p>

<h2 id="how-to-get-started">How to Get Started</h2>
<ol>
  <li>Download <a href="https://bisonwallet.org/#download">Bison Wallet</a></li>
  <li>Configure wallets</li>
  <li>Pay bond</li>
  <li>Start trading</li>
</ol>

<p>A guide is provided on how to trade on Bison wallet <a href="https://firo.org/guide/trading-firo-on-bisonwallet.html">Here</a></p>

<h2 id="acknowledgments">Acknowledgments</h2>

<p>A huge thanks to our Firofam, Devwarrior, for spearheading the integration efforts. We’re also grateful to the Decred community for their collaboration in bringing Firo to Bison Wallet—a significant milestone for privacy-focused, self-custodial trading.</p>]]></content><author><name>Augustus Jong</name></author><category term="community" /><category term="news" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Firo is now available on Bison Wallet, a community-driven, self-custodial wallet within the Decred ecosystem that enables secure, private, and trustless trading via DCRDEX. This integration means the Firofam can: Trade peer-to-peer via atomic swaps – Trade directly peer-to-peer via atomic swaps. No intermediaries, no custodial risk Maintain full self-custody – Your keys, your coins Access enhanced privacy features Enjoy cost-effective trading – Ultra-low transaction fees on most chains Why This Matters for Firo Bison Wallet aligns perfectly with Firo’s values: Decentralization – No reliance on centralized exchanges Privacy – Trade without KYC or surveillance User sovereignty – Full control over your assets About Bison Wallet Bison Wallet is a non-custodial wallet built for: DCRDEX integration (trustless atomic swaps) DeFi &amp; staking (including DCR staking) Enhanced privacy in trading By adding Firo, Bison expands its support for privacy-focused assets, reinforcing its commitment to financial privacy. How to Get Started Download Bison Wallet Configure wallets Pay bond Start trading A guide is provided on how to trade on Bison wallet Here Acknowledgments A huge thanks to our Firofam, Devwarrior, for spearheading the integration efforts. We’re also grateful to the Decred community for their collaboration in bringing Firo to Bison Wallet—a significant milestone for privacy-focused, self-custodial trading.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">WizardSwap.io Integrates Firo Spark Addresses</title><link href="https://firo.org/firo-site/pr-preview/pr-518/2025/04/27/wizardswapio-intergrates-spark-addresses.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="WizardSwap.io Integrates Firo Spark Addresses" /><published>2025-04-27T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-04-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://firo.org/firo-site/pr-preview/pr-518/2025/04/27/wizardswapio-intergrates-spark-addresses</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://firo.org/firo-site/pr-preview/pr-518/2025/04/27/wizardswapio-intergrates-spark-addresses.html"><![CDATA[<p>Firo’s Spark addresses have reached a new milestone with WizardSwap becoming the first instant swap provider to support private Spark transactions! This integration brings seamless privacy to cryptocurrency swaps without accounts, signups, or KYC.</p>

<p>With this integration, you can now:</p>

<ul>
  <li><strong>Swap to/from Spark addresses</strong> – Send and receive fully private Firo transactions</li>
  <li><strong>Stay completely anonymous</strong> – WizardSwap requires no registration, accounts, or personal data</li>
</ul>

<p>This makes private crypto swaps as easy as using a regular exchange – but without sacrificing anonymity.</p>

<h2 id="about-wizardswap">About WizardSwap</h2>

<p><a href="https://www.wizardswap.io/">WizardSwap</a> is a non-custodial instant swap service that offers:</p>

<ul>
  <li><strong>Truly permissionless swaps</strong> – No signups, no KYC</li>
  <li><strong>Fast exchanges between cryptocurrencies</strong></li>
  <li><strong>Operates its own blockchain nodes and wallets</strong> – No dependency on exchanges</li>
</ul>

<p>By adding Spark address support, WizardSwap aligns with Firo’s vision of private, accessible cryptocurrency transactions.</p>

<h2 id="how-to-use-spark-addresses-on-wizardswap">How to Use Spark Addresses on WizardSwap</h2>

<ol>
  <li>Prepare a Firo wallet with Spark support (QT, Campfire, or Stack Wallet)</li>
  <li>Select Firo (Spark) as your receive address when swapping</li>
  <li>Complete your swap – Your transaction stays private from start to finish</li>
</ol>

<p>WizardSwap currently supports FIRO, BTC, XMR, ETH, LTC, DASH, PIVX, PART and ZEC.</p>]]></content><author><name>Augustus Jong</name></author><category term="community" /><category term="news" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Firo’s Spark addresses have reached a new milestone with WizardSwap becoming the first instant swap provider to support private Spark transactions! This integration brings seamless privacy to cryptocurrency swaps without accounts, signups, or KYC. With this integration, you can now: Swap to/from Spark addresses – Send and receive fully private Firo transactions Stay completely anonymous – WizardSwap requires no registration, accounts, or personal data This makes private crypto swaps as easy as using a regular exchange – but without sacrificing anonymity. About WizardSwap WizardSwap is a non-custodial instant swap service that offers: Truly permissionless swaps – No signups, no KYC Fast exchanges between cryptocurrencies Operates its own blockchain nodes and wallets – No dependency on exchanges By adding Spark address support, WizardSwap aligns with Firo’s vision of private, accessible cryptocurrency transactions. How to Use Spark Addresses on WizardSwap Prepare a Firo wallet with Spark support (QT, Campfire, or Stack Wallet) Select Firo (Spark) as your receive address when swapping Complete your swap – Your transaction stays private from start to finish WizardSwap currently supports FIRO, BTC, XMR, ETH, LTC, DASH, PIVX, PART and ZEC.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Spark Names is Launching on Firo Mainnet!</title><link href="https://firo.org/firo-site/pr-preview/pr-518/2025/04/20/spark-names-activating-on-mainet.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Spark Names is Launching on Firo Mainnet!" /><published>2025-04-20T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-04-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://firo.org/firo-site/pr-preview/pr-518/2025/04/20/spark-names-activating-on-mainet</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://firo.org/firo-site/pr-preview/pr-518/2025/04/20/spark-names-activating-on-mainet.html"><![CDATA[<p>We’re thrilled to announce that <strong>Spark Names</strong> will be activated on the Firo mainnet at approximately <strong>block 1,104,500</strong>, expected around <strong>28 May 2025</strong>. To smoothly transition, all users are required to upgrade to <strong>Firo v0.14.14.1</strong>.</p>

<h2 id="what-are-spark-names">What are Spark Names?</h2>

<p>Spark Names simplify Firo addresses by allowing users to register unique, easy-to-remember aliases instead of long cryptographic addresses. This innovation makes sending and receiving FIRO intuitive, convenient, and less prone to error.</p>

<h2 id="supporting-the-community">Supporting the Community</h2>

<p>Registration fees from Spark Names directly contribute to the <strong>Firo Community Fund</strong>, actively supporting ongoing development, ecosystem growth, and adoption initiatives. Your participation helps sustain and enhance the Firo network.</p>

<h2 id="how-to-prepare">How to Prepare</h2>

<p>To ensure seamless functionality, please:</p>

<ul>
  <li>Update your Firo node to <strong>v0.14.14.1</strong> prior to block 1,104,500.</li>
  <li>Look out for updates from <strong>Campfire Wallet</strong> and <strong>Stack Wallet</strong>, both of which are expected to support Spark Names by the activation date or shortly thereafter.</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="learn-more">Learn More</h2>

<p>Dive deeper into Spark Names by exploring the resources below:</p>

<ul>
  <li><a href="/firo-site/pr-preview/pr-518/zh-cn/2025/01/28/spark-names.html">Introduction to Spark Names</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://forum.firo.org/t/new-proposed-feature-spark-names-aliases/3398">Community Discussion and Feedback</a></li>
  <li><a href="/firo-site/pr-preview/pr-518/zh-cn/2025/03/04/spark-names-testnet-launch.html">Testnet Launch Recap</a></li>
</ul>

<p>We appreciate your continued support in making Firo simpler and more accessible for everyone!</p>

<p><strong>Stay tuned for updates and happy naming!</strong></p>]]></content><author><name>Reuben Yap</name></author><category term="community" /><category term="news" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[We’re thrilled to announce that Spark Names will be activated on the Firo mainnet at approximately block 1,104,500, expected around 28 May 2025. To smoothly transition, all users are required to upgrade to Firo v0.14.14.1. What are Spark Names? Spark Names simplify Firo addresses by allowing users to register unique, easy-to-remember aliases instead of long cryptographic addresses. This innovation makes sending and receiving FIRO intuitive, convenient, and less prone to error. Supporting the Community Registration fees from Spark Names directly contribute to the Firo Community Fund, actively supporting ongoing development, ecosystem growth, and adoption initiatives. Your participation helps sustain and enhance the Firo network. How to Prepare To ensure seamless functionality, please: Update your Firo node to v0.14.14.1 prior to block 1,104,500. Look out for updates from Campfire Wallet and Stack Wallet, both of which are expected to support Spark Names by the activation date or shortly thereafter. Learn More Dive deeper into Spark Names by exploring the resources below: Introduction to Spark Names Community Discussion and Feedback Testnet Launch Recap We appreciate your continued support in making Firo simpler and more accessible for everyone! Stay tuned for updates and happy naming!]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Binance Halts Firo Trading – Withdraw Your FIRO Now</title><link href="https://firo.org/firo-site/pr-preview/pr-518/2025/04/16/binance-delisting.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Binance Halts Firo Trading – Withdraw Your FIRO Now" /><published>2025-04-16T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-04-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://firo.org/firo-site/pr-preview/pr-518/2025/04/16/binance-delisting</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://firo.org/firo-site/pr-preview/pr-518/2025/04/16/binance-delisting.html"><![CDATA[<p>Trading on Binance for Firo has now been halted. While Binance is giving a grace period until to <strong>16 June 2025</strong> to withdraw your Firo, we encourage our Firo Fam to withdraw and self custody their Firo as soon as possible. Note that Binance from time to time suspends their withdrawals so ensure you do it soon for peace of mind.</p>

<p>We recommend to <a href="https://firo.org/get-firo/download/">use our wallets here.</a></p>

<p>You can also <a href="/guide/exchange-withdrawal-guide.html">refer to our guides to do so here.</a></p>

<p>Binance has informed us that they will continue to honor redemptions of Binance Smart Chain BEP20 Firo to native FIRO 1:1 but it is unclear whether they would allow withdrawal of native FIRO past <strong>16 June 2025.</strong> We recommend converting this by depositing it to Binance and withdrawing it to native FIRO as soon as possible.</p>

<p>Our guides to <a href="/guide/exchange-withdrawal-guide.html#converting-bep20-firo-to-native-firo">convert BEP20 Firo to native Firo are here.</a></p>

<p>Thereafter you can withdraw to your own wallets as per the withdrawal guides above.</p>

<p>If you want to trade Firo and deposit them to other centralized exchanges, note that some exchanges will forfeit your deposits if you directly send from Spark (such as HTX) so ensure you send from a transparent address. Transparent addresses either start with an “a” or “Z” while Spark addresses always start with “sm”.</p>

<p>As always we recommend users to self custody instead and trade and provide liquidity on non custodial platforms like <a href="https://github.com/firoorg/FiroDEX-Desktop/releases/latest">FiroDEX,</a> Bison Wallet and BasicSwapDEX. We will be working on more detailed guides on how to use these platforms soon to be truly self sovereign and private.</p>]]></content><author><name>Reuben Yap</name></author><category term="community" /><category term="news" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Trading on Binance for Firo has now been halted. While Binance is giving a grace period until to 16 June 2025 to withdraw your Firo, we encourage our Firo Fam to withdraw and self custody their Firo as soon as possible. Note that Binance from time to time suspends their withdrawals so ensure you do it soon for peace of mind. We recommend to use our wallets here. You can also refer to our guides to do so here. Binance has informed us that they will continue to honor redemptions of Binance Smart Chain BEP20 Firo to native FIRO 1:1 but it is unclear whether they would allow withdrawal of native FIRO past 16 June 2025. We recommend converting this by depositing it to Binance and withdrawing it to native FIRO as soon as possible. Our guides to convert BEP20 Firo to native Firo are here. Thereafter you can withdraw to your own wallets as per the withdrawal guides above. If you want to trade Firo and deposit them to other centralized exchanges, note that some exchanges will forfeit your deposits if you directly send from Spark (such as HTX) so ensure you send from a transparent address. Transparent addresses either start with an “a” or “Z” while Spark addresses always start with “sm”. As always we recommend users to self custody instead and trade and provide liquidity on non custodial platforms like FiroDEX, Bison Wallet and BasicSwapDEX. We will be working on more detailed guides on how to use these platforms soon to be truly self sovereign and private.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Firo Core Team receives 574 XMR donation from Power Up Privacy</title><link href="https://firo.org/firo-site/pr-preview/pr-518/2025/04/10/firo-receive-574-xmr-donation-power-up-privacy.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Firo Core Team receives 574 XMR donation from Power Up Privacy" /><published>2025-04-10T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-04-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://firo.org/firo-site/pr-preview/pr-518/2025/04/10/firo-receive-574-xmr-donation-power-up-privacy</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://firo.org/firo-site/pr-preview/pr-518/2025/04/10/firo-receive-574-xmr-donation-power-up-privacy.html"><![CDATA[<p>We are thrilled to announce that Firo has received an additional donation of <strong>574 XMR</strong>—equivalent to roughly <strong>USD 125,000</strong> at the time of donation—from our long-term supporter, <a href="https://powerupprivacy.com/">Power Up Privacy,</a> a privacy advocacy group. This new contribution will be used to further our ongoing development, enhance privacy research, and expand our awareness-building efforts.</p>

<h2 id="a-consistent-supporter-of-firo">A Consistent Supporter of Firo</h2>

<p>Power Up Privacy has repeatedly demonstrated their commitment to Firo’s mission of financial privacy and decentralization, providing past donations and liquidity injections that have helped us remain robust, flexible, and forward-looking. In August 2024, they donated directly to support Firo’s development, and shortly thereafter, they played a key role in expanding our liquidity. By continuing to support us, Power Up Privacy strengthens our ability to deliver cutting-edge privacy technology to crypto enthusiasts worldwide.</p>

<h2 id="driving-firos-future">Driving Firo’s Future</h2>

<p>This latest donation will:</p>

<p>1) <strong>Accelerate Development</strong>: Support ongoing research and development of Firo’s privacy protocols and upcoming features.</p>

<p>2) <strong>Extend Awareness</strong>: Fund strategic marketing and education initiatives, introducing more people to the importance of financial privacy and the unique qualities Firo offers.</p>

<p>3) <strong>Reinforce Liquidity</strong>: Sustain healthy trading environments across exchanges, benefiting both new and existing community members.</p>

<h2 id="our-gratitude">Our Gratitude</h2>

<p>Firo expresses its deepest appreciation to Power Up Privacy for their unwavering and continuous support. Financial privacy matters to everyone, and this donation will help us keep innovating and pushing the boundaries of what’s possible in the space.</p>

<p>As usual, will keep the Firo Fam updated on the progress made possible by their contributions.</p>

<p>Thank you to everyone who continues to stand by Firo’s mission. Together, we continue to build stronger foundations for user empowerment and financial freedom.</p>

<p>Learn more about <a href="https://powerupprivacy.com/">Power Up Privacy.</a></p>

<p>—</p>

<p>For more details on Power Up Privacy’s previous contributions to Firo, check out:</p>

<ul>
  <li><a href="/firo-site/pr-preview/pr-518/zh-cn/2024/08/10/firo-receive-donation-from-powerup-privacy.html">Firo Receives Donation from Power Up Privacy (Aug 10, 2024)</a></li>
  <li><a href="/firo-site/pr-preview/pr-518/zh-cn/2024/10/17/powerupprivacy-firo-liquidity-injection.html">Power Up Privacy &amp; Firo Liquidity Injection (Oct 17, 2024)</a></li>
  <li><a href="/firo-site/pr-preview/pr-518/zh-cn/2024/09/24/firo-liquidity-campaign-sept24.html">Firo Liquidity Campaign (Sept 24, 2024)</a></li>
</ul>]]></content><author><name>Reuben Yap</name></author><category term="community" /><category term="news" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[We are thrilled to announce that Firo has received an additional donation of 574 XMR—equivalent to roughly USD 125,000 at the time of donation—from our long-term supporter, Power Up Privacy, a privacy advocacy group. This new contribution will be used to further our ongoing development, enhance privacy research, and expand our awareness-building efforts. A Consistent Supporter of Firo Power Up Privacy has repeatedly demonstrated their commitment to Firo’s mission of financial privacy and decentralization, providing past donations and liquidity injections that have helped us remain robust, flexible, and forward-looking. In August 2024, they donated directly to support Firo’s development, and shortly thereafter, they played a key role in expanding our liquidity. By continuing to support us, Power Up Privacy strengthens our ability to deliver cutting-edge privacy technology to crypto enthusiasts worldwide. Driving Firo’s Future This latest donation will: 1) Accelerate Development: Support ongoing research and development of Firo’s privacy protocols and upcoming features. 2) Extend Awareness: Fund strategic marketing and education initiatives, introducing more people to the importance of financial privacy and the unique qualities Firo offers. 3) Reinforce Liquidity: Sustain healthy trading environments across exchanges, benefiting both new and existing community members. Our Gratitude Firo expresses its deepest appreciation to Power Up Privacy for their unwavering and continuous support. Financial privacy matters to everyone, and this donation will help us keep innovating and pushing the boundaries of what’s possible in the space. As usual, will keep the Firo Fam updated on the progress made possible by their contributions. Thank you to everyone who continues to stand by Firo’s mission. Together, we continue to build stronger foundations for user empowerment and financial freedom. Learn more about Power Up Privacy. — For more details on Power Up Privacy’s previous contributions to Firo, check out: Firo Receives Donation from Power Up Privacy (Aug 10, 2024) Power Up Privacy &amp; Firo Liquidity Injection (Oct 17, 2024) Firo Liquidity Campaign (Sept 24, 2024)]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Firo Roadmap Updated</title><link href="https://firo.org/firo-site/pr-preview/pr-518/2025/03/19/firo-roadmap-2025.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Firo Roadmap Updated" /><published>2025-03-19T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-03-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://firo.org/firo-site/pr-preview/pr-518/2025/03/19/firo-roadmap-2025</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://firo.org/firo-site/pr-preview/pr-518/2025/03/19/firo-roadmap-2025.html"><![CDATA[<p>Firo has evolved significantly since its inception as Zcoin, pioneering the use of modern zero-knowledge proofs for privacy. Our technology has matured through steady innovation resulting in influential privacy protocols such as Lelantus and <a href="/firo-site/pr-preview/pr-518/zh-cn/2024/01/18/spark-is-live.html">Lelantus Spark—protocols</a> whose design and concepts have influenced and been adopted in other privacy projects.</p>

<p>Our <a href="https://firo.org/about/roadmap/">updated roadmap</a> recognizes the growing maturity of Firo and its tech stack and focuses on <strong>usability</strong>, <strong>utility</strong>, and <strong>upgrades</strong>:</p>
<ul>
  <li><strong>Usability</strong>: Enhanced user experience through additional wallet integrations and support for light clients.</li>
  <li><strong>Utility</strong>: Expand privacy-preserving use cases, including private token issuance.</li>
  <li><strong>Upgrades</strong>: Continuously refine and strengthen protocol features, maintaining leadership in privacy technology.</li>
</ul>

<h1 id="near-term">NEAR-TERM</h1>
<h2 id="spark-names"><a href="/firo-site/pr-preview/pr-518/zh-cn/2025/01/28/spark-names.html">Spark Names</a></h2>
<p>Allow users to create easy-to-remember, human-readable addresses linked to Spark addresses, enabling convenient sharing and decentralized digital identity</p>

<h2 id="spark-coinbase">Spark Coinbase</h2>
<p>Enable miners and masternodes to send rewards directly to private Spark addresses, further enhancing user privacy and Spark adoption.</p>

<h2 id="view-key-tooling">View Key Tooling</h2>
<p>Develop user-friendly methods for sharing and utilizing Spark view keys, enabling watch-only wallets and selectively disclosing Spark-based funds for compliance purposes.</p>

<h1 id="mid-term">MID-TERM</h1>

<h2 id="spark-assets"><a href="/firo-site/pr-preview/pr-518/zh-cn/2022/03/07/spats-confidential-assets-lelantus-spark.html">Spark Assets</a></h2>
<p>Allow users to issue their own privacy-preserving assets. These assets enjoy the same privacy features as Spark, including the ability to hide asset types. All assets (including Firo) contribute to a shared anonymity set, and the protocol can also support privacy-preserving NFTs.</p>

<h2 id="spark-swap">Spark Swap</h2>
<p>Enable atomic swaps between Spark assets and/or Firo, ensuring trustless and private exchanges without using transparent addresses.</p>

<h2 id="curve-trees"><a href="/firo-site/pr-preview/pr-518/zh-cn/2024/03/07/curve-trees-research-results.html">Curve Trees</a></h2>
<p>Adopt Curve Trees, an innovative technique for efficient membership proofs that supports a global anonymity set. This upgrade will substantially improve privacy, scalability, verification speed, and proof size.</p>

<h1 id="long-term">LONG-TERM</h1>

<h2 id="improved-privacy-preserving-light-wallet-infrastructure">Improved Privacy-Preserving Light Wallet Infrastructure</h2>
<p>Reduce reliance on customized SPV servers, giving users more private and decentralized light wallet options.</p>

<h2 id="quantum-resistant-spark">Quantum-Resistant Spark</h2>
<p>Explore paths to transition Spark into a quantum-resistant protocol, as well as potential interim mitigations to safeguard against future quantum threats.</p>

<h2 id="tail-emission-consensus-mechanism">Tail Emission Consensus Mechanism</h2>
<p>Firo’s current hybrid masternode–Proof-of-Work model may evolve once tail emission is reached. We are investigating alternative incentive or consensus mechanisms to secure the chain in the long run.</p>

<h2 id="governance">Governance</h2>
<p>Develop clear, decentralized governance structures to reduce reliance on Firo’s core team. The aim is to align all project stakeholders without focusing solely on coin holdings.</p>

<h1 id="integrations">INTEGRATIONS</h1>

<h2 id="enkrypt-wallet-integration">Enkrypt Wallet Integration</h2>
<p>Seamless access to Spark privacy directly in <a href="https://www.enkrypt.com/">Enkrypt</a>, a popular Web3 wallet, simplifying secure asset management for users.</p>

<h2 id="layerswap-v8-integration">Layerswap v8 Integration</h2>
<p>Leverage Layerswap v8, a peer-to-peer protocol for bridging and swapping crypto assets across different blockchains. By using pre-HTLCs, it addresses many limitations of traditional atomic swaps (e.g., both parties needing to be online) and supports multi-hop transactions.</p>

<h2 id="serai-integration">Serai Integration</h2>
<p>Collaborate with <a href="https://serai.exchange/">Serai</a>, a cross-chain DEX focusing on AMM liquidity for Bitcoin, Ethereum, DAI, and Monero. Integrating Firo expands its cross-chain liquidity options and user base.</p>

<h1 id="iterative-improvements">ITERATIVE IMPROVEMENTS</h1>

<h2 id="campfire">Campfire</h2>
<p>Continue building out <a href="https://firo.org/2024/07/12/campfire-firo-wallet.html">Campfire</a> desktop and mobile wallets to provide full-featured support for masternodes, Spark Assets, and Spark Names.</p>

<h2 id="firodex">FiroDEX</h2>
<p>Rework <a href="https://github.com/firoorg/FiroDEX-Desktop">FiroDEX</a> to be more resilient, ensuring its infrastructure—both nodes and front ends—is operated by a decentralized network of volunteers and community members.</p>

<h1 id="onwards">ONWARDS</h1>
<p>Our ongoing development is powered by our passionate community and crucially supported by privacy-aligned partners such as <a href="https://powerupprivacy.com/">Power Up Privacy</a> and <a href="https://arcadia.agency/">Arcadia Group</a>, who make many of these initiatives possible. We remain committed to decentralization, community-driven growth, and privacy without VC interference. Thank you for your continuous support.</p>]]></content><author><name>Reuben Yap</name></author><category term="community" /><category term="news" /><category term="dev" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Firo has evolved significantly since its inception as Zcoin, pioneering the use of modern zero-knowledge proofs for privacy. Our technology has matured through steady innovation resulting in influential privacy protocols such as Lelantus and Lelantus Spark—protocols whose design and concepts have influenced and been adopted in other privacy projects. Our updated roadmap recognizes the growing maturity of Firo and its tech stack and focuses on usability, utility, and upgrades: Usability: Enhanced user experience through additional wallet integrations and support for light clients. Utility: Expand privacy-preserving use cases, including private token issuance. Upgrades: Continuously refine and strengthen protocol features, maintaining leadership in privacy technology. NEAR-TERM Spark Names Allow users to create easy-to-remember, human-readable addresses linked to Spark addresses, enabling convenient sharing and decentralized digital identity Spark Coinbase Enable miners and masternodes to send rewards directly to private Spark addresses, further enhancing user privacy and Spark adoption. View Key Tooling Develop user-friendly methods for sharing and utilizing Spark view keys, enabling watch-only wallets and selectively disclosing Spark-based funds for compliance purposes. MID-TERM Spark Assets Allow users to issue their own privacy-preserving assets. These assets enjoy the same privacy features as Spark, including the ability to hide asset types. All assets (including Firo) contribute to a shared anonymity set, and the protocol can also support privacy-preserving NFTs. Spark Swap Enable atomic swaps between Spark assets and/or Firo, ensuring trustless and private exchanges without using transparent addresses. Curve Trees Adopt Curve Trees, an innovative technique for efficient membership proofs that supports a global anonymity set. This upgrade will substantially improve privacy, scalability, verification speed, and proof size. LONG-TERM Improved Privacy-Preserving Light Wallet Infrastructure Reduce reliance on customized SPV servers, giving users more private and decentralized light wallet options. Quantum-Resistant Spark Explore paths to transition Spark into a quantum-resistant protocol, as well as potential interim mitigations to safeguard against future quantum threats. Tail Emission Consensus Mechanism Firo’s current hybrid masternode–Proof-of-Work model may evolve once tail emission is reached. We are investigating alternative incentive or consensus mechanisms to secure the chain in the long run. Governance Develop clear, decentralized governance structures to reduce reliance on Firo’s core team. The aim is to align all project stakeholders without focusing solely on coin holdings. INTEGRATIONS Enkrypt Wallet Integration Seamless access to Spark privacy directly in Enkrypt, a popular Web3 wallet, simplifying secure asset management for users. Layerswap v8 Integration Leverage Layerswap v8, a peer-to-peer protocol for bridging and swapping crypto assets across different blockchains. By using pre-HTLCs, it addresses many limitations of traditional atomic swaps (e.g., both parties needing to be online) and supports multi-hop transactions. Serai Integration Collaborate with Serai, a cross-chain DEX focusing on AMM liquidity for Bitcoin, Ethereum, DAI, and Monero. Integrating Firo expands its cross-chain liquidity options and user base. ITERATIVE IMPROVEMENTS Campfire Continue building out Campfire desktop and mobile wallets to provide full-featured support for masternodes, Spark Assets, and Spark Names. FiroDEX Rework FiroDEX to be more resilient, ensuring its infrastructure—both nodes and front ends—is operated by a decentralized network of volunteers and community members. ONWARDS Our ongoing development is powered by our passionate community and crucially supported by privacy-aligned partners such as Power Up Privacy and Arcadia Group, who make many of these initiatives possible. We remain committed to decentralization, community-driven growth, and privacy without VC interference. Thank you for your continuous support.]]></summary></entry></feed>