<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="zh-cn"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://firo.org/firo-site/pr-preview/pr-439/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://firo.org/firo-site/pr-preview/pr-439/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="zh-cn" /><updated>2024-10-13T18:48:54+00:00</updated><id>https://firo.org/firo-site/pr-preview/pr-439/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Firo</title><subtitle>Firo is a cryptocurrency that focuses on privacy and fungibility.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Firo 24-Week Liquidity Mining Campaign</title><link href="https://firo.org/firo-site/pr-preview/pr-439/2024/09/24/firo-liquidity-campaign-sept24.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Firo 24-Week Liquidity Mining Campaign" /><published>2024-09-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-09-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://firo.org/firo-site/pr-preview/pr-439/2024/09/24/firo-liquidity-campaign-sept24</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://firo.org/firo-site/pr-preview/pr-439/2024/09/24/firo-liquidity-campaign-sept24.html"><![CDATA[<p>We are excited to share that the Liquidity campaign is back! Now for 24 weeks with a total reward pool of approximately ~US$19,200 up for grabs! Provide liquidity on Binance and AscendEX via Hummingbot and earn Firo!</p>

<p><img src="/blog/assets/firo-liquidity-campaign-sept24/img1.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<h2 id="campaign-terms">Campaign Terms</h2>

<ul>
  <li>
    <p>Start date: <strong>September 24, 2024, 12:00 AM UTC</strong></p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Total reward pool*: <strong>~US$19,200</strong> (FIRO 684 per week)</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Reward token: <strong>FIRO</strong></p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Eligible token pair: <strong>FIRO/USDT</strong></p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Eligible orders: maker orders placed with spreads of <strong>2.0%</strong> or lower</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Exchange: <strong><a href="https://accounts.binance.com/en/register?ref=37748947">Binance</a></strong> and <strong><a href="https://ascendex.com/en-us/register?inviteCode=URUFAVHHY">AscendEX</a></strong></p>
  </li>
</ul>

<h2 id="what-is-hummingbot">What is Hummingbot?</h2>

<p>Hummingbot Liquidity Mining is a decentralized, community-based market making. It allows anyone (communities, the general market) to participate in market making for a coin/token and contribute to its liquidity and improve the tradability of that coin/token. By participating, users are not only helping to support the coin/token and the project, but through liquidity mining, they are able to earn coin/token rewards based on their trading activity.</p>

<h2 id="how-does-the-campaign-work">How Does the Campaign Work?</h2>

<p>During the campaign, users who provide liquidity to the FIRO/USDT pair on Binance and AscendEX will earn rewards in Firo weekly.</p>

<h2 id="how-to-get-started">How to Get Started?</h2>

<p>To join the campaign, you’ll need to set up your wallet using the <a href="https://miner.hummingbot.io/">Hummingbot Miner App</a>. A detailed setup guide and How-To Articles are available on the <a href="https://support.hummingbot.io/miner/getting-started">Hummingbot website</a>. After installation, you can follow the instructions to connect the app to the Binance and AscendEX exchanges and begin providing liquidity to the FIRO/USDT pool.</p>

<p>Don’t miss this amazing chance to earn rewards while engaging with the Firo community! Whether you’re a current participant or new to liquidity mining, we invite you to take part and enjoy the benefits firsthand.</p>

<p>*For full terms of the campaign, please read the full terms here <a href="https://support.hummingbot.io/miner/new-24-week-for-firo-liquidity-mining-campaign">Hummingbot New 24-week for FIRO liquidity mining campaign!</a></p>

<p>Learn more about Liquidity mining <a href="https://support.hummingbot.io/miner/liquidity-mining-explained">here</a></p>

<h2 id="thank-you">Thank you</h2>

<p>We extend our heartfelt thanks to Power Up Privacy who funded this campaign through their <a href="/firo-site/pr-preview/pr-439/zh-cn2024/08/10/firo-receive-donation-from-powerup-privacy.html">donation</a>. Discover more about Power Up Privacy <a href="https://powerupprivacy.com/">here</a></p>]]></content><author><name>Augustus Jong</name></author><category term="community" /><category term="news" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[We are excited to share that the Liquidity campaign is back! Now for 24 weeks with a total reward pool of approximately ~US$19,200 up for grabs! Provide liquidity on Binance and AscendEX via Hummingbot and earn Firo! Campaign Terms Start date: September 24, 2024, 12:00 AM UTC Total reward pool*: ~US$19,200 (FIRO 684 per week) Reward token: FIRO Eligible token pair: FIRO/USDT Eligible orders: maker orders placed with spreads of 2.0% or lower Exchange: Binance and AscendEX What is Hummingbot? Hummingbot Liquidity Mining is a decentralized, community-based market making. It allows anyone (communities, the general market) to participate in market making for a coin/token and contribute to its liquidity and improve the tradability of that coin/token. By participating, users are not only helping to support the coin/token and the project, but through liquidity mining, they are able to earn coin/token rewards based on their trading activity. How Does the Campaign Work? During the campaign, users who provide liquidity to the FIRO/USDT pair on Binance and AscendEX will earn rewards in Firo weekly. How to Get Started? To join the campaign, you’ll need to set up your wallet using the Hummingbot Miner App. A detailed setup guide and How-To Articles are available on the Hummingbot website. After installation, you can follow the instructions to connect the app to the Binance and AscendEX exchanges and begin providing liquidity to the FIRO/USDT pool. Don’t miss this amazing chance to earn rewards while engaging with the Firo community! Whether you’re a current participant or new to liquidity mining, we invite you to take part and enjoy the benefits firsthand. *For full terms of the campaign, please read the full terms here Hummingbot New 24-week for FIRO liquidity mining campaign! Learn more about Liquidity mining here Thank you We extend our heartfelt thanks to Power Up Privacy who funded this campaign through their donation. Discover more about Power Up Privacy here]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Firo Hardfork Completed Successfully</title><link href="https://firo.org/firo-site/pr-preview/pr-439/2024/09/18/hardfork-2024.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Firo Hardfork Completed Successfully" /><published>2024-09-18T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-09-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://firo.org/firo-site/pr-preview/pr-439/2024/09/18/hardfork-2024</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://firo.org/firo-site/pr-preview/pr-439/2024/09/18/hardfork-2024.html"><![CDATA[<p>The hard fork implementing the latest tokenomics changes as voted in by the community has been completed successfully. This upgrade introduces significant changes to our block reward distribution, emission model, and overall sustainability. Read more about these changes in our previous blog post on it <a href="/firo-site/pr-preview/pr-439/zh-cn/2024/09/01/finalized-tokenomics-2024.html">here</a>.</p>

<p>A huge thank you to our amazing ecosystem of masternode providers, mining pools, and the supportive community who voted in the <a href="/firo-site/pr-preview/pr-439/zh-cn/2024/09/01/finalized-tokenomics-2024.html">finalization of the community polls</a> and ensured a smooth transition. Together, we continue to create a place in privacy and decentralization in Firo!</p>

<p>The core team will be posting an updated proposed roadmap soon so stay tuned!</p>]]></content><author><name>Reuben Yap</name></author><category term="community" /><category term="news" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The hard fork implementing the latest tokenomics changes as voted in by the community has been completed successfully. This upgrade introduces significant changes to our block reward distribution, emission model, and overall sustainability. Read more about these changes in our previous blog post on it here. A huge thank you to our amazing ecosystem of masternode providers, mining pools, and the supportive community who voted in the finalization of the community polls and ensured a smooth transition. Together, we continue to create a place in privacy and decentralization in Firo! The core team will be posting an updated proposed roadmap soon so stay tuned!]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Firo Mandatory Release v0.14.14.0</title><link href="https://firo.org/firo-site/pr-preview/pr-439/2024/09/04/firo-release-014140-mandatory.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Firo Mandatory Release v0.14.14.0" /><published>2024-09-04T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-09-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://firo.org/firo-site/pr-preview/pr-439/2024/09/04/firo-release-014140-mandatory</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://firo.org/firo-site/pr-preview/pr-439/2024/09/04/firo-release-014140-mandatory.html"><![CDATA[<p>Following the <a href="https://firo.org/2024/09/01/finalized-tokenomics-2024.html">finalisation of the community polls</a> to determine Firo’s tokenomics, we are releasing Firo v0.14.14.0 with the agreed-upon changes that require a hard fork.</p>

<p>Please upgrade your wallets, daemons and masternodes to the latest Firo v0.14.14.0 before block 958655 (approximately 16 September 2024). <strong>This is a mandatory upgrade</strong>.</p>

<p>You can download them either from our <a href="https://firo.org/get-firo/download/">official download page</a> or our <a href="https://github.com/firoorg/firo/releases">Github release page</a>.</p>

<p>If you are using Campfire or Stack wallets, no updates are required, as the changes have been made in the backend.</p>]]></content><author><name>Reuben Yap</name></author><category term="community" /><category term="dev" /><category term="news" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Following the finalisation of the community polls to determine Firo’s tokenomics, we are releasing Firo v0.14.14.0 with the agreed-upon changes that require a hard fork. Please upgrade your wallets, daemons and masternodes to the latest Firo v0.14.14.0 before block 958655 (approximately 16 September 2024). This is a mandatory upgrade. You can download them either from our official download page or our Github release page. If you are using Campfire or Stack wallets, no updates are required, as the changes have been made in the backend.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Firo Finalized Tokenomics Results</title><link href="https://firo.org/firo-site/pr-preview/pr-439/2024/09/01/finalized-tokenomics-2024.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Firo Finalized Tokenomics Results" /><published>2024-09-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-09-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://firo.org/firo-site/pr-preview/pr-439/2024/09/01/finalized-tokenomics-2024</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://firo.org/firo-site/pr-preview/pr-439/2024/09/01/finalized-tokenomics-2024.html"><![CDATA[<p>Through Firo’s governance process, Firo’s emission and block reward division has been finalized! A huge thank you  to everyone who voted and shared their thoughts and feedback.</p>

<p>Through several rounds of polls, the community has decided on the implementation of three things to Firo’s tokenomics:</p>

<ul>
  <li>A fixed emission of 6.25 FIRO/block until the cap of 21.4 million FIRO is hit</li>
  <li>A tail emission of 1 FIRO/block thereafter</li>
  <li>A block reward division of 70% Masternodes, 5% Miners, 15% Dev, 10% Community (previously 50% Masternodes, 25% miners, 15% Dev, 10% community)</li>
</ul>

<p>View the <a href="https://forum.firo.org/t/poll-final-tokenomics-and-block-division/3379">final poll results</a></p>

<p>For a more accurate reflection of community sentiment, we employed a system known as <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=3Y3jE3B8HsE">ranked-choice voting or instant run-off</a>. This system allowed voters to select multiple choices and then rank them in order of preference, ensuring that the final decision better represents the community’s preferences.</p>

<h2 id="governance">Governance</h2>

<p>To read through how the Firo community arrived at this decision, you can follow the timeline and links to the relevant discussions below:</p>
<ul>
  <li>April 2024: Initial discussion about tokenomics. <a href="https://firo.org/2024/04/23/firo-tokenomics-and-halving.html">blog</a> <a href="https://forum.firo.org/t/firo-tokenomics-discussion-with-upcoming-halving/3162">forum</a></li>
  <li>June-July 2024: Polls were held regarding <a href="https://forum.firo.org/t/firo-tokenomics-discussion-with-upcoming-halving/3162">tail emission</a>, the <a href="https://forum.firo.org/t/poll-should-firo-continue-its-development-fund-and-community-fund/3274">development and community fund</a>, and <a href="https://forum.firo.org/t/poll-should-firo-keep-its-halving-schedule-or-should-we-revisit-our-emission-curve/3276">the rate of emission</a></li>
  <li>July 2024: A <a href="https://forum.firo.org/t/discussion-on-final-poll-options-for-tokenomics-and-block-division/3345">thread</a> was opened to ensure that the final poll’s voting options would cover all options that the community cared about.</li>
  <li>August 2024: <a href="https://forum.firo.org/t/poll-final-tokenomics-and-block-division/3379">Final polls</a> to vote on the proposed changes.</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="effect-of-changes">Effect of Changes</h2>

<p>The primary effect of the changes is to provide improved incentives for masternodes for the next 4 years, recognizing their continued role and unwavering support of the network. Miners will still contribute to the hybrid PoW/masternode consensus mechanism, but while the hashrate adjusts, there may be a period of slow blocks until the difficulty adjusts to the new hashrate. The chain will remain protected against 51% attacks with Firo’s <a href="https://firo.org/2021/01/28/chainlocks-activated-mainnet.html">masternode chainlocks</a>. Assuming current masternode numbers are maintained at around 3900+ master nodes, the current returns of a masternode will increase from around 16.5% p.a. to around 22% p.a.</p>

<p>There is also a significant change to the supply schedule of Firo to reflect the existence of developed infrastructure and markets for the distribution of cryptocurrencies compared to the time when Bitcoin was first created. Prior to the change, Firo followed Bitcoin’s emission schedule and the block reward would have halved roughly every 4 years with it finally ceasing after it hit 21.4 million. Firo has had a single halving prior to this and was set to have its 2nd halving in mid September 2024. With the new change coming into effect, there will be no more halvings and the existing emission of 6.25 FIRO/block is maintained until the supply of 21.4 million has been fully issued over the next 5-6 years.</p>

<p>After the 21.4 million limit is hit, to ensure a stable monetary supply and a continued stable security subsidy, a fixed tail emission of 1 FIRO/block will continue in perpetuity which works out to be 0.98% inflation rate p.a. at the beginning and over time trends to 0%. To read more about the effects of tail emission and how it leads to a stable monetary supply that is neither inflationary nor deflationary, you can read this <a href="https://petertodd.org/2022/surprisingly-tail-emission-is-not-inflationary">article</a>. There’s also strong <a href="https://www.cs.princeton.edu/~arvindn/publications/mining_CCS.pdf">academic evidence</a> that indicates that having no block reward results in instability in Bitcoin.</p>

<p>To view the effect of changes in tokenomics to Firo’s supply over time, we’ve plotted this graph starting from the hard fork date of block 958655 (approximately 16 September 2024) over the next 20 years. The times are estimated due to the slight variance in block times. Tail emission is hit roughly halfway into year 14 (5+ years from hard fork date).</p>

<p><img src="/blog/assets/finalized-tokenomics-2024/emissioncomparison2024.png" alt="Chart of emission, old versus new starting 2024" /></p>

<h2 id="future-direction">Future Direction</h2>

<p>The core team is making a firm commitment not to propose further changes to Firo’s tokenomics until tail emission is hit. This commitment is aimed at providing stability and certainty to the Firo community, ensuring a secure and confident future.</p>

<p>We will be deploying these changes in release <a href="https://github.com/firoorg/firo/releases/tag/v0.14.14.0">Firo v.14.14.0</a>, as these changes are scheduled to come into force by block 958655 (approximately 16 September 2024). Please ensure you are updated to the <a href="https://github.com/firoorg/firo/releases/latest">latest version</a> as soon as possible.</p>

<p>In the coming weeks, the core team will also be rolling out an updated roadmap for Firo, laying out development and adoption goals for the next few years. This will also include research into blockchain consensus models that would be secure and sustainable through tail emission and also a renewed focus on increasing awareness and adoption.</p>

<p>Again, we would like to thank the community members who have stood by the project and taking part in governance to guide Firo’s future.</p>]]></content><author><name>Reuben Yap</name></author><category term="community" /><category term="news" /><category term="dev" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Through Firo’s governance process, Firo’s emission and block reward division has been finalized! A huge thank you to everyone who voted and shared their thoughts and feedback. Through several rounds of polls, the community has decided on the implementation of three things to Firo’s tokenomics: A fixed emission of 6.25 FIRO/block until the cap of 21.4 million FIRO is hit A tail emission of 1 FIRO/block thereafter A block reward division of 70% Masternodes, 5% Miners, 15% Dev, 10% Community (previously 50% Masternodes, 25% miners, 15% Dev, 10% community) View the final poll results For a more accurate reflection of community sentiment, we employed a system known as ranked-choice voting or instant run-off. This system allowed voters to select multiple choices and then rank them in order of preference, ensuring that the final decision better represents the community’s preferences. Governance To read through how the Firo community arrived at this decision, you can follow the timeline and links to the relevant discussions below: April 2024: Initial discussion about tokenomics. blog forum June-July 2024: Polls were held regarding tail emission, the development and community fund, and the rate of emission July 2024: A thread was opened to ensure that the final poll’s voting options would cover all options that the community cared about. August 2024: Final polls to vote on the proposed changes. Effect of Changes The primary effect of the changes is to provide improved incentives for masternodes for the next 4 years, recognizing their continued role and unwavering support of the network. Miners will still contribute to the hybrid PoW/masternode consensus mechanism, but while the hashrate adjusts, there may be a period of slow blocks until the difficulty adjusts to the new hashrate. The chain will remain protected against 51% attacks with Firo’s masternode chainlocks. Assuming current masternode numbers are maintained at around 3900+ master nodes, the current returns of a masternode will increase from around 16.5% p.a. to around 22% p.a. There is also a significant change to the supply schedule of Firo to reflect the existence of developed infrastructure and markets for the distribution of cryptocurrencies compared to the time when Bitcoin was first created. Prior to the change, Firo followed Bitcoin’s emission schedule and the block reward would have halved roughly every 4 years with it finally ceasing after it hit 21.4 million. Firo has had a single halving prior to this and was set to have its 2nd halving in mid September 2024. With the new change coming into effect, there will be no more halvings and the existing emission of 6.25 FIRO/block is maintained until the supply of 21.4 million has been fully issued over the next 5-6 years. After the 21.4 million limit is hit, to ensure a stable monetary supply and a continued stable security subsidy, a fixed tail emission of 1 FIRO/block will continue in perpetuity which works out to be 0.98% inflation rate p.a. at the beginning and over time trends to 0%. To read more about the effects of tail emission and how it leads to a stable monetary supply that is neither inflationary nor deflationary, you can read this article. There’s also strong academic evidence that indicates that having no block reward results in instability in Bitcoin. To view the effect of changes in tokenomics to Firo’s supply over time, we’ve plotted this graph starting from the hard fork date of block 958655 (approximately 16 September 2024) over the next 20 years. The times are estimated due to the slight variance in block times. Tail emission is hit roughly halfway into year 14 (5+ years from hard fork date). Future Direction The core team is making a firm commitment not to propose further changes to Firo’s tokenomics until tail emission is hit. This commitment is aimed at providing stability and certainty to the Firo community, ensuring a secure and confident future. We will be deploying these changes in release Firo v.14.14.0, as these changes are scheduled to come into force by block 958655 (approximately 16 September 2024). Please ensure you are updated to the latest version as soon as possible. In the coming weeks, the core team will also be rolling out an updated roadmap for Firo, laying out development and adoption goals for the next few years. This will also include research into blockchain consensus models that would be secure and sustainable through tail emission and also a renewed focus on increasing awareness and adoption. Again, we would like to thank the community members who have stood by the project and taking part in governance to guide Firo’s future.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Together We Decide: Vote to Shape Firo’s Future!</title><link href="https://firo.org/firo-site/pr-preview/pr-439/2024/08/19/final-vote-tokenomics-2024.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Together We Decide: Vote to Shape Firo’s Future!" /><published>2024-08-19T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-08-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://firo.org/firo-site/pr-preview/pr-439/2024/08/19/final-vote-tokenomics-2024</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://firo.org/firo-site/pr-preview/pr-439/2024/08/19/final-vote-tokenomics-2024.html"><![CDATA[<p>The community has been actively discussing Firo’s economics, particularly its block reward division and emission model.</p>

<p>After seeking community feedback and <a href="https://forum.firo.org/t/poll-final-tokenomics-and-block-division/3379">preliminary polls</a> since June, we are now approaching the penultimate poll to definitively decide Firo’s future.</p>

<p>The two primary issues being voted on are:</p>

<ul>
  <li>What should Firo’s block reward division be?</li>
  <li>What should Firo’s emissions be?</li>
</ul>

<p>These polls touch on important issues, such as whether there should be a development and/or community fund, the sustainability of masternodes and the role of miners. It also looks into the long-term sustainability of Firo as to whether it should adopt a tail emission or stick closer to the original Bitcoin model.</p>

<p>Instead of a single-choice vote, the poll allows community members to rank their options, resulting in a fairer reflection of sentiment. This is also known as <a href="https://fairvote.org/our-reforms/ranked-choice-voting/">ranked-choice voting</a> and is suitable where there are many options to choose from.</p>

<p>You can view the previous discussions and polls here to help guide your decision!</p>

<ul>
  <li><a href="https://forum.firo.org/t/poll-should-firo-continue-its-development-fund-and-community-fund/3274">Development and Community Funds</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://forum.firo.org/t/poll-should-firo-have-a-tail-emission/3275">Tail Emission</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://forum.firo.org/t/poll-should-firo-keep-its-halving-schedule-or-should-we-revisit-our-emission-curve/3276">Firo’s halving schedule</a></li>
</ul>

<h2 id="how-to-vote">How to Vote!</h2>

<p>Anyone who has been in the Firo community for some time is eligible to vote in this poll.</p>

<p><strong>Step 1</strong>: Register an account at <a href="http://forum.firo.org">forum.firo.org</a></p>

<p><strong>Step 2</strong>: Earn at least Trust Level 1 by <a href="https://blog.discourse.org/2018/06/understanding-discourse-trust-levels/">spending time on the forums</a>. Alternatively, if you have been with the Firo community for a while in other places, you can post in <a href="https://forum.firo.org/t/for-new-members-trust-level-upgrade-request-thread/3294">this thread</a> to request for an admin to upgrade you immediately.</p>

<p><strong>Step 3</strong> Head to the <a href="https://forum.firo.org/t/poll-final-tokenomics-and-block-division/3379"><strong>final poll</strong></a> thread. Note there are two polls to vote on so please don’t forget to vote on both of them!</p>

<p><strong>Step 4</strong>: Rank the options you like with rank 1 being your most preferred option. For options you don’t like, you can choose to not rank them by picking ‘abstain’.</p>

<p><strong>Step 5</strong>: You can post in the thread to explain why you picked a vote!</p>

<p>Do note that in the future, we intend to impose higher requirements in future polls or even require a minimum Firo holding requirement to prove skin in the game without disenfranchising smaller holders.</p>

<h2 id="do-your-part">Do your Part!</h2>

<p>Getting involved in Firo’s polls is an important step in decentralized governance. It ensures that your voice is heard, and every vote counts! The poll closes on the 1 September 2024!</p>]]></content><author><name>Reuben Yap</name></author><category term="community" /><category term="news" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The community has been actively discussing Firo’s economics, particularly its block reward division and emission model. After seeking community feedback and preliminary polls since June, we are now approaching the penultimate poll to definitively decide Firo’s future. The two primary issues being voted on are: What should Firo’s block reward division be? What should Firo’s emissions be? These polls touch on important issues, such as whether there should be a development and/or community fund, the sustainability of masternodes and the role of miners. It also looks into the long-term sustainability of Firo as to whether it should adopt a tail emission or stick closer to the original Bitcoin model. Instead of a single-choice vote, the poll allows community members to rank their options, resulting in a fairer reflection of sentiment. This is also known as ranked-choice voting and is suitable where there are many options to choose from. You can view the previous discussions and polls here to help guide your decision! Development and Community Funds Tail Emission Firo’s halving schedule How to Vote! Anyone who has been in the Firo community for some time is eligible to vote in this poll. Step 1: Register an account at forum.firo.org Step 2: Earn at least Trust Level 1 by spending time on the forums. Alternatively, if you have been with the Firo community for a while in other places, you can post in this thread to request for an admin to upgrade you immediately. Step 3 Head to the final poll thread. Note there are two polls to vote on so please don’t forget to vote on both of them! Step 4: Rank the options you like with rank 1 being your most preferred option. For options you don’t like, you can choose to not rank them by picking ‘abstain’. Step 5: You can post in the thread to explain why you picked a vote! Do note that in the future, we intend to impose higher requirements in future polls or even require a minimum Firo holding requirement to prove skin in the game without disenfranchising smaller holders. Do your Part! Getting involved in Firo’s polls is an important step in decentralized governance. It ensures that your voice is heard, and every vote counts! The poll closes on the 1 September 2024!]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Firo Guardian Program</title><link href="https://firo.org/firo-site/pr-preview/pr-439/2024/08/12/firo-guardian-program.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Firo Guardian Program" /><published>2024-08-12T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-08-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://firo.org/firo-site/pr-preview/pr-439/2024/08/12/firo-guardian-program</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://firo.org/firo-site/pr-preview/pr-439/2024/08/12/firo-guardian-program.html"><![CDATA[<p>Over the years, Firo has continued to gain momentum in the cryptocurrency space, and our community has been instrumental in this success. To further enhance our reach and engagement, we’re thrilled to introduce: Firo Guardian Program!</p>

<h3 id="who-you-are">Who you are:</h3>
<ul>
  <li>You’re passionate about Firo and its privacy mission.</li>
  <li>You understand the project’s core features and values.</li>
  <li>You’re eager to contribute to Firo’s growth.</li>
  <li>You possess excellent networking skills.</li>
  <li>You’re creative and skilled in content creation.</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="how-you-can-contribute">How you can contribute:</h3>
<p>As a Firo Guardian, you can contribute by amplifying  Firo’s presence and promote privacy awareness. 
Guardians will focus on:</p>
<ul>
  <li>Creating diverse content about Firo, including videos, infographics, tweets, and blog posts.</li>
  <li>Actively representing Firo across social media platforms, especially Twitter, CoinMarketCap, and Reddit.</li>
  <li>Engaging in discussions and answering queries in Firo’s Discord and Telegram communities.</li>
  <li>Promoting Firo’s privacy features and acting as a guardian of privacy in the crypto space.</li>
  <li>Participating in community events and initiatives to boost Firo’s visibility.</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="benefits">Benefits</h3>
<p>As a Firo Guardian, you will:</p>
<ul>
  <li>Receive firsthand updates on the project directly from the core team.</li>
  <li>Have direct communication channels with the team.</li>
  <li>Gain exclusive access to the Guardians’ chat.</li>
  <li>Earn rewards in FIRO for your contributions.</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="did-we-catch-your-attention">Did we catch your attention?</h3>
<p>Here’s how to apply:</p>
<ul>
  <li>Join the Firo Discord server: <a href="https://discord.gg/Ws5C9f3uPC">https://discord.gg/Ws5C9f3uPC</a></li>
  <li>Open a thread in the Firo-guardian-signup channel under “Community-Firo-Guardians” Section.</li>
  <li>Write a 5-line introduction about yourself, including your region.</li>
  <li>Provide a link to your X (Twitter) profile.</li>
  <li>Once selected, you’ll be assigned the Guardian role and given further instructions.</li>
</ul>

<p>We’re excited to welcome passionate individuals to help spread the word about Firo’s innovative privacy solutions. Join us in shaping the future of private transactions in crypto.</p>]]></content><author><name>LilKinggg</name></author><category term="community" /><category term="news" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Over the years, Firo has continued to gain momentum in the cryptocurrency space, and our community has been instrumental in this success. To further enhance our reach and engagement, we’re thrilled to introduce: Firo Guardian Program! Who you are: You’re passionate about Firo and its privacy mission. You understand the project’s core features and values. You’re eager to contribute to Firo’s growth. You possess excellent networking skills. You’re creative and skilled in content creation. How you can contribute: As a Firo Guardian, you can contribute by amplifying Firo’s presence and promote privacy awareness. Guardians will focus on: Creating diverse content about Firo, including videos, infographics, tweets, and blog posts. Actively representing Firo across social media platforms, especially Twitter, CoinMarketCap, and Reddit. Engaging in discussions and answering queries in Firo’s Discord and Telegram communities. Promoting Firo’s privacy features and acting as a guardian of privacy in the crypto space. Participating in community events and initiatives to boost Firo’s visibility. Benefits As a Firo Guardian, you will: Receive firsthand updates on the project directly from the core team. Have direct communication channels with the team. Gain exclusive access to the Guardians’ chat. Earn rewards in FIRO for your contributions. Did we catch your attention? Here’s how to apply: Join the Firo Discord server: https://discord.gg/Ws5C9f3uPC Open a thread in the Firo-guardian-signup channel under “Community-Firo-Guardians” Section. Write a 5-line introduction about yourself, including your region. Provide a link to your X (Twitter) profile. Once selected, you’ll be assigned the Guardian role and given further instructions. We’re excited to welcome passionate individuals to help spread the word about Firo’s innovative privacy solutions. Join us in shaping the future of private transactions in crypto.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Firo Core Team receives 345 XMR donation from Power Up Privacy</title><link href="https://firo.org/firo-site/pr-preview/pr-439/2024/08/10/firo-receive-donation-from-powerup-privacy.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Firo Core Team receives 345 XMR donation from Power Up Privacy" /><published>2024-08-10T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-08-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://firo.org/firo-site/pr-preview/pr-439/2024/08/10/firo-receive-donation-from-powerup-privacy</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://firo.org/firo-site/pr-preview/pr-439/2024/08/10/firo-receive-donation-from-powerup-privacy.html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://powerupprivacy.com/">Power Up Privacy</a>, an anonymous privacy advocacy group that funds privacy-related research and development, has donated 345 XMR (~50,000 USD) to the Firo Core Team fund to support our development work.</p>

<p>We would like to thank them for their generous donation in supporting our work and also for making a significant impact on other important privacy-focused tools and projects, such as Monero, Tor, and xrdp.</p>

<p>Learn more about <a href="https://powerupprivacy.com/">Power Up Privacy</a>.</p>]]></content><author><name>Reuben Yap</name></author><category term="community" /><category term="news" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Power Up Privacy, an anonymous privacy advocacy group that funds privacy-related research and development, has donated 345 XMR (~50,000 USD) to the Firo Core Team fund to support our development work. We would like to thank them for their generous donation in supporting our work and also for making a significant impact on other important privacy-focused tools and projects, such as Monero, Tor, and xrdp. Learn more about Power Up Privacy.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Firo listed on Ascendex</title><link href="https://firo.org/firo-site/pr-preview/pr-439/2024/08/09/firo-ascendex.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Firo listed on Ascendex" /><published>2024-08-09T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-08-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://firo.org/firo-site/pr-preview/pr-439/2024/08/09/firo-ascendex</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://firo.org/firo-site/pr-preview/pr-439/2024/08/09/firo-ascendex.html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="firo-announces-listing-on-ascendex-expanding-accessibility-and-trading-options">Firo Announces Listing on AscendEx: Expanding Accessibility and Trading Options</h1>
<p>We are thrilled to announce that Firo, the leading privacy-focused cryptocurrency, is now listed on AscendEx (formerly known as BitMax) with a FIRO/USDT pair.</p>

<p>Please note the following times:</p>

<ul>
  <li>Deposit: August 9, 10:00 AM UTC</li>
  <li>Trading: August 9, 12:00 PM UTC</li>
  <li>Withdrawal: August 10, 12:00 PM UTC</li>
</ul>

<p>AscendEx is available in a <a href="https://ascendex.com/en/support/articles/36371-countriesregions-available-for-registration">wide variety of countries</a>, which further expands FIRO’s global accessibility and also further builds centralized exchange redundancy.</p>

<p>Stay tuned for news on further activities with AscendEx! You can discuss this listing in our forums here!</p>

<h2 id="about-ascendex">About AscendEx</h2>

<p>AscendEX (formerly BitMax) is a global digital asset financial platform founded by a group of Wall Street quantitative trading veterans in 2018, building on core value of “Efficiency, Resilience and Transparency.” The global cryptocurrency exchange platform serves both retail and institutional clients in more than 200 regions.</p>]]></content><author><name>Reuben Yap</name></author><category term="community" /><category term="news" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Firo Announces Listing on AscendEx: Expanding Accessibility and Trading Options We are thrilled to announce that Firo, the leading privacy-focused cryptocurrency, is now listed on AscendEx (formerly known as BitMax) with a FIRO/USDT pair. Please note the following times: Deposit: August 9, 10:00 AM UTC Trading: August 9, 12:00 PM UTC Withdrawal: August 10, 12:00 PM UTC AscendEx is available in a wide variety of countries, which further expands FIRO’s global accessibility and also further builds centralized exchange redundancy. Stay tuned for news on further activities with AscendEx! You can discuss this listing in our forums here! About AscendEx AscendEX (formerly BitMax) is a global digital asset financial platform founded by a group of Wall Street quantitative trading veterans in 2018, building on core value of “Efficiency, Resilience and Transparency.” The global cryptocurrency exchange platform serves both retail and institutional clients in more than 200 regions.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Campfire Wallet Release</title><link href="https://firo.org/firo-site/pr-preview/pr-439/2024/07/12/campfire-firo-wallet.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Campfire Wallet Release" /><published>2024-07-12T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-07-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://firo.org/firo-site/pr-preview/pr-439/2024/07/12/campfire-firo-wallet</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://firo.org/firo-site/pr-preview/pr-439/2024/07/12/campfire-firo-wallet.html"><![CDATA[<p>We are proud to release our new revamped Campfire wallet in collaboration with Cypher Stack.</p>

<p>Campfire is a Firo-only wallet with a default on Spark privacy. It features many other Firo-specific enhancements, such as masternode collateral recognition and EX-address support. It also includes inbuilt TOR for additional network privacy. It even works on both desktop and mobile devices!</p>

<p>Like its namesake, Campfire is designed to be a warm, welcoming experience where our Firofam can begin their privacy journey.</p>

<h2 id="improved-user-experience">Improved User Experience</h2>

<p>Much work has been put into making the wallet user-friendly with Firo colours, and our Sparky mascot is featured prominently.</p>

<p><img src="/blog/assets/campfirewallet/preview-1.png" alt="Mobile Preview 1" /></p>

<p><img src="/blog/assets/campfirewallet/preview-2.jpg" alt="Desktop Preview 2" /></p>

<p>Under the hood, both teams have made many optimisations to make Spark transactions and syncing speedy and snappy, even with the complex math behind them.</p>

<p>Instead of using the default server, users can choose to host their own light server backend for even more privacy.</p>

<h2 id="open-source">Open source</h2>

<p>Campfire remains true to our goals of being free and open source. All source code is available on <a href="https://github.com/firoorg/campfire">GitHub</a>.</p>

<p>While the original Campfire started as a Firo wallet that supported our previous privacy protocol, Lelantus, the new revamped Campfire has full Spark privacy support and shares the same internals as Stack wallet, a multi-coin wallet also developed by Cypher Stack.</p>

<h2 id="download-campfire-here"><a href="https://firo.org/get-firo/download/">Download Campfire Here</a></h2>

<h2 id="whats-next">What’s next?</h2>

<p>We would like to develop more features for Campfire, such as DEX support and Spark asset support!</p>

<p>If you want to donate to this cause, you can do so through <a href="https://funding.firo.org/proposals/campfire-development-donation-ajaydono">this Firo Crowdfunding proposal</a>.</p>

<h2 id="special-thanks">Special Thanks</h2>

<p>We would like to thank Rasikh Morani from Arcadia, who provided the initial funding for Campfire and Cypher Stack, whose development and research services have greatly improved Firo and its technology stack.</p>

<p>We also would like to thank the Firo Community Fund Committee, whose continued support of core team activities has made this possible.</p>]]></content><author><name>Reuben Yap</name></author><category term="community" /><category term="news" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[We are proud to release our new revamped Campfire wallet in collaboration with Cypher Stack. Campfire is a Firo-only wallet with a default on Spark privacy. It features many other Firo-specific enhancements, such as masternode collateral recognition and EX-address support. It also includes inbuilt TOR for additional network privacy. It even works on both desktop and mobile devices! Like its namesake, Campfire is designed to be a warm, welcoming experience where our Firofam can begin their privacy journey. Improved User Experience Much work has been put into making the wallet user-friendly with Firo colours, and our Sparky mascot is featured prominently. Under the hood, both teams have made many optimisations to make Spark transactions and syncing speedy and snappy, even with the complex math behind them. Instead of using the default server, users can choose to host their own light server backend for even more privacy. Open source Campfire remains true to our goals of being free and open source. All source code is available on GitHub. While the original Campfire started as a Firo wallet that supported our previous privacy protocol, Lelantus, the new revamped Campfire has full Spark privacy support and shares the same internals as Stack wallet, a multi-coin wallet also developed by Cypher Stack. Download Campfire Here What’s next? We would like to develop more features for Campfire, such as DEX support and Spark asset support! If you want to donate to this cause, you can do so through this Firo Crowdfunding proposal. Special Thanks We would like to thank Rasikh Morani from Arcadia, who provided the initial funding for Campfire and Cypher Stack, whose development and research services have greatly improved Firo and its technology stack. We also would like to thank the Firo Community Fund Committee, whose continued support of core team activities has made this possible.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Binance adds new cross margin pair for FIRO</title><link href="https://firo.org/firo-site/pr-preview/pr-439/2024/06/25/binance-firo-cross-margin.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Binance adds new cross margin pair for FIRO" /><published>2024-06-25T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-06-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://firo.org/firo-site/pr-preview/pr-439/2024/06/25/binance-firo-cross-margin</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://firo.org/firo-site/pr-preview/pr-439/2024/06/25/binance-firo-cross-margin.html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="binance-adds-firousdt-cross-margin-pair">Binance Adds FIRO/USDT Cross Margin Pair!</h2>

<p>Binance has added the <a href="https://www.binance.com/en/support/announcement/binance-margin-adds-new-fdusd-usdc-and-usdt-pairs-2024-06-18-d9aba607bf2f4d41ac97d1c22ea41dea">FIRO/USDT pair to Cross Margin</a>. This adds to the existing FIRO/USDT spot and isolated margin pairs.</p>

<h2 id="what-is-cross-margin">What is Cross Margin?</h2>

<p>In Cross Margin, the entire margin balance is shared across open positions to avoid liquidation. If Cross Margin is enabled, the trader risks losing their entire margin balance, along with any open positions, in the event of a liquidation. Any realized PnL (profit and loss) from another position can support a losing position that is close to being liquidated.</p>

<p>With the existing Isolated Margin mode, you can allocate a specific amount of margin to a single position to limit risks. In contrast, the Cross Margin mode uses the balance of your entire Margin Account on Binance as collateral, providing you with greater flexibility and lower margin requirements. Read the difference between isolated and cross margin <a href="https://www.binance.info/en/support/faq/differences-between-isolated-margin-and-cross-margin-b4e9e6ad70934bd082e8e09e33e69513?hl=en">here</a>.</p>

<p>As always, trade responsibly!</p>]]></content><author><name>Augustus Jong</name></author><category term="community" /><category term="news" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Binance Adds FIRO/USDT Cross Margin Pair! Binance has added the FIRO/USDT pair to Cross Margin. This adds to the existing FIRO/USDT spot and isolated margin pairs. What is Cross Margin? In Cross Margin, the entire margin balance is shared across open positions to avoid liquidation. If Cross Margin is enabled, the trader risks losing their entire margin balance, along with any open positions, in the event of a liquidation. Any realized PnL (profit and loss) from another position can support a losing position that is close to being liquidated. With the existing Isolated Margin mode, you can allocate a specific amount of margin to a single position to limit risks. In contrast, the Cross Margin mode uses the balance of your entire Margin Account on Binance as collateral, providing you with greater flexibility and lower margin requirements. Read the difference between isolated and cross margin here. As always, trade responsibly!]]></summary></entry></feed>