<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="id"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://firo.org/firo-site/pr-preview/pr-461/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://firo.org/firo-site/pr-preview/pr-461/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="id" /><updated>2025-01-30T18:22:03+00:00</updated><id>https://firo.org/firo-site/pr-preview/pr-461/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Firo</title><subtitle>Firo is a cryptocurrency that focuses on privacy and fungibility.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Help Shape Firo’s Mining Future: Weigh In on FiroPoW’s VRAM Requirements</title><link href="https://firo.org/firo-site/pr-preview/pr-461/2025/01/30/firopow-vram-requirement.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Help Shape Firo’s Mining Future: Weigh In on FiroPoW’s VRAM Requirements" /><published>2025-01-30T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-01-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://firo.org/firo-site/pr-preview/pr-461/2025/01/30/firopow-vram-requirement</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://firo.org/firo-site/pr-preview/pr-461/2025/01/30/firopow-vram-requirement.html"><![CDATA[<p>Firo’s unique hybrid consensus model relies on both Masternodes and miners to secure our network. Mining remains an essential pillar—especially for those who prefer to acquire Firo without relying on an exchange. Recent developments, however, have prompted discussions about the VRAM requirements for mining Firo. We’d like the community’s input on how to proceed.</p>

<h2 id="background-firopows-increasing-dag-size">Background: FiroPOW’s Increasing DAG Size</h2>

<p>When FiroPOW was introduced in 2021, it began with a VRAM requirement of <strong>4 GB.</strong> From the outset, our mining algorithm was designed to steadily increase its DAG size. The purpose?</p>

<ol>
  <li>
    <p><strong>Discourage the use of older, dirt-cheap GPUs</strong> that large farms could easily accumulate.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p><strong>Maintain a level of decentralization</strong> by using relatively modern GPUs.</p>
  </li>
</ol>

<p>Since FiroPOW’s launch, the DAG size has continued to grow at approximately <strong>8 MB every 1,300 blocks</strong> (about <strong>2.26 days</strong>). Recently, it <strong>surpassed 7.7 GB</strong>, causing many 8 GB GPUs to fall below the mining threshold due to the GPU overhead.</p>

<h2 id="why-we-need-to-revisit-this">Why We Need to Revisit This</h2>

<ul>
  <li>
    <p><strong>Evolving GPU Market:</strong> Mid-range GPUs from 2015 typically had 2-4 GB of VRAM, increasing to 4–8 GB in the 2016–2019 period. Even in 2020–2023, many mid-range cards still ship with 6–8 GB. Meanwhile, rumors suggest the upcoming RTX 5060 may only have 8 GB of VRAM.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p><strong>Continued Role of Miners:</strong> Although Firo has a hybrid consensus system, miners still play an important part in securing the network and offering an alternative onramp to Firo ownership. If VRAM requirements climb too high, we risk excluding a broader audience of potential miners—particularly those using mid-range GPUs.</p>
  </li>
</ul>

<h2 id="balancing-accessibility-and-security">Balancing Accessibility and Security</h2>

<p>On one hand, <strong>increasing the DAG size</strong> reduces the risk of someone acquiring large amounts of outdated GPUs at bargain prices to exploit or attack the network. On the other hand, setting the VRAM requirement too high leaves many loyal miners—and potential new ones—unable to participate.</p>

<p><strong>Current Options Being Discussed</strong></p>

<ol>
  <li>
    <p><strong>Maintain the requirement at around 8GB:</strong></p>

    <ul>
      <li>
        <p>This aligns with most mid-range cards from the past few years.</p>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p>Ensures even upcoming rumored 8GB GPUs can participate.</p>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p>If VRAM trends change significantly, we can revisit in the future.</p>
      </li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p><strong>Lower to just under 6GB and allow it to creep up slowly:</strong></p>

    <ul>
      <li>
        <p>This potentially opens up Firo mining to more people immediately.</p>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p>Still gradually phases out older cards but at a slower rate.</p>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p>Balances concerns about security with broader accessibility.</p>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p>Possibly reduces the need for a future hard-fork when VRAM in GPUs increase</p>
      </li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p><strong>Keep status-quo</strong></p>

    <ul>
      <li>
        <p>Only higher-end cards can mine FIRO</p>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p>Potential reduction in security as less GPUs can participate</p>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p>More rewards for remaining miners who can still mine.</p>
      </li>
    </ul>
  </li>
</ol>

<h2 id="have-your-say-in-our-forum">Have Your Say in Our Forum</h2>

<p>We believe community feedback is vital to making the best decision for Firo’s long-term health. We invite you to:</p>

<ol>
  <li>
    <p><strong>Read the full discussion</strong> on our <a href="https://forum.firo.org/t/poll-what-should-the-vram-requirement-for-mining-firo-be/3877">official forum post.</a></p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p><strong>Cast your vote</strong> on the solution you think best supports Firo’s vision.</p>
  </li>
</ol>

<p>This is a critical moment to weigh in on the direction of our mining infrastructure. Your input will help shape how we balance accessibility with security, ensuring Firo remains both robust and welcoming to new and existing miners.</p>

<h3 id="next-steps">Next Steps</h3>

<ul>
  <li>
    <p><strong>Join the Discussion:</strong> Head over to our <a href="https://forum.firo.org/t/poll-what-should-the-vram-requirement-for-mining-firo-be/3877">forum thread</a> and share your thoughts. Ensure you’re at least Trust Level 1.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p><strong>Vote on Your Preferred Approach:</strong> A simple poll is available for you to vote on locking the VRAM requirement to slightly below 8GB or adjusting it to a slower growth rate starting near 6GB or just maintaining the status quo.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p><strong>Stay Informed:</strong> We will announce any consensus-driven changes and next steps on our official channels.</p>
  </li>
</ul>

<p>Thank you for being part of the Firo community. Together, we can chart a path forward that keeps our network secure, decentralized, and accessible to a broad range of miners.
<strong>—The Firo Core Team</strong></p>]]></content><author><name>Reuben Yap</name></author><category term="community" /><category term="news" /><category term="dev" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Firo’s unique hybrid consensus model relies on both Masternodes and miners to secure our network. Mining remains an essential pillar—especially for those who prefer to acquire Firo without relying on an exchange. Recent developments, however, have prompted discussions about the VRAM requirements for mining Firo. We’d like the community’s input on how to proceed. Background: FiroPOW’s Increasing DAG Size When FiroPOW was introduced in 2021, it began with a VRAM requirement of 4 GB. From the outset, our mining algorithm was designed to steadily increase its DAG size. The purpose? Discourage the use of older, dirt-cheap GPUs that large farms could easily accumulate. Maintain a level of decentralization by using relatively modern GPUs. Since FiroPOW’s launch, the DAG size has continued to grow at approximately 8 MB every 1,300 blocks (about 2.26 days). Recently, it surpassed 7.7 GB, causing many 8 GB GPUs to fall below the mining threshold due to the GPU overhead. Why We Need to Revisit This Evolving GPU Market: Mid-range GPUs from 2015 typically had 2-4 GB of VRAM, increasing to 4–8 GB in the 2016–2019 period. Even in 2020–2023, many mid-range cards still ship with 6–8 GB. Meanwhile, rumors suggest the upcoming RTX 5060 may only have 8 GB of VRAM. Continued Role of Miners: Although Firo has a hybrid consensus system, miners still play an important part in securing the network and offering an alternative onramp to Firo ownership. If VRAM requirements climb too high, we risk excluding a broader audience of potential miners—particularly those using mid-range GPUs. Balancing Accessibility and Security On one hand, increasing the DAG size reduces the risk of someone acquiring large amounts of outdated GPUs at bargain prices to exploit or attack the network. On the other hand, setting the VRAM requirement too high leaves many loyal miners—and potential new ones—unable to participate. Current Options Being Discussed Maintain the requirement at around 8GB: This aligns with most mid-range cards from the past few years. Ensures even upcoming rumored 8GB GPUs can participate. If VRAM trends change significantly, we can revisit in the future. Lower to just under 6GB and allow it to creep up slowly: This potentially opens up Firo mining to more people immediately. Still gradually phases out older cards but at a slower rate. Balances concerns about security with broader accessibility. Possibly reduces the need for a future hard-fork when VRAM in GPUs increase Keep status-quo Only higher-end cards can mine FIRO Potential reduction in security as less GPUs can participate More rewards for remaining miners who can still mine. Have Your Say in Our Forum We believe community feedback is vital to making the best decision for Firo’s long-term health. We invite you to: Read the full discussion on our official forum post. Cast your vote on the solution you think best supports Firo’s vision. This is a critical moment to weigh in on the direction of our mining infrastructure. Your input will help shape how we balance accessibility with security, ensuring Firo remains both robust and welcoming to new and existing miners. Next Steps Join the Discussion: Head over to our forum thread and share your thoughts. Ensure you’re at least Trust Level 1. Vote on Your Preferred Approach: A simple poll is available for you to vote on locking the VRAM requirement to slightly below 8GB or adjusting it to a slower growth rate starting near 6GB or just maintaining the status quo. Stay Informed: We will announce any consensus-driven changes and next steps on our official channels. Thank you for being part of the Firo community. Together, we can chart a path forward that keeps our network secure, decentralized, and accessible to a broad range of miners. —The Firo Core Team]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Firo Spark Names</title><link href="https://firo.org/firo-site/pr-preview/pr-461/2025/01/28/spark-names.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Firo Spark Names" /><published>2025-01-28T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-01-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://firo.org/firo-site/pr-preview/pr-461/2025/01/28/spark-names</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://firo.org/firo-site/pr-preview/pr-461/2025/01/28/spark-names.html"><![CDATA[<p>We have a new feature coming to Firo which greatly improves two of the biggest pain points of dealing with crypto: hard to remember cryptocurrency addresses and digital identity!</p>

<p>Spark Names allows users to register user-friendly human-readable names to <a href="/firo-site/pr-preview/pr-461/id/2021/08/24/presenting-lelantus-spark.html">privacy preserving Spark Addresses</a> directly on Firo’s blockchain, for e.g. ‘@sparky’ instead of a lengthy 144 character Spark address. Spark Names also allow you to attach metadata to it allowing you to add any information you wish to associate with your handle.</p>

<p>While the idea of registering human readable aliases to crypto addresses is not new, as seen in Namecoin, Ethereum Name Service, FIO, Handshake and Zano aliases, our Spark Names implementation offers some advantages over existing naming systems..</p>

<h3 id="i--spark-names-as-your-digital-identity">i)  Spark Names as your Digital Identity</h3>
<p>Spark Names not only tie Spark addresses to a name but can also serve as your decentralized digital identity! While many other address alias protocols primarily focus only on tying handles to crypto addresses, Spark Names allows you to optionally add metadata to your Spark Name, be it social media handles, avatar urls, and any other text based data so that your Spark Name can identify you while keeping your transaction history private. Metadata can be updated through a renewal which you can perform at any time.</p>

<h3 id="ii-spark-names-does-not-compromise-on-privacy">ii) Spark Names does not compromise on privacy:</h3>
<p>In many alias systems like ENS, the alias is tied to a crypto address that can be looked up on the blockchain. This is a huge privacy risk as now everyone not only knows that the address belongs to you, but can see all transaction activity associated with it.</p>

<p><img src="/blog/assets/spark-names/image1.png" alt="Image1" /></p>

<p>Spark Names are tied to privacy preserving Spark Addresses (a type of stealth address) which are not searchable on the blockchain, so someone with your Spark Name can only resolve to a Spark Address which does not reveal any transaction details associated with it. This means you can freely share your Spark Name out without someone getting information about the transactions you receive or send much like an e-mail address!</p>

<h3 id="iii-spark-name-fees-fund-community-fund">iii) Spark Name fees fund Community Fund</h3>

<p>As the Firo project doesn’t rely on funding from VCs or investors, it primarily relies on donations and a percentage of the block reward. As Firo gradually moves into decentralized funding, additional continuing sources of revenue are important. All Spark Name related fees are channeled towards the Community Fund led by the community elected <a href="/firo-site/pr-preview/pr-461/id/2022/07/04/community-fund-committee-elected.html">Community Fund Committee</a> which is independent from the Core team. These funds can be used to fund various tasks such as audits, community initiatives, listings or even development tasks to support Firo and its ecosystem.</p>

<p>In future updates should the community desire, Spark Name fees can be burnt or channeled towards miners or masternode holders that can be helpful when Firo goes into tail emission in a couple of years.</p>

<h3 id="iv-spark-names-requires-renewal">iv) Spark Names requires renewal</h3>

<p>Some naming schemes allow perpetual registration which can result in squatting where one user just hogs a lot of potential names. While requiring renewal does not completely prevent this, it ensures that there’s an ongoing price to squat or at least pay a bigger fee upfront to secure a multi-year registration. This also partially addresses issues where users become inactive and yet hold on to valuable aliases. Having Spark Names fee model in this way generates organic demand for FIRO and an ongoing revenue source for the FIRO ecosystem.</p>

<h3 id="v--fee-structure-based-on-length">v)  Fee structure based on length</h3>

<p>Spark Name’s fee structure is based on the length of the Spark Name where shorter names have higher fees.</p>

<ul>
  <li>One character: 1000 FIRO/year</li>
  <li>Two characters: 100 FIRO/year</li>
  <li>3-5 characters: 10 FIRO/year</li>
  <li>6 characters and above: 1 FIRO/year</li>
</ul>

<p>This properly recognizes the scarcity of shorter names while keeping it affordable to most users instead of a flat rate. Users are free to pre-purchase as many years as they want in advance.</p>

<h3 id="vi-ownership-proof">vi) Ownership proof</h3>

<p>To prevent abuse, users can only register aliases to Spark addresses that they control and not third parties since registration requires an ownership proof. This prevents someone from assigning derogatory or offensive names to your Spark address. In the same logic, we also only allow one Spark Name per Spark address to minimize the chance of confusion.</p>

<h3 id="vii-transfer-of-ownership">vii) Transfer of ownership</h3>

<p>Spark Names allows for the transfer of ownership to a new user should a user decide to sell it. This feature would be unavailable at launch but will be added on at a later time.</p>

<h3 id="when">When?</h3>

<p>We are in the final stages of coding Spark Names and have released it on our internal devnet. We expect to release Spark Names on testnet in a week or two and mainnet in a month after that. We would be requiring a hard fork along with other updates when we roll out Spark Names.</p>

<p>Spark name functionality is also being added into our mobile wallets.</p>

<p>The core team is excited to bring a new level of usability and added functionality to FIRO with Spark Names!</p>]]></content><author><name>Reuben Yap</name></author><category term="community" /><category term="news" /><category term="dev" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[We have a new feature coming to Firo which greatly improves two of the biggest pain points of dealing with crypto: hard to remember cryptocurrency addresses and digital identity! Spark Names allows users to register user-friendly human-readable names to privacy preserving Spark Addresses directly on Firo’s blockchain, for e.g. ‘@sparky’ instead of a lengthy 144 character Spark address. Spark Names also allow you to attach metadata to it allowing you to add any information you wish to associate with your handle. While the idea of registering human readable aliases to crypto addresses is not new, as seen in Namecoin, Ethereum Name Service, FIO, Handshake and Zano aliases, our Spark Names implementation offers some advantages over existing naming systems.. i) Spark Names as your Digital Identity Spark Names not only tie Spark addresses to a name but can also serve as your decentralized digital identity! While many other address alias protocols primarily focus only on tying handles to crypto addresses, Spark Names allows you to optionally add metadata to your Spark Name, be it social media handles, avatar urls, and any other text based data so that your Spark Name can identify you while keeping your transaction history private. Metadata can be updated through a renewal which you can perform at any time. ii) Spark Names does not compromise on privacy: In many alias systems like ENS, the alias is tied to a crypto address that can be looked up on the blockchain. This is a huge privacy risk as now everyone not only knows that the address belongs to you, but can see all transaction activity associated with it. Spark Names are tied to privacy preserving Spark Addresses (a type of stealth address) which are not searchable on the blockchain, so someone with your Spark Name can only resolve to a Spark Address which does not reveal any transaction details associated with it. This means you can freely share your Spark Name out without someone getting information about the transactions you receive or send much like an e-mail address! iii) Spark Name fees fund Community Fund As the Firo project doesn’t rely on funding from VCs or investors, it primarily relies on donations and a percentage of the block reward. As Firo gradually moves into decentralized funding, additional continuing sources of revenue are important. All Spark Name related fees are channeled towards the Community Fund led by the community elected Community Fund Committee which is independent from the Core team. These funds can be used to fund various tasks such as audits, community initiatives, listings or even development tasks to support Firo and its ecosystem. In future updates should the community desire, Spark Name fees can be burnt or channeled towards miners or masternode holders that can be helpful when Firo goes into tail emission in a couple of years. iv) Spark Names requires renewal Some naming schemes allow perpetual registration which can result in squatting where one user just hogs a lot of potential names. While requiring renewal does not completely prevent this, it ensures that there’s an ongoing price to squat or at least pay a bigger fee upfront to secure a multi-year registration. This also partially addresses issues where users become inactive and yet hold on to valuable aliases. Having Spark Names fee model in this way generates organic demand for FIRO and an ongoing revenue source for the FIRO ecosystem. v) Fee structure based on length Spark Name’s fee structure is based on the length of the Spark Name where shorter names have higher fees. One character: 1000 FIRO/year Two characters: 100 FIRO/year 3-5 characters: 10 FIRO/year 6 characters and above: 1 FIRO/year This properly recognizes the scarcity of shorter names while keeping it affordable to most users instead of a flat rate. Users are free to pre-purchase as many years as they want in advance. vi) Ownership proof To prevent abuse, users can only register aliases to Spark addresses that they control and not third parties since registration requires an ownership proof. This prevents someone from assigning derogatory or offensive names to your Spark address. In the same logic, we also only allow one Spark Name per Spark address to minimize the chance of confusion. vii) Transfer of ownership Spark Names allows for the transfer of ownership to a new user should a user decide to sell it. This feature would be unavailable at launch but will be added on at a later time. When? We are in the final stages of coding Spark Names and have released it on our internal devnet. We expect to release Spark Names on testnet in a week or two and mainnet in a month after that. We would be requiring a hard fork along with other updates when we roll out Spark Names. Spark name functionality is also being added into our mobile wallets. The core team is excited to bring a new level of usability and added functionality to FIRO with Spark Names!]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Firo USDT-M Perpetual Futures now available on MEXC</title><link href="https://firo.org/firo-site/pr-preview/pr-461/2025/01/08/mexc-futures-firo.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Firo USDT-M Perpetual Futures now available on MEXC" /><published>2025-01-08T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-01-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://firo.org/firo-site/pr-preview/pr-461/2025/01/08/mexc-futures-firo</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://firo.org/firo-site/pr-preview/pr-461/2025/01/08/mexc-futures-firo.html"><![CDATA[<p>MEXC has launched <a href="https://futures.mexc.com/exchange/FIRO_USDT">FIRO Perpetual Futures contracts</a> with up to 50x leverage, available in both cross and isolated margin modes.</p>

<h3 id="what-are-perpetual-futures">What Are Perpetual Futures?</h3>

<p>Perpetual futures contracts, unlike traditional futures contracts with expiration dates, can be held indefinitely, providing traders with a flexible tool for both hedging and speculation in the cryptocurrency market.</p>

<p>Learn more about Perpetual Futures <a href="https://coinmarketcap.com/academy/glossary/perpetual-futures">here</a>.</p>

<p><strong>Note</strong>: While perpetual futures can be a powerful tool for experienced traders, they carry significant risk due to the use of leverage.</p>

<p>As always, trade responsibly and be aware of the risks of perpetual futures!</p>]]></content><author><name>Augustus Jong</name></author><category term="community" /><category term="news" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[MEXC has launched FIRO Perpetual Futures contracts with up to 50x leverage, available in both cross and isolated margin modes. What Are Perpetual Futures? Perpetual futures contracts, unlike traditional futures contracts with expiration dates, can be held indefinitely, providing traders with a flexible tool for both hedging and speculation in the cryptocurrency market. Learn more about Perpetual Futures here. Note: While perpetual futures can be a powerful tool for experienced traders, they carry significant risk due to the use of leverage. As always, trade responsibly and be aware of the risks of perpetual futures!]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Firo listed on Biconomy</title><link href="https://firo.org/firo-site/pr-preview/pr-461/2024/12/02/firo-listed-on-biconomy.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Firo listed on Biconomy" /><published>2024-12-02T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-12-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://firo.org/firo-site/pr-preview/pr-461/2024/12/02/firo-listed-on-biconomy</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://firo.org/firo-site/pr-preview/pr-461/2024/12/02/firo-listed-on-biconomy.html"><![CDATA[<p>We are thrilled to announce that Firo is now listed on <a href="https://www.biconomy.com/">Biconomy</a> with a USDT trading pair!</p>

<p>To celebrate this listing, Biconomy is hosting a Kickstarter session where users can commit USDT tokens for a chance to earn airdrop rewards totaling $2,500 in Firo and $1,000 in USDT.</p>

<p>For more details, visit: <a href="https://biconomy.zendesk.com/hc/en-us/articles/40679980919961-Biconomy-FIRO-Kickstarter-2-500-FIRO-and-1-000-USDT-Airdrops">Biconomy Firo Kickstarter</a>. Stay tuned for other activities coming really soon!</p>

<p>The Biconomy listing supports both native FIRO and BEP20 FIRO networks and most notably also supports direct withdrawal to Spark addresses from the exchange for added privacy making it the 2nd centralized exchange to do so.</p>

<h2 id="about-biconomy">About Biconomy</h2>

<p>Biconomy.com is a cryptocurrency trading and investment platform that enables users to easily buy, sell, exchange, and store digital assets. Designed with an intuitive and beginner-friendly interface, it supports key crypto transactions, digital wallets, and payment methods like SEPA and SWIFT.</p>

<p>Established in October 2019, Biconomy.com serves over 1 million users and institutions globally, offering access to a wide range of assets and contracts across Spot markets and crypto derivatives such as Futures and Options. The platform also includes features like Demo and Copy Trading, Launchpad projects, Earn and Kickstarter programs, an NFT Marketplace, and more.</p>]]></content><author><name>Augustus Jong</name></author><category term="community" /><category term="news" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[We are thrilled to announce that Firo is now listed on Biconomy with a USDT trading pair! To celebrate this listing, Biconomy is hosting a Kickstarter session where users can commit USDT tokens for a chance to earn airdrop rewards totaling $2,500 in Firo and $1,000 in USDT. For more details, visit: Biconomy Firo Kickstarter. Stay tuned for other activities coming really soon! The Biconomy listing supports both native FIRO and BEP20 FIRO networks and most notably also supports direct withdrawal to Spark addresses from the exchange for added privacy making it the 2nd centralized exchange to do so. About Biconomy Biconomy.com is a cryptocurrency trading and investment platform that enables users to easily buy, sell, exchange, and store digital assets. Designed with an intuitive and beginner-friendly interface, it supports key crypto transactions, digital wallets, and payment methods like SEPA and SWIFT. Established in October 2019, Biconomy.com serves over 1 million users and institutions globally, offering access to a wide range of assets and contracts across Spot markets and crypto derivatives such as Futures and Options. The platform also includes features like Demo and Copy Trading, Launchpad projects, Earn and Kickstarter programs, an NFT Marketplace, and more.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">MAGIC approves grant to develop Enkrypt wallet integration</title><link href="https://firo.org/firo-site/pr-preview/pr-461/2024/11/25/magic-grant-enkrypt-wallet-integration.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="MAGIC approves grant to develop Enkrypt wallet integration" /><published>2024-11-25T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-11-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://firo.org/firo-site/pr-preview/pr-461/2024/11/25/magic-grant-enkrypt-wallet-integration</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://firo.org/firo-site/pr-preview/pr-461/2024/11/25/magic-grant-enkrypt-wallet-integration.html"><![CDATA[<p>We are thrilled to announce that MAGIC Grants has approved a grant from the MAGIC Firo Fund to integrate Firo, a leading privacy-preserving cryptocurrency, with the <a href="https://www.enkrypt.com/">Enkrypt</a> wallet. The integration work will be spearheaded by <a href="https://blockstars.tech/">BlockStars</a>, a renowned web3 development company. This collaboration will include full support for Spark, enhancing the usability and accessibility of Firo within a multi-chain ecosystem. We expect the work to take about 3 months.</p>

<h2 id="elevating-privacy-and-accessibility-with-enkrypt">Elevating Privacy and Accessibility with Enkrypt</h2>

<p>The integration of Firo into Enkrypt wallet marks a significant milestone in our mission to provide users with seamless and secure access to privacy-focused financial solutions. Enkrypt is not just another crypto wallet; it’s a true multichain browser extension wallet developed by <a href="https://www.myetherwallet.com/">MyEtherWallet</a>. With support for over 70 natively integrated chains—including Ethereum, Bitcoin, Solana, and many more—Enkrypt offers a unified platform for managing diverse digital assets.</p>

<h3 id="why-enkrypt">Why Enkrypt?</h3>

<ul>
  <li><strong>Multichain Support</strong>: Access EVM chains, Solana, Parachains, Canto, and the Bitcoin Network—all with a single account.</li>
  <li><strong>User-Friendly Interface</strong>: Easy access to the world of web3 with integrated DApps and NFT management.</li>
  <li><strong>One Recovery Phrase</strong>: Simplify your crypto experience with one recovery phrase for all chains.</li>
  <li><strong>Security and Control</strong>: An open-source, self-custody wallet where users have full control over their digital assets.</li>
</ul>

<p>By integrating Firo into Enkrypt, we are enabling our community to manage their Firo holdings alongside other cryptocurrencies, all within a single, user-friendly platform.</p>

<h2 id="full-spark-support">Full Spark Support</h2>

<p>The integration will include comprehensive support for Spark, Firo’s innovative protocol that enhances privacy. This means users will enjoy all the benefits of Spark directly within the Enkrypt wallet, including easy swaps from other assets and improved privacy features.</p>

<h2 id="about-magic-grants-and-the-magic-firo-fund">About MAGIC Grants and the MAGIC Firo Fund</h2>

<p><a href="https://magicgrants.org">MAGIC Grants</a> is a 501(c)(3) public charity that supports essential public infrastructure for  cryptocurrency networks and supports privacy. Through the establishment of semi-autonomous MAGIC Funds, communities can fund various qualifying activities such as educational materials, essential development projects, research, and security audits.</p>

<p>The <a href="https://magicgrants.org/funds/firo">MAGIC Firo Fund</a>, established in December 2022, operates independently from the Firo Core team and is administered by the MAGIC Board. Funded by generous donations from Firo supporters like Arcadia, donations to the fund are tax-deductible for U.S.-based contributors.</p>

<h2 id="blockstars">BlockStars</h2>

<p><a href="https://blockstars.tech/">BlockStars</a>, is a blockchain-based software development company committed to bringing the power of blockchain technology to businesses worldwide. BlockStars specializes in developing real-world decentralized applications, smart contracts, NFTs, DeFi apps, and blockchain gaming solutions. Their expertise ensures that the Firo integration with Enkrypt will be seamless, secure, and efficient.</p>

<h2 id="the-benefits-of-a-multichain-browser-extension-wallet">The Benefits of a Multichain Browser Extension Wallet</h2>

<p>Integrating Firo into a multichain wallet like Enkrypt offers numerous benefits:</p>

<ul>
  <li><strong>Convenience</strong>: Manage multiple cryptocurrencies across different blockchains in one place.</li>
  <li><strong>Enhanced Security</strong>: Benefit from self-custody and open-source security features.</li>
  <li><strong>Unified Experience</strong>: Access a wide range of decentralized applications and services without switching wallets.</li>
  <li><strong>Future-Proof</strong>: Easily adopt new blockchain innovations as they are integrated into Enkrypt.</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="looking-ahead">Looking Ahead</h2>

<p>This integration is a significant step forward in making Firo more accessible and user-friendly. We believe that by partnering with MAGIC Grants, Enkrypt, and BlockStars, we are paving the way for a more private, secure, and inclusive financial future.</p>

<p>Stay tuned for updates on the integration progress. We are committed to keeping our community informed every step of the way.</p>]]></content><author><name>Reuben Yap</name></author><category term="community" /><category term="news" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[We are thrilled to announce that MAGIC Grants has approved a grant from the MAGIC Firo Fund to integrate Firo, a leading privacy-preserving cryptocurrency, with the Enkrypt wallet. The integration work will be spearheaded by BlockStars, a renowned web3 development company. This collaboration will include full support for Spark, enhancing the usability and accessibility of Firo within a multi-chain ecosystem. We expect the work to take about 3 months. Elevating Privacy and Accessibility with Enkrypt The integration of Firo into Enkrypt wallet marks a significant milestone in our mission to provide users with seamless and secure access to privacy-focused financial solutions. Enkrypt is not just another crypto wallet; it’s a true multichain browser extension wallet developed by MyEtherWallet. With support for over 70 natively integrated chains—including Ethereum, Bitcoin, Solana, and many more—Enkrypt offers a unified platform for managing diverse digital assets. Why Enkrypt? Multichain Support: Access EVM chains, Solana, Parachains, Canto, and the Bitcoin Network—all with a single account. User-Friendly Interface: Easy access to the world of web3 with integrated DApps and NFT management. One Recovery Phrase: Simplify your crypto experience with one recovery phrase for all chains. Security and Control: An open-source, self-custody wallet where users have full control over their digital assets. By integrating Firo into Enkrypt, we are enabling our community to manage their Firo holdings alongside other cryptocurrencies, all within a single, user-friendly platform. Full Spark Support The integration will include comprehensive support for Spark, Firo’s innovative protocol that enhances privacy. This means users will enjoy all the benefits of Spark directly within the Enkrypt wallet, including easy swaps from other assets and improved privacy features. About MAGIC Grants and the MAGIC Firo Fund MAGIC Grants is a 501(c)(3) public charity that supports essential public infrastructure for cryptocurrency networks and supports privacy. Through the establishment of semi-autonomous MAGIC Funds, communities can fund various qualifying activities such as educational materials, essential development projects, research, and security audits. The MAGIC Firo Fund, established in December 2022, operates independently from the Firo Core team and is administered by the MAGIC Board. Funded by generous donations from Firo supporters like Arcadia, donations to the fund are tax-deductible for U.S.-based contributors. BlockStars BlockStars, is a blockchain-based software development company committed to bringing the power of blockchain technology to businesses worldwide. BlockStars specializes in developing real-world decentralized applications, smart contracts, NFTs, DeFi apps, and blockchain gaming solutions. Their expertise ensures that the Firo integration with Enkrypt will be seamless, secure, and efficient. The Benefits of a Multichain Browser Extension Wallet Integrating Firo into a multichain wallet like Enkrypt offers numerous benefits: Convenience: Manage multiple cryptocurrencies across different blockchains in one place. Enhanced Security: Benefit from self-custody and open-source security features. Unified Experience: Access a wide range of decentralized applications and services without switching wallets. Future-Proof: Easily adopt new blockchain innovations as they are integrated into Enkrypt. Looking Ahead This integration is a significant step forward in making Firo more accessible and user-friendly. We believe that by partnering with MAGIC Grants, Enkrypt, and BlockStars, we are paving the way for a more private, secure, and inclusive financial future. Stay tuned for updates on the integration progress. We are committed to keeping our community informed every step of the way.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">BEP20 FIRO Liquidity Injection</title><link href="https://firo.org/firo-site/pr-preview/pr-461/2024/10/17/powerupprivacy-firo-liquidity-injection.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="BEP20 FIRO Liquidity Injection" /><published>2024-10-17T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-10-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://firo.org/firo-site/pr-preview/pr-461/2024/10/17/powerupprivacy-firo-liquidity-injection</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://firo.org/firo-site/pr-preview/pr-461/2024/10/17/powerupprivacy-firo-liquidity-injection.html"><![CDATA[<p>We are happy to announce the addition of  80,356.8262 BEP20-FIRO and 167.286754 BNB (~200,000 USD) to the <a href="https://pancakeswap.finance/swap?outputCurrency=0xd5d0322b6bAb6a762C79f8c81A0B674778E13aeD&amp;inputCurrency=0x55d398326f99059fF775485246999027B3197955">Pancakeswap pool</a> on BNB Chain provided by the generous people at <a href="https://powerupprivacy.com/">Power Up Privacy</a>. This also adds to the existing position that is maintained by the Firo Community Fund bringing the total in the pool of ~224,000 USD at the time of writing. The addition of this liquidity brings much needed depth and usability to the pool.</p>

<p>BEP20-FIRO is a wrapped version of FIRO that is issued and backed 1:1 with native FIRO by Binance. As a BEP20 token on BNB Chain, it does not have privacy features but it allows permissionless access to BNB Chain’s rich DeFi ecosystem such as AMM DEXes and also access to all major stablecoins that are either native to BNB Chain or can be bridged into it.</p>

<p>Binance has <a href="https://bscscan.com/tx/0x834c69aae5aa972f6fb9cfb4b0d1a8fbf051fd86867f216799b13c81a684fe36">recently minted an additional 400,000 BEP20-FIRO</a> and its backing of native FIRO can be verified on-chain at this <a href="https://explorer.firo.org/address/a8tXPzGEYxcehK6ehfpCUXTtQ6VocQHHRT">address</a>.</p>

<p>BEP20-FIRO can be swapped to and from native FIRO either through FiroDEX or Komodo Platform, swap providers such as ChangeNow or directly through Binance or MEXC. We’ll be posting more detailed guides on each of these options soon.</p>]]></content><author><name>Reuben Yap</name></author><category term="community" /><category term="news" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[We are happy to announce the addition of 80,356.8262 BEP20-FIRO and 167.286754 BNB (~200,000 USD) to the Pancakeswap pool on BNB Chain provided by the generous people at Power Up Privacy. This also adds to the existing position that is maintained by the Firo Community Fund bringing the total in the pool of ~224,000 USD at the time of writing. The addition of this liquidity brings much needed depth and usability to the pool. BEP20-FIRO is a wrapped version of FIRO that is issued and backed 1:1 with native FIRO by Binance. As a BEP20 token on BNB Chain, it does not have privacy features but it allows permissionless access to BNB Chain’s rich DeFi ecosystem such as AMM DEXes and also access to all major stablecoins that are either native to BNB Chain or can be bridged into it. Binance has recently minted an additional 400,000 BEP20-FIRO and its backing of native FIRO can be verified on-chain at this address. BEP20-FIRO can be swapped to and from native FIRO either through FiroDEX or Komodo Platform, swap providers such as ChangeNow or directly through Binance or MEXC. We’ll be posting more detailed guides on each of these options soon.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Firo 24-Week Liquidity Mining Campaign</title><link href="https://firo.org/firo-site/pr-preview/pr-461/2024/09/24/firo-liquidity-campaign-sept24.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Firo 24-Week Liquidity Mining Campaign" /><published>2024-09-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-09-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://firo.org/firo-site/pr-preview/pr-461/2024/09/24/firo-liquidity-campaign-sept24</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://firo.org/firo-site/pr-preview/pr-461/2024/09/24/firo-liquidity-campaign-sept24.html"><![CDATA[<p>We are excited to share that the Liquidity campaign is back! Now for 24 weeks with a total reward pool of approximately ~US$19,200 up for grabs! Provide liquidity on Binance and AscendEX via Hummingbot and earn Firo!</p>

<p><img src="/blog/assets/firo-liquidity-campaign-sept24/img1.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<h2 id="campaign-terms">Campaign Terms</h2>

<ul>
  <li>
    <p>Start date: <strong>September 24, 2024, 12:00 AM UTC</strong></p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Total reward pool*: <strong>~US$19,200</strong> (FIRO 684 per week)</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Reward token: <strong>FIRO</strong></p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Eligible token pair: <strong>FIRO/USDT</strong></p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Eligible orders: maker orders placed with spreads of <strong>2.0%</strong> or lower</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Exchange: <strong><a href="https://accounts.binance.com/en/register?ref=37748947">Binance</a></strong> and <strong><a href="https://ascendex.com/en-us/register?inviteCode=URUFAVHHY">AscendEX</a></strong></p>
  </li>
</ul>

<h2 id="what-is-hummingbot">What is Hummingbot?</h2>

<p>Hummingbot Liquidity Mining is a decentralized, community-based market making. It allows anyone (communities, the general market) to participate in market making for a coin/token and contribute to its liquidity and improve the tradability of that coin/token. By participating, users are not only helping to support the coin/token and the project, but through liquidity mining, they are able to earn coin/token rewards based on their trading activity.</p>

<h2 id="how-does-the-campaign-work">How Does the Campaign Work?</h2>

<p>During the campaign, users who provide liquidity to the FIRO/USDT pair on Binance and AscendEX will earn rewards in Firo weekly.</p>

<h2 id="how-to-get-started">How to Get Started?</h2>

<p>To join the campaign, you’ll need to set up your wallet using the <a href="https://miner.hummingbot.io/">Hummingbot Miner App</a>. A detailed setup guide and How-To Articles are available on the <a href="https://support.hummingbot.io/miner/getting-started">Hummingbot website</a>. After installation, you can follow the instructions to connect the app to the Binance and AscendEX exchanges and begin providing liquidity to the FIRO/USDT pool.</p>

<p>Don’t miss this amazing chance to earn rewards while engaging with the Firo community! Whether you’re a current participant or new to liquidity mining, we invite you to take part and enjoy the benefits firsthand.</p>

<p>*For full terms of the campaign, please read the full terms here <a href="https://support.hummingbot.io/miner/new-24-week-for-firo-liquidity-mining-campaign">Hummingbot New 24-week for FIRO liquidity mining campaign!</a></p>

<p>Learn more about Liquidity mining <a href="https://support.hummingbot.io/miner/liquidity-mining-explained">here</a></p>

<h2 id="thank-you">Thank you</h2>

<p>We extend our heartfelt thanks to Power Up Privacy who funded this campaign through their <a href="/firo-site/pr-preview/pr-461/id2024/08/10/firo-receive-donation-from-powerup-privacy.html">donation</a>. Discover more about Power Up Privacy <a href="https://powerupprivacy.com/">here</a></p>]]></content><author><name>Augustus Jong</name></author><category term="community" /><category term="news" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[We are excited to share that the Liquidity campaign is back! Now for 24 weeks with a total reward pool of approximately ~US$19,200 up for grabs! Provide liquidity on Binance and AscendEX via Hummingbot and earn Firo! Campaign Terms Start date: September 24, 2024, 12:00 AM UTC Total reward pool*: ~US$19,200 (FIRO 684 per week) Reward token: FIRO Eligible token pair: FIRO/USDT Eligible orders: maker orders placed with spreads of 2.0% or lower Exchange: Binance and AscendEX What is Hummingbot? Hummingbot Liquidity Mining is a decentralized, community-based market making. It allows anyone (communities, the general market) to participate in market making for a coin/token and contribute to its liquidity and improve the tradability of that coin/token. By participating, users are not only helping to support the coin/token and the project, but through liquidity mining, they are able to earn coin/token rewards based on their trading activity. How Does the Campaign Work? During the campaign, users who provide liquidity to the FIRO/USDT pair on Binance and AscendEX will earn rewards in Firo weekly. How to Get Started? To join the campaign, you’ll need to set up your wallet using the Hummingbot Miner App. A detailed setup guide and How-To Articles are available on the Hummingbot website. After installation, you can follow the instructions to connect the app to the Binance and AscendEX exchanges and begin providing liquidity to the FIRO/USDT pool. Don’t miss this amazing chance to earn rewards while engaging with the Firo community! Whether you’re a current participant or new to liquidity mining, we invite you to take part and enjoy the benefits firsthand. *For full terms of the campaign, please read the full terms here Hummingbot New 24-week for FIRO liquidity mining campaign! Learn more about Liquidity mining here Thank you We extend our heartfelt thanks to Power Up Privacy who funded this campaign through their donation. Discover more about Power Up Privacy here]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Firo Hardfork Completed Successfully</title><link href="https://firo.org/firo-site/pr-preview/pr-461/2024/09/18/hardfork-2024.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Firo Hardfork Completed Successfully" /><published>2024-09-18T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-09-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://firo.org/firo-site/pr-preview/pr-461/2024/09/18/hardfork-2024</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://firo.org/firo-site/pr-preview/pr-461/2024/09/18/hardfork-2024.html"><![CDATA[<p>The hard fork implementing the latest tokenomics changes as voted in by the community has been completed successfully. This upgrade introduces significant changes to our block reward distribution, emission model, and overall sustainability. Read more about these changes in our previous blog post on it <a href="/firo-site/pr-preview/pr-461/id/2024/09/01/finalized-tokenomics-2024.html">here</a>.</p>

<p>A huge thank you to our amazing ecosystem of masternode providers, mining pools, and the supportive community who voted in the <a href="/firo-site/pr-preview/pr-461/id/2024/09/01/finalized-tokenomics-2024.html">finalization of the community polls</a> and ensured a smooth transition. Together, we continue to create a place in privacy and decentralization in Firo!</p>

<p>The core team will be posting an updated proposed roadmap soon so stay tuned!</p>]]></content><author><name>Reuben Yap</name></author><category term="community" /><category term="news" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The hard fork implementing the latest tokenomics changes as voted in by the community has been completed successfully. This upgrade introduces significant changes to our block reward distribution, emission model, and overall sustainability. Read more about these changes in our previous blog post on it here. A huge thank you to our amazing ecosystem of masternode providers, mining pools, and the supportive community who voted in the finalization of the community polls and ensured a smooth transition. Together, we continue to create a place in privacy and decentralization in Firo! The core team will be posting an updated proposed roadmap soon so stay tuned!]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Firo Mandatory Release v0.14.14.0</title><link href="https://firo.org/firo-site/pr-preview/pr-461/2024/09/04/firo-release-014140-mandatory.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Firo Mandatory Release v0.14.14.0" /><published>2024-09-04T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-09-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://firo.org/firo-site/pr-preview/pr-461/2024/09/04/firo-release-014140-mandatory</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://firo.org/firo-site/pr-preview/pr-461/2024/09/04/firo-release-014140-mandatory.html"><![CDATA[<p>Following the <a href="https://firo.org/2024/09/01/finalized-tokenomics-2024.html">finalisation of the community polls</a> to determine Firo’s tokenomics, we are releasing Firo v0.14.14.0 with the agreed-upon changes that require a hard fork.</p>

<p>Please upgrade your wallets, daemons and masternodes to the latest Firo v0.14.14.0 before block 958655 (approximately 16 September 2024). <strong>This is a mandatory upgrade</strong>.</p>

<p>You can download them either from our <a href="https://firo.org/get-firo/download/">official download page</a> or our <a href="https://github.com/firoorg/firo/releases">Github release page</a>.</p>

<p>If you are using Campfire or Stack wallets, no updates are required, as the changes have been made in the backend.</p>]]></content><author><name>Reuben Yap</name></author><category term="community" /><category term="dev" /><category term="news" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Following the finalisation of the community polls to determine Firo’s tokenomics, we are releasing Firo v0.14.14.0 with the agreed-upon changes that require a hard fork. Please upgrade your wallets, daemons and masternodes to the latest Firo v0.14.14.0 before block 958655 (approximately 16 September 2024). This is a mandatory upgrade. You can download them either from our official download page or our Github release page. If you are using Campfire or Stack wallets, no updates are required, as the changes have been made in the backend.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Firo Finalized Tokenomics Results</title><link href="https://firo.org/firo-site/pr-preview/pr-461/2024/09/01/finalized-tokenomics-2024.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Firo Finalized Tokenomics Results" /><published>2024-09-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-09-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://firo.org/firo-site/pr-preview/pr-461/2024/09/01/finalized-tokenomics-2024</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://firo.org/firo-site/pr-preview/pr-461/2024/09/01/finalized-tokenomics-2024.html"><![CDATA[<p>Through Firo’s governance process, Firo’s emission and block reward division has been finalized! A huge thank you  to everyone who voted and shared their thoughts and feedback.</p>

<p>Through several rounds of polls, the community has decided on the implementation of three things to Firo’s tokenomics:</p>

<ul>
  <li>A fixed emission of 6.25 FIRO/block until the cap of 21.4 million FIRO is hit</li>
  <li>A tail emission of 1 FIRO/block thereafter</li>
  <li>A block reward division of 70% Masternodes, 5% Miners, 15% Dev, 10% Community (previously 50% Masternodes, 25% miners, 15% Dev, 10% community)</li>
</ul>

<p>View the <a href="https://forum.firo.org/t/poll-final-tokenomics-and-block-division/3379">final poll results</a></p>

<p>For a more accurate reflection of community sentiment, we employed a system known as <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=3Y3jE3B8HsE">ranked-choice voting or instant run-off</a>. This system allowed voters to select multiple choices and then rank them in order of preference, ensuring that the final decision better represents the community’s preferences.</p>

<h2 id="governance">Governance</h2>

<p>To read through how the Firo community arrived at this decision, you can follow the timeline and links to the relevant discussions below:</p>
<ul>
  <li>April 2024: Initial discussion about tokenomics. <a href="https://firo.org/2024/04/23/firo-tokenomics-and-halving.html">blog</a> <a href="https://forum.firo.org/t/firo-tokenomics-discussion-with-upcoming-halving/3162">forum</a></li>
  <li>June-July 2024: Polls were held regarding <a href="https://forum.firo.org/t/firo-tokenomics-discussion-with-upcoming-halving/3162">tail emission</a>, the <a href="https://forum.firo.org/t/poll-should-firo-continue-its-development-fund-and-community-fund/3274">development and community fund</a>, and <a href="https://forum.firo.org/t/poll-should-firo-keep-its-halving-schedule-or-should-we-revisit-our-emission-curve/3276">the rate of emission</a></li>
  <li>July 2024: A <a href="https://forum.firo.org/t/discussion-on-final-poll-options-for-tokenomics-and-block-division/3345">thread</a> was opened to ensure that the final poll’s voting options would cover all options that the community cared about.</li>
  <li>August 2024: <a href="https://forum.firo.org/t/poll-final-tokenomics-and-block-division/3379">Final polls</a> to vote on the proposed changes.</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="effect-of-changes">Effect of Changes</h2>

<p>The primary effect of the changes is to provide improved incentives for masternodes for the next 4 years, recognizing their continued role and unwavering support of the network. Miners will still contribute to the hybrid PoW/masternode consensus mechanism, but while the hashrate adjusts, there may be a period of slow blocks until the difficulty adjusts to the new hashrate. The chain will remain protected against 51% attacks with Firo’s <a href="https://firo.org/2021/01/28/chainlocks-activated-mainnet.html">masternode chainlocks</a>. Assuming current masternode numbers are maintained at around 3900+ master nodes, the current returns of a masternode will increase from around 16.5% p.a. to around 22% p.a.</p>

<p>There is also a significant change to the supply schedule of Firo to reflect the existence of developed infrastructure and markets for the distribution of cryptocurrencies compared to the time when Bitcoin was first created. Prior to the change, Firo followed Bitcoin’s emission schedule and the block reward would have halved roughly every 4 years with it finally ceasing after it hit 21.4 million. Firo has had a single halving prior to this and was set to have its 2nd halving in mid September 2024. With the new change coming into effect, there will be no more halvings and the existing emission of 6.25 FIRO/block is maintained until the supply of 21.4 million has been fully issued over the next 5-6 years.</p>

<p>After the 21.4 million limit is hit, to ensure a stable monetary supply and a continued stable security subsidy, a fixed tail emission of 1 FIRO/block will continue in perpetuity which works out to be 0.98% inflation rate p.a. at the beginning and over time trends to 0%. To read more about the effects of tail emission and how it leads to a stable monetary supply that is neither inflationary nor deflationary, you can read this <a href="https://petertodd.org/2022/surprisingly-tail-emission-is-not-inflationary">article</a>. There’s also strong <a href="https://www.cs.princeton.edu/~arvindn/publications/mining_CCS.pdf">academic evidence</a> that indicates that having no block reward results in instability in Bitcoin.</p>

<p>To view the effect of changes in tokenomics to Firo’s supply over time, we’ve plotted this graph starting from the hard fork date of block 958655 (approximately 16 September 2024) over the next 20 years. The times are estimated due to the slight variance in block times. Tail emission is hit roughly halfway into year 14 (5+ years from hard fork date).</p>

<p><img src="/blog/assets/finalized-tokenomics-2024/emissioncomparison2024.png" alt="Chart of emission, old versus new starting 2024" /></p>

<h2 id="future-direction">Future Direction</h2>

<p>The core team is making a firm commitment not to propose further changes to Firo’s tokenomics until tail emission is hit. This commitment is aimed at providing stability and certainty to the Firo community, ensuring a secure and confident future.</p>

<p>We will be deploying these changes in release <a href="https://github.com/firoorg/firo/releases/tag/v0.14.14.0">Firo v.14.14.0</a>, as these changes are scheduled to come into force by block 958655 (approximately 16 September 2024). Please ensure you are updated to the <a href="https://github.com/firoorg/firo/releases/latest">latest version</a> as soon as possible.</p>

<p>In the coming weeks, the core team will also be rolling out an updated roadmap for Firo, laying out development and adoption goals for the next few years. This will also include research into blockchain consensus models that would be secure and sustainable through tail emission and also a renewed focus on increasing awareness and adoption.</p>

<p>Again, we would like to thank the community members who have stood by the project and taking part in governance to guide Firo’s future.</p>]]></content><author><name>Reuben Yap</name></author><category term="community" /><category term="news" /><category term="dev" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Through Firo’s governance process, Firo’s emission and block reward division has been finalized! A huge thank you to everyone who voted and shared their thoughts and feedback. Through several rounds of polls, the community has decided on the implementation of three things to Firo’s tokenomics: A fixed emission of 6.25 FIRO/block until the cap of 21.4 million FIRO is hit A tail emission of 1 FIRO/block thereafter A block reward division of 70% Masternodes, 5% Miners, 15% Dev, 10% Community (previously 50% Masternodes, 25% miners, 15% Dev, 10% community) View the final poll results For a more accurate reflection of community sentiment, we employed a system known as ranked-choice voting or instant run-off. This system allowed voters to select multiple choices and then rank them in order of preference, ensuring that the final decision better represents the community’s preferences. Governance To read through how the Firo community arrived at this decision, you can follow the timeline and links to the relevant discussions below: April 2024: Initial discussion about tokenomics. blog forum June-July 2024: Polls were held regarding tail emission, the development and community fund, and the rate of emission July 2024: A thread was opened to ensure that the final poll’s voting options would cover all options that the community cared about. August 2024: Final polls to vote on the proposed changes. Effect of Changes The primary effect of the changes is to provide improved incentives for masternodes for the next 4 years, recognizing their continued role and unwavering support of the network. Miners will still contribute to the hybrid PoW/masternode consensus mechanism, but while the hashrate adjusts, there may be a period of slow blocks until the difficulty adjusts to the new hashrate. The chain will remain protected against 51% attacks with Firo’s masternode chainlocks. Assuming current masternode numbers are maintained at around 3900+ master nodes, the current returns of a masternode will increase from around 16.5% p.a. to around 22% p.a. There is also a significant change to the supply schedule of Firo to reflect the existence of developed infrastructure and markets for the distribution of cryptocurrencies compared to the time when Bitcoin was first created. Prior to the change, Firo followed Bitcoin’s emission schedule and the block reward would have halved roughly every 4 years with it finally ceasing after it hit 21.4 million. Firo has had a single halving prior to this and was set to have its 2nd halving in mid September 2024. With the new change coming into effect, there will be no more halvings and the existing emission of 6.25 FIRO/block is maintained until the supply of 21.4 million has been fully issued over the next 5-6 years. After the 21.4 million limit is hit, to ensure a stable monetary supply and a continued stable security subsidy, a fixed tail emission of 1 FIRO/block will continue in perpetuity which works out to be 0.98% inflation rate p.a. at the beginning and over time trends to 0%. To read more about the effects of tail emission and how it leads to a stable monetary supply that is neither inflationary nor deflationary, you can read this article. There’s also strong academic evidence that indicates that having no block reward results in instability in Bitcoin. To view the effect of changes in tokenomics to Firo’s supply over time, we’ve plotted this graph starting from the hard fork date of block 958655 (approximately 16 September 2024) over the next 20 years. The times are estimated due to the slight variance in block times. Tail emission is hit roughly halfway into year 14 (5+ years from hard fork date). Future Direction The core team is making a firm commitment not to propose further changes to Firo’s tokenomics until tail emission is hit. This commitment is aimed at providing stability and certainty to the Firo community, ensuring a secure and confident future. We will be deploying these changes in release Firo v.14.14.0, as these changes are scheduled to come into force by block 958655 (approximately 16 September 2024). Please ensure you are updated to the latest version as soon as possible. In the coming weeks, the core team will also be rolling out an updated roadmap for Firo, laying out development and adoption goals for the next few years. This will also include research into blockchain consensus models that would be secure and sustainable through tail emission and also a renewed focus on increasing awareness and adoption. Again, we would like to thank the community members who have stood by the project and taking part in governance to guide Firo’s future.]]></summary></entry></feed>