<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="id"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://firo.org/firo-site/pr-preview/pr-424/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://firo.org/firo-site/pr-preview/pr-424/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="id" /><updated>2024-09-01T13:11:15+00:00</updated><id>https://firo.org/firo-site/pr-preview/pr-424/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Firo</title><subtitle>Firo is a cryptocurrency that focuses on privacy and fungibility.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Together We Decide: Vote to Shape Firo’s Future!</title><link href="https://firo.org/firo-site/pr-preview/pr-424/2024/08/19/final-vote-tokenomics-2024.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Together We Decide: Vote to Shape Firo’s Future!" /><published>2024-08-19T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-08-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://firo.org/firo-site/pr-preview/pr-424/2024/08/19/final-vote-tokenomics-2024</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://firo.org/firo-site/pr-preview/pr-424/2024/08/19/final-vote-tokenomics-2024.html"><![CDATA[<p>The community has been actively discussing Firo’s economics, particularly its block reward division and emission model.</p>

<p>After seeking community feedback and <a href="https://forum.firo.org/t/poll-final-tokenomics-and-block-division/3379">preliminary polls</a> since June, we are now approaching the penultimate poll to definitively decide Firo’s future.</p>

<p>The two primary issues being voted on are:</p>

<ul>
  <li>What should Firo’s block reward division be?</li>
  <li>What should Firo’s emissions be?</li>
</ul>

<p>These polls touch on important issues, such as whether there should be a development and/or community fund, the sustainability of masternodes and the role of miners. It also looks into the long-term sustainability of Firo as to whether it should adopt a tail emission or stick closer to the original Bitcoin model.</p>

<p>Instead of a single-choice vote, the poll allows community members to rank their options, resulting in a fairer reflection of sentiment. This is also known as <a href="https://fairvote.org/our-reforms/ranked-choice-voting/">ranked-choice voting</a> and is suitable where there are many options to choose from.</p>

<p>You can view the previous discussions and polls here to help guide your decision!</p>

<ul>
  <li><a href="https://forum.firo.org/t/poll-should-firo-continue-its-development-fund-and-community-fund/3274">Development and Community Funds</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://forum.firo.org/t/poll-should-firo-have-a-tail-emission/3275">Tail Emission</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://forum.firo.org/t/poll-should-firo-keep-its-halving-schedule-or-should-we-revisit-our-emission-curve/3276">Firo’s halving schedule</a></li>
</ul>

<h2 id="how-to-vote">How to Vote!</h2>

<p>Anyone who has been in the Firo community for some time is eligible to vote in this poll.</p>

<p><strong>Step 1</strong>: Register an account at <a href="http://forum.firo.org">forum.firo.org</a></p>

<p><strong>Step 2</strong>: Earn at least Trust Level 1 by <a href="https://blog.discourse.org/2018/06/understanding-discourse-trust-levels/">spending time on the forums</a>. Alternatively, if you have been with the Firo community for a while in other places, you can post in <a href="https://forum.firo.org/t/for-new-members-trust-level-upgrade-request-thread/3294">this thread</a> to request for an admin to upgrade you immediately.</p>

<p><strong>Step 3</strong> Head to the <a href="https://forum.firo.org/t/poll-final-tokenomics-and-block-division/3379"><strong>final poll</strong></a> thread. Note there are two polls to vote on so please don’t forget to vote on both of them!</p>

<p><strong>Step 4</strong>: Rank the options you like with rank 1 being your most preferred option. For options you don’t like, you can choose to not rank them by picking ‘abstain’.</p>

<p><strong>Step 5</strong>: You can post in the thread to explain why you picked a vote!</p>

<p>Do note that in the future, we intend to impose higher requirements in future polls or even require a minimum Firo holding requirement to prove skin in the game without disenfranchising smaller holders.</p>

<h2 id="do-your-part">Do your Part!</h2>

<p>Getting involved in Firo’s polls is an important step in decentralized governance. It ensures that your voice is heard, and every vote counts! The poll closes on the 1 September 2024!</p>]]></content><author><name>Reuben Yap</name></author><category term="community" /><category term="news" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The community has been actively discussing Firo’s economics, particularly its block reward division and emission model. After seeking community feedback and preliminary polls since June, we are now approaching the penultimate poll to definitively decide Firo’s future. The two primary issues being voted on are: What should Firo’s block reward division be? What should Firo’s emissions be? These polls touch on important issues, such as whether there should be a development and/or community fund, the sustainability of masternodes and the role of miners. It also looks into the long-term sustainability of Firo as to whether it should adopt a tail emission or stick closer to the original Bitcoin model. Instead of a single-choice vote, the poll allows community members to rank their options, resulting in a fairer reflection of sentiment. This is also known as ranked-choice voting and is suitable where there are many options to choose from. You can view the previous discussions and polls here to help guide your decision! Development and Community Funds Tail Emission Firo’s halving schedule How to Vote! Anyone who has been in the Firo community for some time is eligible to vote in this poll. Step 1: Register an account at forum.firo.org Step 2: Earn at least Trust Level 1 by spending time on the forums. Alternatively, if you have been with the Firo community for a while in other places, you can post in this thread to request for an admin to upgrade you immediately. Step 3 Head to the final poll thread. Note there are two polls to vote on so please don’t forget to vote on both of them! Step 4: Rank the options you like with rank 1 being your most preferred option. For options you don’t like, you can choose to not rank them by picking ‘abstain’. Step 5: You can post in the thread to explain why you picked a vote! Do note that in the future, we intend to impose higher requirements in future polls or even require a minimum Firo holding requirement to prove skin in the game without disenfranchising smaller holders. Do your Part! Getting involved in Firo’s polls is an important step in decentralized governance. It ensures that your voice is heard, and every vote counts! The poll closes on the 1 September 2024!]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Firo Guardian Program</title><link href="https://firo.org/firo-site/pr-preview/pr-424/2024/08/12/firo-guardian-program.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Firo Guardian Program" /><published>2024-08-12T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-08-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://firo.org/firo-site/pr-preview/pr-424/2024/08/12/firo-guardian-program</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://firo.org/firo-site/pr-preview/pr-424/2024/08/12/firo-guardian-program.html"><![CDATA[<p>Over the years, Firo has continued to gain momentum in the cryptocurrency space, and our community has been instrumental in this success. To further enhance our reach and engagement, we’re thrilled to introduce: Firo Guardian Program!</p>

<h3 id="who-you-are">Who you are:</h3>
<ul>
  <li>You’re passionate about Firo and its privacy mission.</li>
  <li>You understand the project’s core features and values.</li>
  <li>You’re eager to contribute to Firo’s growth.</li>
  <li>You possess excellent networking skills.</li>
  <li>You’re creative and skilled in content creation.</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="how-you-can-contribute">How you can contribute:</h3>
<p>As a Firo Guardian, you can contribute by amplifying  Firo’s presence and promote privacy awareness. 
Guardians will focus on:</p>
<ul>
  <li>Creating diverse content about Firo, including videos, infographics, tweets, and blog posts.</li>
  <li>Actively representing Firo across social media platforms, especially Twitter, CoinMarketCap, and Reddit.</li>
  <li>Engaging in discussions and answering queries in Firo’s Discord and Telegram communities.</li>
  <li>Promoting Firo’s privacy features and acting as a guardian of privacy in the crypto space.</li>
  <li>Participating in community events and initiatives to boost Firo’s visibility.</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="benefits">Benefits</h3>
<p>As a Firo Guardian, you will:</p>
<ul>
  <li>Receive firsthand updates on the project directly from the core team.</li>
  <li>Have direct communication channels with the team.</li>
  <li>Gain exclusive access to the Guardians’ chat.</li>
  <li>Earn rewards in FIRO for your contributions.</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="did-we-catch-your-attention">Did we catch your attention?</h3>
<p>Here’s how to apply:</p>
<ul>
  <li>Join the Firo Discord server: <a href="https://discord.gg/Ws5C9f3uPC">https://discord.gg/Ws5C9f3uPC</a></li>
  <li>Open a thread in the Firo-guardian-signup channel under “Community-Firo-Guardians” Section.</li>
  <li>Write a 5-line introduction about yourself, including your region.</li>
  <li>Provide a link to your X (Twitter) profile.</li>
  <li>Once selected, you’ll be assigned the Guardian role and given further instructions.</li>
</ul>

<p>We’re excited to welcome passionate individuals to help spread the word about Firo’s innovative privacy solutions. Join us in shaping the future of private transactions in crypto.</p>]]></content><author><name>LilKinggg</name></author><category term="community" /><category term="news" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Over the years, Firo has continued to gain momentum in the cryptocurrency space, and our community has been instrumental in this success. To further enhance our reach and engagement, we’re thrilled to introduce: Firo Guardian Program! Who you are: You’re passionate about Firo and its privacy mission. You understand the project’s core features and values. You’re eager to contribute to Firo’s growth. You possess excellent networking skills. You’re creative and skilled in content creation. How you can contribute: As a Firo Guardian, you can contribute by amplifying Firo’s presence and promote privacy awareness. Guardians will focus on: Creating diverse content about Firo, including videos, infographics, tweets, and blog posts. Actively representing Firo across social media platforms, especially Twitter, CoinMarketCap, and Reddit. Engaging in discussions and answering queries in Firo’s Discord and Telegram communities. Promoting Firo’s privacy features and acting as a guardian of privacy in the crypto space. Participating in community events and initiatives to boost Firo’s visibility. Benefits As a Firo Guardian, you will: Receive firsthand updates on the project directly from the core team. Have direct communication channels with the team. Gain exclusive access to the Guardians’ chat. Earn rewards in FIRO for your contributions. Did we catch your attention? Here’s how to apply: Join the Firo Discord server: https://discord.gg/Ws5C9f3uPC Open a thread in the Firo-guardian-signup channel under “Community-Firo-Guardians” Section. Write a 5-line introduction about yourself, including your region. Provide a link to your X (Twitter) profile. Once selected, you’ll be assigned the Guardian role and given further instructions. We’re excited to welcome passionate individuals to help spread the word about Firo’s innovative privacy solutions. Join us in shaping the future of private transactions in crypto.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Firo Core Team receives 345 XMR donation from Power Up Privacy</title><link href="https://firo.org/firo-site/pr-preview/pr-424/2024/08/10/firo-receive-donation-from-powerup-privacy.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Firo Core Team receives 345 XMR donation from Power Up Privacy" /><published>2024-08-10T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-08-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://firo.org/firo-site/pr-preview/pr-424/2024/08/10/firo-receive-donation-from-powerup-privacy</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://firo.org/firo-site/pr-preview/pr-424/2024/08/10/firo-receive-donation-from-powerup-privacy.html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://powerupprivacy.com/">Power Up Privacy</a>, an anonymous privacy advocacy group that funds privacy-related research and development, has donated 345 XMR (~50,000 USD) to the Firo Core Team fund to support our development work.</p>

<p>We would like to thank them for their generous donation in supporting our work and also for making a significant impact on other important privacy-focused tools and projects, such as Monero, Tor, and xrdp.</p>

<p>Learn more about <a href="https://powerupprivacy.com/">Power Up Privacy</a>.</p>]]></content><author><name>Reuben Yap</name></author><category term="community" /><category term="news" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Power Up Privacy, an anonymous privacy advocacy group that funds privacy-related research and development, has donated 345 XMR (~50,000 USD) to the Firo Core Team fund to support our development work. We would like to thank them for their generous donation in supporting our work and also for making a significant impact on other important privacy-focused tools and projects, such as Monero, Tor, and xrdp. Learn more about Power Up Privacy.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Firo listed on Ascendex</title><link href="https://firo.org/firo-site/pr-preview/pr-424/2024/08/09/firo-ascendex.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Firo listed on Ascendex" /><published>2024-08-09T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-08-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://firo.org/firo-site/pr-preview/pr-424/2024/08/09/firo-ascendex</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://firo.org/firo-site/pr-preview/pr-424/2024/08/09/firo-ascendex.html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="firo-announces-listing-on-ascendex-expanding-accessibility-and-trading-options">Firo Announces Listing on AscendEx: Expanding Accessibility and Trading Options</h1>
<p>We are thrilled to announce that Firo, the leading privacy-focused cryptocurrency, is now listed on AscendEx (formerly known as BitMax) with a FIRO/USDT pair.</p>

<p>Please note the following times:</p>

<ul>
  <li>Deposit: August 9, 10:00 AM UTC</li>
  <li>Trading: August 9, 12:00 PM UTC</li>
  <li>Withdrawal: August 10, 12:00 PM UTC</li>
</ul>

<p>AscendEx is available in a <a href="https://ascendex.com/en/support/articles/36371-countriesregions-available-for-registration">wide variety of countries</a>, which further expands FIRO’s global accessibility and also further builds centralized exchange redundancy.</p>

<p>Stay tuned for news on further activities with AscendEx! You can discuss this listing in our forums here!</p>

<h2 id="about-ascendex">About AscendEx</h2>

<p>AscendEX (formerly BitMax) is a global digital asset financial platform founded by a group of Wall Street quantitative trading veterans in 2018, building on core value of “Efficiency, Resilience and Transparency.” The global cryptocurrency exchange platform serves both retail and institutional clients in more than 200 regions.</p>]]></content><author><name>Reuben Yap</name></author><category term="community" /><category term="news" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Firo Announces Listing on AscendEx: Expanding Accessibility and Trading Options We are thrilled to announce that Firo, the leading privacy-focused cryptocurrency, is now listed on AscendEx (formerly known as BitMax) with a FIRO/USDT pair. Please note the following times: Deposit: August 9, 10:00 AM UTC Trading: August 9, 12:00 PM UTC Withdrawal: August 10, 12:00 PM UTC AscendEx is available in a wide variety of countries, which further expands FIRO’s global accessibility and also further builds centralized exchange redundancy. Stay tuned for news on further activities with AscendEx! You can discuss this listing in our forums here! About AscendEx AscendEX (formerly BitMax) is a global digital asset financial platform founded by a group of Wall Street quantitative trading veterans in 2018, building on core value of “Efficiency, Resilience and Transparency.” The global cryptocurrency exchange platform serves both retail and institutional clients in more than 200 regions.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Campfire Wallet Release</title><link href="https://firo.org/firo-site/pr-preview/pr-424/2024/07/12/campfire-firo-wallet.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Campfire Wallet Release" /><published>2024-07-12T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-07-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://firo.org/firo-site/pr-preview/pr-424/2024/07/12/campfire-firo-wallet</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://firo.org/firo-site/pr-preview/pr-424/2024/07/12/campfire-firo-wallet.html"><![CDATA[<p>We are proud to release our new revamped Campfire wallet in collaboration with Cypher Stack.</p>

<p>Campfire is a Firo-only wallet with a default on Spark privacy. It features many other Firo-specific enhancements, such as masternode collateral recognition and EX-address support. It also includes inbuilt TOR for additional network privacy. It even works on both desktop and mobile devices!</p>

<p>Like its namesake, Campfire is designed to be a warm, welcoming experience where our Firofam can begin their privacy journey.</p>

<h2 id="improved-user-experience">Improved User Experience</h2>

<p>Much work has been put into making the wallet user-friendly with Firo colours, and our Sparky mascot is featured prominently.</p>

<p><img src="/blog/assets/campfirewallet/preview-1.png" alt="Mobile Preview 1" /></p>

<p><img src="/blog/assets/campfirewallet/preview-2.jpg" alt="Desktop Preview 2" /></p>

<p>Under the hood, both teams have made many optimisations to make Spark transactions and syncing speedy and snappy, even with the complex math behind them.</p>

<p>Instead of using the default server, users can choose to host their own light server backend for even more privacy.</p>

<h2 id="open-source">Open source</h2>

<p>Campfire remains true to our goals of being free and open source. All source code is available on <a href="https://github.com/firoorg/campfire">GitHub</a>.</p>

<p>While the original Campfire started as a Firo wallet that supported our previous privacy protocol, Lelantus, the new revamped Campfire has full Spark privacy support and shares the same internals as Stack wallet, a multi-coin wallet also developed by Cypher Stack.</p>

<h2 id="download-campfire-here"><a href="https://firo.org/get-firo/download/">Download Campfire Here</a></h2>

<h2 id="whats-next">What’s next?</h2>

<p>We would like to develop more features for Campfire, such as DEX support and Spark asset support!</p>

<p>If you want to donate to this cause, you can do so through <a href="https://funding.firo.org/proposals/campfire-development-donation-ajaydono">this Firo Crowdfunding proposal</a>.</p>

<h2 id="special-thanks">Special Thanks</h2>

<p>We would like to thank Rasikh Morani from Arcadia, who provided the initial funding for Campfire and Cypher Stack, whose development and research services have greatly improved Firo and its technology stack.</p>

<p>We also would like to thank the Firo Community Fund Committee, whose continued support of core team activities has made this possible.</p>]]></content><author><name>Reuben Yap</name></author><category term="community" /><category term="news" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[We are proud to release our new revamped Campfire wallet in collaboration with Cypher Stack. Campfire is a Firo-only wallet with a default on Spark privacy. It features many other Firo-specific enhancements, such as masternode collateral recognition and EX-address support. It also includes inbuilt TOR for additional network privacy. It even works on both desktop and mobile devices! Like its namesake, Campfire is designed to be a warm, welcoming experience where our Firofam can begin their privacy journey. Improved User Experience Much work has been put into making the wallet user-friendly with Firo colours, and our Sparky mascot is featured prominently. Under the hood, both teams have made many optimisations to make Spark transactions and syncing speedy and snappy, even with the complex math behind them. Instead of using the default server, users can choose to host their own light server backend for even more privacy. Open source Campfire remains true to our goals of being free and open source. All source code is available on GitHub. While the original Campfire started as a Firo wallet that supported our previous privacy protocol, Lelantus, the new revamped Campfire has full Spark privacy support and shares the same internals as Stack wallet, a multi-coin wallet also developed by Cypher Stack. Download Campfire Here What’s next? We would like to develop more features for Campfire, such as DEX support and Spark asset support! If you want to donate to this cause, you can do so through this Firo Crowdfunding proposal. Special Thanks We would like to thank Rasikh Morani from Arcadia, who provided the initial funding for Campfire and Cypher Stack, whose development and research services have greatly improved Firo and its technology stack. We also would like to thank the Firo Community Fund Committee, whose continued support of core team activities has made this possible.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Binance adds new cross margin pair for FIRO</title><link href="https://firo.org/firo-site/pr-preview/pr-424/2024/06/25/binance-firo-cross-margin.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Binance adds new cross margin pair for FIRO" /><published>2024-06-25T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-06-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://firo.org/firo-site/pr-preview/pr-424/2024/06/25/binance-firo-cross-margin</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://firo.org/firo-site/pr-preview/pr-424/2024/06/25/binance-firo-cross-margin.html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="binance-adds-firousdt-cross-margin-pair">Binance Adds FIRO/USDT Cross Margin Pair!</h2>

<p>Binance has added the <a href="https://www.binance.com/en/support/announcement/binance-margin-adds-new-fdusd-usdc-and-usdt-pairs-2024-06-18-d9aba607bf2f4d41ac97d1c22ea41dea">FIRO/USDT pair to Cross Margin</a>. This adds to the existing FIRO/USDT spot and isolated margin pairs.</p>

<h2 id="what-is-cross-margin">What is Cross Margin?</h2>

<p>In Cross Margin, the entire margin balance is shared across open positions to avoid liquidation. If Cross Margin is enabled, the trader risks losing their entire margin balance, along with any open positions, in the event of a liquidation. Any realized PnL (profit and loss) from another position can support a losing position that is close to being liquidated.</p>

<p>With the existing Isolated Margin mode, you can allocate a specific amount of margin to a single position to limit risks. In contrast, the Cross Margin mode uses the balance of your entire Margin Account on Binance as collateral, providing you with greater flexibility and lower margin requirements. Read the difference between isolated and cross margin <a href="https://www.binance.info/en/support/faq/differences-between-isolated-margin-and-cross-margin-b4e9e6ad70934bd082e8e09e33e69513?hl=en">here</a>.</p>

<p>As always, trade responsibly!</p>]]></content><author><name>Augustus Jong</name></author><category term="community" /><category term="news" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Binance Adds FIRO/USDT Cross Margin Pair! Binance has added the FIRO/USDT pair to Cross Margin. This adds to the existing FIRO/USDT spot and isolated margin pairs. What is Cross Margin? In Cross Margin, the entire margin balance is shared across open positions to avoid liquidation. If Cross Margin is enabled, the trader risks losing their entire margin balance, along with any open positions, in the event of a liquidation. Any realized PnL (profit and loss) from another position can support a losing position that is close to being liquidated. With the existing Isolated Margin mode, you can allocate a specific amount of margin to a single position to limit risks. In contrast, the Cross Margin mode uses the balance of your entire Margin Account on Binance as collateral, providing you with greater flexibility and lower margin requirements. Read the difference between isolated and cross margin here. As always, trade responsibly!]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Exchange Addresses live for FIRO on Binance</title><link href="https://firo.org/firo-site/pr-preview/pr-424/2024/06/20/ex-address-live-on-binance.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Exchange Addresses live for FIRO on Binance" /><published>2024-06-20T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-06-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://firo.org/firo-site/pr-preview/pr-424/2024/06/20/ex-address-live-on-binance</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://firo.org/firo-site/pr-preview/pr-424/2024/06/20/ex-address-live-on-binance.html"><![CDATA[<p>Binance has confirmed with us that <a href="/firo-site/pr-preview/pr-424/2023/11/06/exchange-addresses.html">Exchange Addresses</a> are now fully implemented and live on their exchange.</p>

<p>EX addresses are not meant for regular users to create but for exchanges that require them for regulatory or transparency reasons. However, users will need to interact with EX addresses if they are depositing into Binance or another exchange that deploys them.</p>

<p>You can identify an EX-address easily as the address begins with EXX.</p>

<p><img src="/blog/assets/exaddressbinance/exaddress.png" alt="Binance deposit EX address" /></p>

<h2 id="transition-notes">Transition Notes</h2>

<p>Binance has confirmed the roll out of EX-addresses for its users, though if for some reason you do not have an EX-address yet, do not send funds from Spark directly to Binance’s deposit address. Otherwise, they will be frozen until you open a support ticket with Binance to return the funds to you. This process can take up to 30 working days.</p>

<p>EX-addresses only accept FIRO from transparent addresses. If you have funds held in Spark, you would first need to send them to a transparent address (that begins with a or Z) before sending them to the EX address. At the time of writing, the only exchange that uses EX addresses is Binance.</p>

<p>Most exchanges do not yet support withdrawals to an EX-address, so you would need to withdraw from your own wallet first with a transparent address before sending the money to Binance. We are in communication with other centralised exchanges to facilitate easy exchange-to-exchange transfers. At the time of writing, only NonKYC.io supports direct withdrawals to an EX address. You can also do your part by opening a ticket with your favourite exchange or wallet to encourage them to support sending to EX-addresses.</p>

<p>Most major exchanges such as MEXC, HTX and Gate support FIRO deposits from EX-addresses so you can send from Binance to these exchanges directly. Always test with a small amount first if unsure!</p>

<h2 id="reopening-of-firo-trading-in-europe">Reopening of Firo trading in Europe</h2>

<p>Last year, in May 2023, <a href="https://www.theblock.co/post/232751/binance-privacy-coins-delisting-europe">Binance made Firo and several other privacy coins unavailable in several European countries</a> namely Poland, France, Spain, Italy, Belgium and Sweden, due to new EU regulations restricting the trading of privacy coins.</p>

<p>Firo has been reopened for trading in these countries with immediate effect. If you are in an affected country, you might receive an email notification from Binance informing you of this. Do ensure you take note of your new deposit addresses which would have been updated to an EX-address.</p>

<p><img src="/blog/assets/exaddressbinance/deposit-address-expired.png" alt="Binance deposit address expired example" /></p>]]></content><author><name>Reuben Yap</name></author><category term="community" /><category term="news" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Binance has confirmed with us that Exchange Addresses are now fully implemented and live on their exchange. EX addresses are not meant for regular users to create but for exchanges that require them for regulatory or transparency reasons. However, users will need to interact with EX addresses if they are depositing into Binance or another exchange that deploys them. You can identify an EX-address easily as the address begins with EXX. Transition Notes Binance has confirmed the roll out of EX-addresses for its users, though if for some reason you do not have an EX-address yet, do not send funds from Spark directly to Binance’s deposit address. Otherwise, they will be frozen until you open a support ticket with Binance to return the funds to you. This process can take up to 30 working days. EX-addresses only accept FIRO from transparent addresses. If you have funds held in Spark, you would first need to send them to a transparent address (that begins with a or Z) before sending them to the EX address. At the time of writing, the only exchange that uses EX addresses is Binance. Most exchanges do not yet support withdrawals to an EX-address, so you would need to withdraw from your own wallet first with a transparent address before sending the money to Binance. We are in communication with other centralised exchanges to facilitate easy exchange-to-exchange transfers. At the time of writing, only NonKYC.io supports direct withdrawals to an EX address. You can also do your part by opening a ticket with your favourite exchange or wallet to encourage them to support sending to EX-addresses. Most major exchanges such as MEXC, HTX and Gate support FIRO deposits from EX-addresses so you can send from Binance to these exchanges directly. Always test with a small amount first if unsure! Reopening of Firo trading in Europe Last year, in May 2023, Binance made Firo and several other privacy coins unavailable in several European countries namely Poland, France, Spain, Italy, Belgium and Sweden, due to new EU regulations restricting the trading of privacy coins. Firo has been reopened for trading in these countries with immediate effect. If you are in an affected country, you might receive an email notification from Binance informing you of this. Do ensure you take note of your new deposit addresses which would have been updated to an EX-address.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Firo Release 0.14.13.3 Mandatory Upgrade</title><link href="https://firo.org/firo-site/pr-preview/pr-424/2024/06/19/firo-release-0141303-mandatory-upgrade.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Firo Release 0.14.13.3 Mandatory Upgrade" /><published>2024-06-19T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-06-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://firo.org/firo-site/pr-preview/pr-424/2024/06/19/firo-release-0141303-mandatory-upgrade</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://firo.org/firo-site/pr-preview/pr-424/2024/06/19/firo-release-0141303-mandatory-upgrade.html"><![CDATA[<p>We are proud to release Firo v0.14.13.3 which focuses on improving Spark performance, overall user experience and better Spark light wallet support.</p>

<h2 id="rpcs-for-better-spark-light-wallet-support">RPCs for better Spark light wallet support</h2>

<p>New RPCs allow for light wallet servers to query the node for Spark state allowing for mobile wallets to recognize Spark transactions in the mempool even before they’re included in a block. It also ensures proper balance calculation in certain edge cases.</p>

<p>We have also added a way for mobile wallets to recognize masternode collateral so that it will ignore it when sending FIRO.</p>

<p>This is in preparation of our new Firo-only mobile wallet release and also a light desktop wallet developed together with Cypher Stack.</p>

<h2 id="increase-in-max-transaction-relay-size">Increase in max transaction relay size</h2>

<p>We have <a href="https://github.com/firoorg/firo/pull/1457">increased the maximum transaction relay size from 100 kB to 250 kB</a> allowing for easier consolidation of UTXOs and Spark minting. Nodes that do not upgrade will not be able to relay these larger transactions.</p>

<p>We have also included various other bug fixes in relation to Lelantus migration to Spark and user interface improvements.</p>

<p>While there is no deadline for upgrading, we recommend you to update as soon as possible. Mining pools and masternodes are encouraged to update immediately to ensure the network will propagate these larger transactions.</p>

<h2 id="spark-optimization-improvements">Spark Optimization Improvements</h2>

<p>We have various improvements to <a href="https://github.com/firoorg/firo/pull/1431">Spark batch verification</a> and <a href="https://github.com/firoorg/firo/pull/1417">Spark transaction processing</a> improving sync times.</p>

<h2 id="sending-to-ex-address-support">Sending to EX-Address support</h2>

<p>With Binance adopting EX-addresses, we have simplified sending to EX-addresses in the UI by recognizing the EX-address and if the funds are in Spark, to do the necessary transition to a transparent address before sending to an EX-address.</p>

<p><a href="https://github.com/firoorg/firo/releases/tag/v0.14.13.3">Download v0.14.13.3 now!</a></p>]]></content><author><name>Reuben Yap</name></author><category term="community" /><category term="news" /><category term="dev" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[We are proud to release Firo v0.14.13.3 which focuses on improving Spark performance, overall user experience and better Spark light wallet support. RPCs for better Spark light wallet support New RPCs allow for light wallet servers to query the node for Spark state allowing for mobile wallets to recognize Spark transactions in the mempool even before they’re included in a block. It also ensures proper balance calculation in certain edge cases. We have also added a way for mobile wallets to recognize masternode collateral so that it will ignore it when sending FIRO. This is in preparation of our new Firo-only mobile wallet release and also a light desktop wallet developed together with Cypher Stack. Increase in max transaction relay size We have increased the maximum transaction relay size from 100 kB to 250 kB allowing for easier consolidation of UTXOs and Spark minting. Nodes that do not upgrade will not be able to relay these larger transactions. We have also included various other bug fixes in relation to Lelantus migration to Spark and user interface improvements. While there is no deadline for upgrading, we recommend you to update as soon as possible. Mining pools and masternodes are encouraged to update immediately to ensure the network will propagate these larger transactions. Spark Optimization Improvements We have various improvements to Spark batch verification and Spark transaction processing improving sync times. Sending to EX-Address support With Binance adopting EX-addresses, we have simplified sending to EX-addresses in the UI by recognizing the EX-address and if the funds are in Spark, to do the necessary transition to a transparent address before sending to an EX-address. Download v0.14.13.3 now!]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The 3rd term of CFC members are formed!</title><link href="https://firo.org/firo-site/pr-preview/pr-424/2024/05/03/3rd-term-cfc-members-formed.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The 3rd term of CFC members are formed!" /><published>2024-05-03T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-05-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://firo.org/firo-site/pr-preview/pr-424/2024/05/03/3rd-term-cfc-members-formed</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://firo.org/firo-site/pr-preview/pr-424/2024/05/03/3rd-term-cfc-members-formed.html"><![CDATA[<p>The 7 member Community Fund Committee (“CFC”) is formed to oversee the Firo Community Fund (“FCF”) has been completed!</p>

<p>The following community members will serve as CFC members for a period of 1 year:</p>

<ul>
  <li><a href="https://forum.firo.org/t/nominations-for-the-3rd-community-fund-committee-cfc-are-now-open/3150/2">FiroFan</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://forum.firo.org/t/nominations-for-the-3rd-community-fund-committee-cfc-are-now-open/3150/3">Fiendish</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://forum.firo.org/t/nominations-for-the-3rd-community-fund-committee-cfc-are-now-open/3150/4">Devwarrior</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://forum.firo.org/t/nominations-for-the-3rd-community-fund-committee-cfc-are-now-open/3150/5">Rehrar</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://forum.firo.org/t/nominations-for-the-3rd-community-fund-committee-cfc-are-now-open/3150/6">Nrsimha</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://forum.firo.org/t/nominations-for-the-3rd-community-fund-committee-cfc-are-now-open/3150/10">Rasikhmorani</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://forum.firo.org/t/nominations-for-the-3rd-community-fund-committee-cfc-are-now-open/3150/11">sproxet</a></li>
</ul>

<p>The elected committee comprises a well-rounded mix of established community members, subject matter experts, and developers, who have been actively involved in voting on proposals and steering Firo community fund to help with the project.</p>

<p>Since there were no additional nominations, these seven members were automatically elected. We would like to thank them for agreeing to serve on the Firo Community Fund (FCF) and helping to decentralize funding decisions. We would also like to thank the outgoing committee members who have served.</p>

<h2 id="how-to-get-funded-from-the-firo-community-fund">How to get funded from the Firo Community Fund</h2>

<p>Anyone can apply to be funded from the FCF by opening up a proposal in the <a href="https://funding.firo.org/">Firo Crowdfunding System</a> and also opening a <a href="https://forum.firo.org/c/fcs-proposals/16">thread on the forums</a> to open discussion about it. The Community Fund Committee can also independently initiate proposals to be funded from the Firo Community Fund.</p>

<h2 id="what-are-the-responsibilities-of-the-community-fund-committee">What are the responsibilities of the Community Fund Committee?</h2>

<ol>
  <li>To decide along with taking into account community feedback on how the Firo Community Fund should be utilised.</li>
  <li>To help evaluate community requests for funding, do due diligence of applicants applying for funding and obtain all necessary information to ensure sufficient detail for scope of work.</li>
  <li>To evaluate and approve payment of milestone requests.</li>
  <li>To make all reasonings of the CFC for approval/rejection public.</li>
  <li>CFC can request for the core team’s feedback and opinion on proposals.</li>
  <li>To always conduct themselves with professionalism without resorting to personal attacks or insults.</li>
</ol>

<h2 id="how-will-the-firo-community-fund-fcf-be-utilised">How will the Firo Community Fund (FCF) be utilised?</h2>

<ol>
  <li>FCF funds must always be utilised for the benefit of Firo. Research, development or promotional activities that do not directly benefit Firo should not be undertaken.</li>
  <li>All FCF expenditure has to be disclosed. Any proposal that does not allow this will not be able to be funded from the FCF.</li>
  <li>FCF funds should not be used for giveaways even for the purpose of promoting adoption or participation.</li>
  <li>FCF funds should not be used to host purely social events. Educational or awareness events are acceptable but must be the primary component of the event.</li>
  <li>FCF funds should be used and while there shouldn’t be a pressure to spend funds, the FCF should not be hoarded.</li>
  <li>CFC can choose to use the FCF to employ contractors to embark on specific tasks or roles that will report directly to the CFC.</li>
  <li>Should the CFC deem fit, FCF funds can be burnt by sending it to this burn address.</li>
  <li>FCF funds address can be viewed here</li>
</ol>

<h2 id="where-can-i-see-the-deliberations-of-the-community-fund-committee">Where can I see the deliberations of the Community Fund Committee?</h2>

<p>All discussions of the CFC can be seen in our <a href="https://discord.gg/TGZPRbRT3Y">Discord</a> in the channel #communityfund and is read-only. You will need to have verified status by passing the captcha to view the channel.</p>]]></content><author><name>Augustus Jong</name></author><category term="community" /><category term="news" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The 7 member Community Fund Committee (“CFC”) is formed to oversee the Firo Community Fund (“FCF”) has been completed! The following community members will serve as CFC members for a period of 1 year: FiroFan Fiendish Devwarrior Rehrar Nrsimha Rasikhmorani sproxet The elected committee comprises a well-rounded mix of established community members, subject matter experts, and developers, who have been actively involved in voting on proposals and steering Firo community fund to help with the project. Since there were no additional nominations, these seven members were automatically elected. We would like to thank them for agreeing to serve on the Firo Community Fund (FCF) and helping to decentralize funding decisions. We would also like to thank the outgoing committee members who have served. How to get funded from the Firo Community Fund Anyone can apply to be funded from the FCF by opening up a proposal in the Firo Crowdfunding System and also opening a thread on the forums to open discussion about it. The Community Fund Committee can also independently initiate proposals to be funded from the Firo Community Fund. What are the responsibilities of the Community Fund Committee? To decide along with taking into account community feedback on how the Firo Community Fund should be utilised. To help evaluate community requests for funding, do due diligence of applicants applying for funding and obtain all necessary information to ensure sufficient detail for scope of work. To evaluate and approve payment of milestone requests. To make all reasonings of the CFC for approval/rejection public. CFC can request for the core team’s feedback and opinion on proposals. To always conduct themselves with professionalism without resorting to personal attacks or insults. How will the Firo Community Fund (FCF) be utilised? FCF funds must always be utilised for the benefit of Firo. Research, development or promotional activities that do not directly benefit Firo should not be undertaken. All FCF expenditure has to be disclosed. Any proposal that does not allow this will not be able to be funded from the FCF. FCF funds should not be used for giveaways even for the purpose of promoting adoption or participation. FCF funds should not be used to host purely social events. Educational or awareness events are acceptable but must be the primary component of the event. FCF funds should be used and while there shouldn’t be a pressure to spend funds, the FCF should not be hoarded. CFC can choose to use the FCF to employ contractors to embark on specific tasks or roles that will report directly to the CFC. Should the CFC deem fit, FCF funds can be burnt by sending it to this burn address. FCF funds address can be viewed here Where can I see the deliberations of the Community Fund Committee? All discussions of the CFC can be seen in our Discord in the channel #communityfund and is read-only. You will need to have verified status by passing the captcha to view the channel.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Firo Tokenomics Discussion with upcoming Halving</title><link href="https://firo.org/firo-site/pr-preview/pr-424/2024/04/23/firo-tokenomics-and-halving.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Firo Tokenomics Discussion with upcoming Halving" /><published>2024-04-23T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-04-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://firo.org/firo-site/pr-preview/pr-424/2024/04/23/firo-tokenomics-and-halving</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://firo.org/firo-site/pr-preview/pr-424/2024/04/23/firo-tokenomics-and-halving.html"><![CDATA[<p>With the upcoming scheduled halving of emissions in supply in September 2024, the Firo community has raised questions about whether the Firo block reward distribution or tokenomics would be revisited, as was the case with the previous halving. The last time this was done was in <a href="https://forum.firo.org/t/tokenomics-and-funding-division-of-block-reward-discussion-and-community-matching-fund/2061">May 2022</a>.</p>

<p>In particular, whether the block reward distribution would be adjusted and whether there should be a change in the emission cycle; for example, whether to have a more gradual emission decrease instead of halvings, implement a tail emission, etc.</p>

<p>The core team highly values the Firo community’s input in these crucial changes. We are actively seeking your feedback on <a href="https://forum.firo.org/t/firo-tokenomics-discussion-with-upcoming-halving/3162">our forums</a> and plan to keep the feedback period open until at least the end of June 2024. This will allow us to implement your insights prior to the upcoming hard fork, underscoring your integral role in shaping Firo’s future.</p>

<p>As these changes will significantly impact Firo’s future and development direction, we look forward to hearing from the community and greatly appreciate the well-reasoned feedback we’ve received thus far. Let your voice be heard!</p>

<p>Join us in the discussion in our Firo forums located <a href="https://forum.firo.org/t/firo-tokenomics-discussion-with-upcoming-halving/3162">Here</a>!</p>]]></content><author><name>Reuben Yap</name></author><category term="community" /><category term="dev" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[With the upcoming scheduled halving of emissions in supply in September 2024, the Firo community has raised questions about whether the Firo block reward distribution or tokenomics would be revisited, as was the case with the previous halving. The last time this was done was in May 2022. In particular, whether the block reward distribution would be adjusted and whether there should be a change in the emission cycle; for example, whether to have a more gradual emission decrease instead of halvings, implement a tail emission, etc. The core team highly values the Firo community’s input in these crucial changes. We are actively seeking your feedback on our forums and plan to keep the feedback period open until at least the end of June 2024. This will allow us to implement your insights prior to the upcoming hard fork, underscoring your integral role in shaping Firo’s future. As these changes will significantly impact Firo’s future and development direction, we look forward to hearing from the community and greatly appreciate the well-reasoned feedback we’ve received thus far. Let your voice be heard! Join us in the discussion in our Firo forums located Here!]]></summary></entry></feed>