<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="zh-cn"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://firo.org/firo-site/pr-preview/pr-543/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://firo.org/firo-site/pr-preview/pr-543/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="zh-cn" /><updated>2025-12-05T08:25:12+00:00</updated><id>https://firo.org/firo-site/pr-preview/pr-543/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Firo</title><subtitle>Firo is a cryptocurrency that focuses on privacy and fungibility.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Firo Partners with Rosen Bridge</title><link href="https://firo.org/firo-site/pr-preview/pr-543/2025/12/05/rosen-bridge-partnetship.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Firo Partners with Rosen Bridge" /><published>2025-12-05T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-12-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://firo.org/firo-site/pr-preview/pr-543/2025/12/05/rosen-bridge-partnetship</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://firo.org/firo-site/pr-preview/pr-543/2025/12/05/rosen-bridge-partnetship.html"><![CDATA[<p>We’re excited to announce that Firo is partnering with <a href="https://rosen.tech/">Rosen Bridge</a> to enable cross-chain asset transfers, opening the door to some of the largest decentralized finance ecosystems and liquidity venues in cryptocurrency.</p>

<p>Through this integration, Firo will become accessible on Ethereum, BNB Chain, and Cardano. Integrations to Base and other prominent EVMs are also in the works. Home to billions of dollars in decentralized exchange liquidity and a thriving landscape of DeFi applications all without relying on centralized intermediaries.</p>

<h2 id="why-this-matters">Why This Matters</h2>

<p>Over the past few years, privacy-focused cryptocurrencies have faced an increasingly hostile environment on centralized exchanges. Regulatory pressure and compliance concerns have led to widespread delistings, restricting access for users who simply want to transact with financial privacy.</p>

<p>This reality underscores a fundamental lesson: relying on centralized gatekeepers is incompatible with the ethos of censorship-resistant money. If a privacy coin can be removed from circulation with a policy decision, its utility as permissionless currency is compromised at the infrastructure level.</p>

<p>Cross-chain bridges offer a path forward. By enabling Firo to be represented on decentralized exchanges across multiple ecosystems, we reduce dependence on any single point of failure. Users can acquire, hold, and trade Firo through permissionless protocols that no centralized entity can unilaterally shut down.</p>

<h2 id="why-rosen-bridge">Why Rosen Bridge</h2>

<p>Rosen Bridge stands out for several reasons that align with Firo’s values:</p>

<p><strong>Decentralized architecture.</strong> Rosen employs a two-layer security model consisting of Watchers (who monitor and report cross-chain events) and Guards (who verify and execute transactions). Both layers require economic collateral and operate under multi-signature constraints, meaning no single entity controls the bridge.</p>

<p><strong>Multi-layered verification.</strong> Each Watcher observes the network independently rather than relying on other Watchers’ reports, preventing fault cascades. A finalized report only proceeds if enough distinct Watchers confirm the same event. Guards then independently verify these reports before processing, and transactions require signatures from a quorum of Guards. So no small group of compromised actors can generate arbitrary transactions.</p>

<p><strong>Skin in the game.</strong> Both Watchers and Guards must lock collateral (RSN and ERG tokens) to participate. Malicious behaviour results in slashed funds, creating strong economic disincentives against misconduct.</p>

<p><strong>Open source and auditable.</strong> All Rosen Bridge code is <a href="https://github.com/rosen-bridge">publicly accessible</a> for review. Every bridge event is tracked on the Ergo blockchain, creating a transparent audit trail.</p>

<p><strong>Scalable design.</strong> Rosen’s modular architecture allows new chains to be integrated through independent, chain-specific modules, positioning this partnership for expansion as additional ecosystems become relevant.</p>

<h2 id="what-this-means-for-firo-users">What This Means for Firo Users</h2>

<p>Once the integration is live, Firo holders will be able to bridge their assets to Ethereum, BNB Chain, and Cardano, gaining access to:</p>

<ul>
  <li>Deep liquidity on established DEXes like Uniswap, PancakeSwap, and Cardano-native exchanges.</li>
  <li>Participation in DeFi protocols including lending, liquidity provision, and yield generation.</li>
  <li>A censorship-resistant on-ramp and off-ramp that operates independently of centralized exchange policies.</li>
</ul>

<p>This isn’t about chasing DeFi trends. It’s about building resilient infrastructure. When centralized access points fail, decentralized alternatives must exist. Rosen Bridge provides exactly that.</p>

<h2 id="looking-ahead">Looking Ahead</h2>

<p>This partnership represents a strategic step in ensuring Firo remains accessible and liquid regardless of the regulatory climate surrounding privacy technologies. We believe that financial privacy is a fundamental right, and that belief must be backed by infrastructure that cannot be switched off.</p>

<p>We’ll share further details on the integration timeline but development is already underway and progressing quickly.
We have also secured commitments from Firo holders to bridge meaningful amounts of Firo once the bridge is live ensuring strong bootstrapped liquidity upon launch.</p>

<p>In the meantime, you can learn more about Rosen Bridge at <a href="https://rosen.tech/">rosen.tech</a> and follow our official channels for updates.</p>

<p>Privacy isn’t just a feature. It’s infrastructure worth defending.</p>]]></content><author><name>Augustus Jong</name></author><category term="community" /><category term="news" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[We’re excited to announce that Firo is partnering with Rosen Bridge to enable cross-chain asset transfers, opening the door to some of the largest decentralized finance ecosystems and liquidity venues in cryptocurrency. Through this integration, Firo will become accessible on Ethereum, BNB Chain, and Cardano. Integrations to Base and other prominent EVMs are also in the works. Home to billions of dollars in decentralized exchange liquidity and a thriving landscape of DeFi applications all without relying on centralized intermediaries. Why This Matters Over the past few years, privacy-focused cryptocurrencies have faced an increasingly hostile environment on centralized exchanges. Regulatory pressure and compliance concerns have led to widespread delistings, restricting access for users who simply want to transact with financial privacy. This reality underscores a fundamental lesson: relying on centralized gatekeepers is incompatible with the ethos of censorship-resistant money. If a privacy coin can be removed from circulation with a policy decision, its utility as permissionless currency is compromised at the infrastructure level. Cross-chain bridges offer a path forward. By enabling Firo to be represented on decentralized exchanges across multiple ecosystems, we reduce dependence on any single point of failure. Users can acquire, hold, and trade Firo through permissionless protocols that no centralized entity can unilaterally shut down. Why Rosen Bridge Rosen Bridge stands out for several reasons that align with Firo’s values: Decentralized architecture. Rosen employs a two-layer security model consisting of Watchers (who monitor and report cross-chain events) and Guards (who verify and execute transactions). Both layers require economic collateral and operate under multi-signature constraints, meaning no single entity controls the bridge. Multi-layered verification. Each Watcher observes the network independently rather than relying on other Watchers’ reports, preventing fault cascades. A finalized report only proceeds if enough distinct Watchers confirm the same event. Guards then independently verify these reports before processing, and transactions require signatures from a quorum of Guards. So no small group of compromised actors can generate arbitrary transactions. Skin in the game. Both Watchers and Guards must lock collateral (RSN and ERG tokens) to participate. Malicious behaviour results in slashed funds, creating strong economic disincentives against misconduct. Open source and auditable. All Rosen Bridge code is publicly accessible for review. Every bridge event is tracked on the Ergo blockchain, creating a transparent audit trail. Scalable design. Rosen’s modular architecture allows new chains to be integrated through independent, chain-specific modules, positioning this partnership for expansion as additional ecosystems become relevant. What This Means for Firo Users Once the integration is live, Firo holders will be able to bridge their assets to Ethereum, BNB Chain, and Cardano, gaining access to: Deep liquidity on established DEXes like Uniswap, PancakeSwap, and Cardano-native exchanges. Participation in DeFi protocols including lending, liquidity provision, and yield generation. A censorship-resistant on-ramp and off-ramp that operates independently of centralized exchange policies. This isn’t about chasing DeFi trends. It’s about building resilient infrastructure. When centralized access points fail, decentralized alternatives must exist. Rosen Bridge provides exactly that. Looking Ahead This partnership represents a strategic step in ensuring Firo remains accessible and liquid regardless of the regulatory climate surrounding privacy technologies. We believe that financial privacy is a fundamental right, and that belief must be backed by infrastructure that cannot be switched off. We’ll share further details on the integration timeline but development is already underway and progressing quickly. We have also secured commitments from Firo holders to bridge meaningful amounts of Firo once the bridge is live ensuring strong bootstrapped liquidity upon launch. In the meantime, you can learn more about Rosen Bridge at rosen.tech and follow our official channels for updates. Privacy isn’t just a feature. It’s infrastructure worth defending.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">SHKeeper Integrates Firo</title><link href="https://firo.org/firo-site/pr-preview/pr-543/2025/12/01/shkeeper-firo-integration.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="SHKeeper Integrates Firo" /><published>2025-12-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-12-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://firo.org/firo-site/pr-preview/pr-543/2025/12/01/shkeeper-firo-integration</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://firo.org/firo-site/pr-preview/pr-543/2025/12/01/shkeeper-firo-integration.html"><![CDATA[<p>We’re excited to announce that Firo has been integrated into <a href="https://shkeeper.io/">SHKeeper</a>, the self-hosted and open-source cryptocurrency payment gateway. This integration, <a href="https://funding.firo.org/proposals/firo-integration-with-shkeeper-self-hosted-payment-processor-reuben">funded through the Firo Community Fund Committee (CFC)</a>, marks an important step in making Firo accessible to merchants and businesses worldwide.</p>

<h2 id="what-is-shkeeper">What is SHKeeper?</h2>

<p>SHKeeper is a non-custodial cryptocurrency payment processor developed by VSYS Host that allows businesses to accept cryptocurrency payments directly without intermediaries, without third-party fees, and without surrendering control of their funds.</p>

<p>What makes SHKeeper stand out is its commitment to the principles that cryptocurrency was built on. As a self-hosted solution, merchants run the software on their own infrastructure, meaning they retain full custody of their private keys and complete autonomy over their payment processing. There’s no KYC required, no middlemen taking a cut, and no dependence on centralized services that could freeze funds or deny service.</p>

<p>SHKeeper also integrates seamlessly with popular e-commerce platforms including WordPress, WooCommerce, WHMCS, and Shopify through ready-made plugins lowering the barrier for merchants who want to accept crypto without extensive technical knowledge.</p>

<h2 id="why-this-matters-for-firo">Why This Matters for Firo</h2>

<p>This integration addresses one of the most practical questions any cryptocurrency faces: where can people actually spend it?</p>

<p>For Firo, a project built around financial privacy, SHKeeper is a natural fit. Both share a philosophy of minimizing trust and maximizing user control. Importantly, <strong>SHKeeper’s Firo integration uses Spark addresses</strong>, meaning payments take full advantage of Lelantus Spark’s privacy features. Customers paying with Firo enjoy the protocol’s high anonymity sets and the sender privacy that Spark provides, while merchants receive funds directly to their own Spark-enabled wallet.</p>

<p>No custodian ever touches the funds. No payment processor logs the transaction on their servers. The privacy that Firo provides at the protocol level is complemented by infrastructure that respects that privacy at the payment layer.</p>

<p>This integration also makes Firo accessible to a much broader range of businesses. A small online shop running WooCommerce can now accept Firo with minimal setup. Hosting providers using WHMCS can offer Firo as a payment option to privacy-conscious customers. The easier it becomes to accept Firo, the more useful Firo becomes as a medium of exchange and that utility is what drives sustainable adoption.</p>

<h2 id="funded-by-the-community-for-the-community">Funded by the Community, for the Community</h2>

<p>This integration was made possible through Firo’s Community Fund Committee, which oversees the Firo Community Fund, a pool funded by 10% of the block reward specifically designated for community-driven initiatives. The CFC is composed of elected community members who evaluate and approve proposals that benefit the Firo ecosystem.</p>

<p>The SHKeeper integration exemplifies what the Community Fund was designed for: practical improvements that expand Firo’s reach and usability, driven by community priorities rather than top-down decisions.</p>

<h2 id="getting-started">Getting Started</h2>

<p>Merchants interested in accepting Firo through SHKeeper can visit <a href="https://shkeeper.io">shkeeper.io</a> to learn more about setup and integration options. The software is fully open-source and available on GitHub for those who want to inspect the code or contribute.</p>

<p>For the Firo community, this is another step toward building the infrastructure that makes private digital cash practical for everyday use. We encourage you to spread the word to merchants you know and support businesses that choose to accept Firo.</p>

<h2 id="demo-site">Demo site</h2>

<p>There is a demo page where merchants or anyone can log in to check it out: <a href="https://demo.shkeeper.io/">https://demo.shkeeper.io/</a></p>

<p>Username: admin
Password: admin</p>

<p>Here are some screenshot.</p>

<p><img src="/blog/assets/shkeeper-firo-integration/img1.png" alt="wallets" /></p>

<p><img src="/blog/assets/shkeeper-firo-integration/img2.png" alt="Spark wallet" /></p>

<p><img src="/blog/assets/shkeeper-firo-integration/img3.png" alt="Transactions" /></p>

<p><img src="/blog/assets/shkeeper-firo-integration/img4.png" alt="Payout" /></p>]]></content><author><name>Augustus Jong</name></author><category term="community" /><category term="news" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[We’re excited to announce that Firo has been integrated into SHKeeper, the self-hosted and open-source cryptocurrency payment gateway. This integration, funded through the Firo Community Fund Committee (CFC), marks an important step in making Firo accessible to merchants and businesses worldwide. What is SHKeeper? SHKeeper is a non-custodial cryptocurrency payment processor developed by VSYS Host that allows businesses to accept cryptocurrency payments directly without intermediaries, without third-party fees, and without surrendering control of their funds. What makes SHKeeper stand out is its commitment to the principles that cryptocurrency was built on. As a self-hosted solution, merchants run the software on their own infrastructure, meaning they retain full custody of their private keys and complete autonomy over their payment processing. There’s no KYC required, no middlemen taking a cut, and no dependence on centralized services that could freeze funds or deny service. SHKeeper also integrates seamlessly with popular e-commerce platforms including WordPress, WooCommerce, WHMCS, and Shopify through ready-made plugins lowering the barrier for merchants who want to accept crypto without extensive technical knowledge. Why This Matters for Firo This integration addresses one of the most practical questions any cryptocurrency faces: where can people actually spend it? For Firo, a project built around financial privacy, SHKeeper is a natural fit. Both share a philosophy of minimizing trust and maximizing user control. Importantly, SHKeeper’s Firo integration uses Spark addresses, meaning payments take full advantage of Lelantus Spark’s privacy features. Customers paying with Firo enjoy the protocol’s high anonymity sets and the sender privacy that Spark provides, while merchants receive funds directly to their own Spark-enabled wallet. No custodian ever touches the funds. No payment processor logs the transaction on their servers. The privacy that Firo provides at the protocol level is complemented by infrastructure that respects that privacy at the payment layer. This integration also makes Firo accessible to a much broader range of businesses. A small online shop running WooCommerce can now accept Firo with minimal setup. Hosting providers using WHMCS can offer Firo as a payment option to privacy-conscious customers. The easier it becomes to accept Firo, the more useful Firo becomes as a medium of exchange and that utility is what drives sustainable adoption. Funded by the Community, for the Community This integration was made possible through Firo’s Community Fund Committee, which oversees the Firo Community Fund, a pool funded by 10% of the block reward specifically designated for community-driven initiatives. The CFC is composed of elected community members who evaluate and approve proposals that benefit the Firo ecosystem. The SHKeeper integration exemplifies what the Community Fund was designed for: practical improvements that expand Firo’s reach and usability, driven by community priorities rather than top-down decisions. Getting Started Merchants interested in accepting Firo through SHKeeper can visit shkeeper.io to learn more about setup and integration options. The software is fully open-source and available on GitHub for those who want to inspect the code or contribute. For the Firo community, this is another step toward building the infrastructure that makes private digital cash practical for everyday use. We encourage you to spread the word to merchants you know and support businesses that choose to accept Firo. Demo site There is a demo page where merchants or anyone can log in to check it out: https://demo.shkeeper.io/ Username: admin Password: admin Here are some screenshot.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Lelantus V1.0 Redemption Period Closing Soon</title><link href="https://firo.org/firo-site/pr-preview/pr-543/2025/11/28/lelantus-v1-closing.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Lelantus V1.0 Redemption Period Closing Soon" /><published>2025-11-28T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-11-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://firo.org/firo-site/pr-preview/pr-543/2025/11/28/lelantus-v1-closing</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://firo.org/firo-site/pr-preview/pr-543/2025/11/28/lelantus-v1-closing.html"><![CDATA[<p>As part of Firo’s continued evolution, we are completing the transition from <strong>Lelantus (V1)</strong> to <strong>Lelantus Spark</strong>, our next-generation privacy protocol.</p>

<p>The redemption window for Lelantus (V1) will <strong>close at block 1,223,500 (approximately 20 December 2025)</strong>. After this point, it will no longer be possible to redeem your Lelantus coins.</p>

<h2 id="why-is-this-happening">Why is this happening?</h2>

<p>With the launch of <strong>Lelantus Spark</strong>, users can no longer create new Lelantus mints but instead create Lelantus Spark Mints. Lelantus Spark offers stronger privacy by hiding the <strong>sender, receiver, amounts, and even asset types</strong>, while maintaining a more efficient and flexible design. To fully complete this transition, all Lelantus mints need to be redeemed before the redemption window closes.</p>

<h2 id="what-this-means-for-users">What this means for users</h2>

<ul>
  <li>If you still hold unredeemed Lelantus mints, please redeem them before block 1,223,500.</li>
  <li>After this block, redemption will no longer be possible, and those funds will become inaccessible.</li>
  <li>Moving forward, all privacy transactions will use the <strong>Lelantus Spark</strong> protocol, which provides enhanced anonymity and long-term maintainability.</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="how-to-redeemmigrate">How to redeem/migrate</h2>

<p>This is only for Users that owns Lelantus V1.0 Coins <strong>before January 18, 2024</strong>. If you hold Firo after January 18, 2024, You do NOT need to do anything.</p>

<h3 id="if-you-are-not-a-campfire-users-jump-to-step-4">If you are not a Campfire users, Jump to Step 4</h3>

<p>If you have anonymized your Firo in <strong>Campfire</strong> before <strong>January 18, 2024</strong>, Please recover your wallet on the <strong>Referrence QT wallet</strong> using your 12-24 recovery words.</p>

<p>1) Download and install the Reference wallet: <a href="https://firo.org/get-firo/download/">https://firo.org/get-firo/download/</a></p>

<p><img src="/blog/assets/lelantus-v1-closing/img2.png" alt="Download Firo" /></p>

<p>2) Retrive your 12-24 recovery words in Campfire and recover on the Reference desktop wallet. Make sure the properly select the <strong>Recover existing wallet</strong> option.</p>

<p><img src="/blog/assets/lelantus-v1-closing/img3.png" alt="Recover on Reference" /></p>

<p>3) Wait to be fully synced to the network.</p>

<p><img src="/blog/assets/lelantus-v1-closing/img4.png" alt="Syncing" /></p>

<p>4) Simply click on “Click Here” highlighted button. It will automatically do the redemption for you to Lelantus Spark.</p>

<p><img src="/blog/assets/lelantus-v1-closing/img1.png" alt="QT wallet" /></p>

<h2 id="additional-notes">Additional Notes</h2>

<p>Lelantus (V1) was a major milestone in Firo’s history, pioneering new approaches to privacy that inspired research across the crypto space. Lelantus Spark builds on this foundation, offering stronger privacy guarantees and a more robust security model for the future.
We encourage all users to redeem their Lelantus (V1) mints before the window closes and begin using Spark for their private transactions.</p>]]></content><author><name>Augustus Jong</name></author><category term="community" /><category term="news" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[As part of Firo’s continued evolution, we are completing the transition from Lelantus (V1) to Lelantus Spark, our next-generation privacy protocol. The redemption window for Lelantus (V1) will close at block 1,223,500 (approximately 20 December 2025). After this point, it will no longer be possible to redeem your Lelantus coins. Why is this happening? With the launch of Lelantus Spark, users can no longer create new Lelantus mints but instead create Lelantus Spark Mints. Lelantus Spark offers stronger privacy by hiding the sender, receiver, amounts, and even asset types, while maintaining a more efficient and flexible design. To fully complete this transition, all Lelantus mints need to be redeemed before the redemption window closes. What this means for users If you still hold unredeemed Lelantus mints, please redeem them before block 1,223,500. After this block, redemption will no longer be possible, and those funds will become inaccessible. Moving forward, all privacy transactions will use the Lelantus Spark protocol, which provides enhanced anonymity and long-term maintainability. How to redeem/migrate This is only for Users that owns Lelantus V1.0 Coins before January 18, 2024. If you hold Firo after January 18, 2024, You do NOT need to do anything. If you are not a Campfire users, Jump to Step 4 If you have anonymized your Firo in Campfire before January 18, 2024, Please recover your wallet on the Referrence QT wallet using your 12-24 recovery words. 1) Download and install the Reference wallet: https://firo.org/get-firo/download/ 2) Retrive your 12-24 recovery words in Campfire and recover on the Reference desktop wallet. Make sure the properly select the Recover existing wallet option. 3) Wait to be fully synced to the network. 4) Simply click on “Click Here” highlighted button. It will automatically do the redemption for you to Lelantus Spark. Additional Notes Lelantus (V1) was a major milestone in Firo’s history, pioneering new approaches to privacy that inspired research across the crypto space. Lelantus Spark builds on this foundation, offering stronger privacy guarantees and a more robust security model for the future. We encourage all users to redeem their Lelantus (V1) mints before the window closes and begin using Spark for their private transactions.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Hard Fork Successfully Completed</title><link href="https://firo.org/firo-site/pr-preview/pr-543/2025/11/19/hardfork-successful-nov-2025.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Hard Fork Successfully Completed" /><published>2025-11-19T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-11-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://firo.org/firo-site/pr-preview/pr-543/2025/11/19/hardfork-successful-nov-2025</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://firo.org/firo-site/pr-preview/pr-543/2025/11/19/hardfork-successful-nov-2025.html"><![CDATA[<p>We are glad to announce that the Firo hard fork has been successfully completed.
Firo’s latest hard fork activated at block 1,205,100 without issues.</p>

<p>This upgrade introduces two major improvements to the Firo network:</p>

<h2 id="spark-name-transfers">Spark Name Transfers</h2>

<p>Users can now transfer, buy, and sell Spark Names on-chain, enabling a new Firo-native economy around privacy-preserving digital identities.</p>

<h2 id="lower-gpu-vram-requirements-for-mining">Lower GPU VRAM Requirements for Mining</h2>

<p>This hard fork reduces the VRAM requirements for FiroPoW miners, making mining more accessible and allowing 8 GB graphics cards to mine Firo again.</p>

<p>We would like to thank all exchanges, mining pools, nodes and masternodes for the smooth transition.</p>

<p>If you run a node, masternode, or the QT Reference Wallet, please ensure you are updated to the <a href="https://github.com/firoorg/firo/releases">latest version</a>.
You may need to perform a reindex if you updated after the hard fork: <a href="https://firo.org/guide/reindex-wallet.html">https://firo.org/guide/reindex-wallet.html</a></p>]]></content><author><name>Augustus Jong</name></author><category term="community" /><category term="news" /><category term="dev" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[We are glad to announce that the Firo hard fork has been successfully completed. Firo’s latest hard fork activated at block 1,205,100 without issues. This upgrade introduces two major improvements to the Firo network: Spark Name Transfers Users can now transfer, buy, and sell Spark Names on-chain, enabling a new Firo-native economy around privacy-preserving digital identities. Lower GPU VRAM Requirements for Mining This hard fork reduces the VRAM requirements for FiroPoW miners, making mining more accessible and allowing 8 GB graphics cards to mine Firo again. We would like to thank all exchanges, mining pools, nodes and masternodes for the smooth transition. If you run a node, masternode, or the QT Reference Wallet, please ensure you are updated to the latest version. You may need to perform a reindex if you updated after the hard fork: https://firo.org/guide/reindex-wallet.html]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Cedric Crispin Mining Pool Adds Support for Spark Names and Addresses</title><link href="https://firo.org/firo-site/pr-preview/pr-543/2025/10/22/cedric-pool-spark-support.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Cedric Crispin Mining Pool Adds Support for Spark Names and Addresses" /><published>2025-10-22T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-10-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://firo.org/firo-site/pr-preview/pr-543/2025/10/22/cedric-pool-spark-support</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://firo.org/firo-site/pr-preview/pr-543/2025/10/22/cedric-pool-spark-support.html"><![CDATA[<p>We’re pleased to share that the <a href="https://www.cedric-crispin.com/">Cedric Crispin Mining Pool</a>, which added Firo in 2023, now supports <strong>Spark Names</strong> and <strong>Spark Addresses</strong> for block reward payouts!</p>

<p>This integration means miners can now receive their rewards <strong>directly into their Spark Names or Spark addresses</strong>, maintaining full confidentiality.
You can start mining Firo with Cedric Crispin at:</p>

<p><strong>Website</strong>: <a href="https://firo.cedric-crispin.com/">https://firo.cedric-crispin.com/</a></p>

<p><strong>Stratum</strong>:</p>
<ul>
  <li>firo.cedric-crispin.com:4064</li>
  <li>firo.cedric-crispin.com:4065 (SSL)</li>
</ul>

<p>The guide on <strong>How to Mine Firo</strong> on Cedric Crispin pool can be found <a href="https://firo.cedric-crispin.com/start-mining/">here</a>.</p>

<h2 id="what-are-spark-names-and-spark-addresses">What Are Spark Names and Spark Addresses?</h2>

<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=aBh8nUTiy_A">Spark Addresses</a> are part of Firo’s Lelantus Spark protocol, allowing transactions that hide the sender, receiver, and amount while remaining fully verifiable. This provides true financial privacy on-chain.</p>

<p><a href="https://sparknames.firo.org/">Spark Names</a> make private transactions easier by replacing long, complex Spark addresses with simple, human-readable identifiers - like usernames for your wallet. This lowers the barrier to using privacy features while keeping everything fully private under the hood.</p>

<h2 id="thank-you-to-cedric-crispin">Thank You to Cedric Crispin</h2>

<p>We’d like to extend our gratitude to Cedric Crispin Mining Pool for their continued support of Firo. Their recent integration of Spark Names and Spark Addresses for block reward payouts enables privacy-conscious miners to receive rewards directly into their private Spark addresses.</p>

<p><strong>Q: You’ve been a huge supporter of Firo, running a mining pool for a long time, can you tell us what motivated you to start one up?</strong></p>

<p>I’m a computer nerd and I also graduated in computer science.
Running a mining pool was inevitable in my case since it touches things i love: networking, coding and blockchain.
I also wanted to be a contributor in the blockchain space.</p>

<p><strong>Q: What drew you to Firo? Anything that you are particularly excited about?</strong></p>

<p>FIRO is one the first coins I mined, although it was still called ZCOIN back then.
The project has always been very vocal about its advocacy for POW. The switch from MTP to FIROPOW was the perfect reaffirmation.
So as soon as I found out there was actually a chance for me to be a contributor in term of stratum pool software, I did not hesitate a single moment.</p>

<p><strong>Q: Why do you think miners in many PoW coins don’t seem to care about decentralization of hashrate?</strong></p>

<p>It’s a tough question but I think the main reasons simply boil down to greed, lack of ethics and education.
Unfortunately some mining pools are also not ashamed and not afraid when it comes to exploiting those behaviors for their own benefits.</p>

<p><strong>Q: Anything you would like to see in Firo or its ecosystem?</strong></p>

<p>Of course more POW decentralization.
But I would also love to see miners more involved in community topics/debates/contributions.
FIRO has already implemented multiple fascinating and crucial features: Lelantus spark &amp; FIRODEX. So I hope it will continue to create tools which will make the excessive selling pressure just for FIAT less compelling.</p>]]></content><author><name>Augustus Jong</name></author><category term="community" /><category term="news" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[We’re pleased to share that the Cedric Crispin Mining Pool, which added Firo in 2023, now supports Spark Names and Spark Addresses for block reward payouts! This integration means miners can now receive their rewards directly into their Spark Names or Spark addresses, maintaining full confidentiality. You can start mining Firo with Cedric Crispin at: Website: https://firo.cedric-crispin.com/ Stratum: firo.cedric-crispin.com:4064 firo.cedric-crispin.com:4065 (SSL) The guide on How to Mine Firo on Cedric Crispin pool can be found here. What Are Spark Names and Spark Addresses? Spark Addresses are part of Firo’s Lelantus Spark protocol, allowing transactions that hide the sender, receiver, and amount while remaining fully verifiable. This provides true financial privacy on-chain. Spark Names make private transactions easier by replacing long, complex Spark addresses with simple, human-readable identifiers - like usernames for your wallet. This lowers the barrier to using privacy features while keeping everything fully private under the hood. Thank You to Cedric Crispin We’d like to extend our gratitude to Cedric Crispin Mining Pool for their continued support of Firo. Their recent integration of Spark Names and Spark Addresses for block reward payouts enables privacy-conscious miners to receive rewards directly into their private Spark addresses. Q: You’ve been a huge supporter of Firo, running a mining pool for a long time, can you tell us what motivated you to start one up? I’m a computer nerd and I also graduated in computer science. Running a mining pool was inevitable in my case since it touches things i love: networking, coding and blockchain. I also wanted to be a contributor in the blockchain space. Q: What drew you to Firo? Anything that you are particularly excited about? FIRO is one the first coins I mined, although it was still called ZCOIN back then. The project has always been very vocal about its advocacy for POW. The switch from MTP to FIROPOW was the perfect reaffirmation. So as soon as I found out there was actually a chance for me to be a contributor in term of stratum pool software, I did not hesitate a single moment. Q: Why do you think miners in many PoW coins don’t seem to care about decentralization of hashrate? It’s a tough question but I think the main reasons simply boil down to greed, lack of ethics and education. Unfortunately some mining pools are also not ashamed and not afraid when it comes to exploiting those behaviors for their own benefits. Q: Anything you would like to see in Firo or its ecosystem? Of course more POW decentralization. But I would also love to see miners more involved in community topics/debates/contributions. FIRO has already implemented multiple fascinating and crucial features: Lelantus spark &amp; FIRODEX. So I hope it will continue to create tools which will make the excessive selling pressure just for FIAT less compelling.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">DataVEX Masternode Provider now Accepts Firo and Spark as Payments</title><link href="https://firo.org/firo-site/pr-preview/pr-543/2025/10/22/datavex-firo-masternode.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="DataVEX Masternode Provider now Accepts Firo and Spark as Payments" /><published>2025-10-22T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-10-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://firo.org/firo-site/pr-preview/pr-543/2025/10/22/datavex-firo-masternode</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://firo.org/firo-site/pr-preview/pr-543/2025/10/22/datavex-firo-masternode.html"><![CDATA[<p>We’re pleased to share that <a href="https://datavex.eu/">DataVEX</a>, a new masternode hosting provider, has added <strong>Firo</strong> to its list of supported masternodes. You can now easily deploy and manage <strong>Firo masternodes</strong> - no technical skills required. This makes it simple for anyone to participate in securing the Firo network without needing to handle server setups or command-line configurations.</p>

<p>DataVEX now accepts <strong>FIRO</strong> and <strong>Spark</strong> as payment options, aligning with our shared vision of privacy, flexibility, and user empowerment.</p>

<h2 id="special-launch-promotion">Special Launch Promotion</h2>

<p>To celebrate the addition of Firo, <a href="https://datavex.eu/prices/FIRO/">DataVEX is offering one month of free hosting</a> for a Firo masternode to the <strong>first 10 customers</strong>.</p>

<p>It’s a <em>first come, first served</em> opportunity for community members looking to set up their own masternode and contribute to network stability.</p>

<h2 id="qa">Q&amp;A</h2>

<p><strong>Q: You’re a relatively newcomer to the Firo ecosystem, what made you decide to add Firo support?</strong></p>

<p>At DataVex, we choose projects where we see real potential and concrete use cases. We added FIRO support to help grow the network and make it easier for people who want to run a node but have little or no experience setting one up. Our goal is to lower the barrier to entry—so anyone who wants to support FIRO can do it quickly, safely, and without complex administration.</p>

<p><strong>Q: What drew you to Firo? Anything that you are particularly excited about?</strong></p>

<p>Privacy is the headline reason. In both crypto and traditional finance, real-world users need payments that don’t leak business intelligence or personal activity by default. Firo’s focus on practical, on-chain privacy aligns perfectly with that need.</p>

<p><strong>Q: You had to code your Firo payment gateway from scratch to accept Spark payments, tell us abit about the process.</strong></p>

<p>We already had a native Firo gateway, but we’re big on privacy—so we added Spark. We wrote the Spark integration from scratch (addresses, detection, confirmations) to keep payments private by default while keeping our checkout simple and self-hosted.</p>

<p><strong>Q: Anything you would like to see in Firo or its ecosystem?</strong></p>

<p>What we’ve already started:</p>

<ul>
  <li>A Spark-first gateway reference (templated, self-hosted) to serve as a BTCPay-style baseline.</li>
  <li>Lightweight SDKs — Python core first (invoices, confirmations), with a small JS client for browser/apps.</li>
  <li>A draft Spark URI/QR convention + webhook/event guidelines.</li>
  <li>WooCommerce plugin MVP (checkout + callbacks); PrestaShop prototype next.</li>
  <li>Merchant docs &amp; examples: quick-starts, invoice flow, troubleshooting.</li>
</ul>]]></content><author><name>Augustus Jong</name></author><category term="community" /><category term="news" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[We’re pleased to share that DataVEX, a new masternode hosting provider, has added Firo to its list of supported masternodes. You can now easily deploy and manage Firo masternodes - no technical skills required. This makes it simple for anyone to participate in securing the Firo network without needing to handle server setups or command-line configurations. DataVEX now accepts FIRO and Spark as payment options, aligning with our shared vision of privacy, flexibility, and user empowerment. Special Launch Promotion To celebrate the addition of Firo, DataVEX is offering one month of free hosting for a Firo masternode to the first 10 customers. It’s a first come, first served opportunity for community members looking to set up their own masternode and contribute to network stability. Q&amp;A Q: You’re a relatively newcomer to the Firo ecosystem, what made you decide to add Firo support? At DataVex, we choose projects where we see real potential and concrete use cases. We added FIRO support to help grow the network and make it easier for people who want to run a node but have little or no experience setting one up. Our goal is to lower the barrier to entry—so anyone who wants to support FIRO can do it quickly, safely, and without complex administration. Q: What drew you to Firo? Anything that you are particularly excited about? Privacy is the headline reason. In both crypto and traditional finance, real-world users need payments that don’t leak business intelligence or personal activity by default. Firo’s focus on practical, on-chain privacy aligns perfectly with that need. Q: You had to code your Firo payment gateway from scratch to accept Spark payments, tell us abit about the process. We already had a native Firo gateway, but we’re big on privacy—so we added Spark. We wrote the Spark integration from scratch (addresses, detection, confirmations) to keep payments private by default while keeping our checkout simple and self-hosted. Q: Anything you would like to see in Firo or its ecosystem? What we’ve already started: A Spark-first gateway reference (templated, self-hosted) to serve as a BTCPay-style baseline. Lightweight SDKs — Python core first (invoices, confirmations), with a small JS client for browser/apps. A draft Spark URI/QR convention + webhook/event guidelines. WooCommerce plugin MVP (checkout + callbacks); PrestaShop prototype next. Merchant docs &amp; examples: quick-starts, invoice flow, troubleshooting.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Firo Mandatory Release v0.14.15.0</title><link href="https://firo.org/firo-site/pr-preview/pr-543/2025/10/20/firo-v014150.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Firo Mandatory Release v0.14.15.0" /><published>2025-10-20T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-10-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://firo.org/firo-site/pr-preview/pr-543/2025/10/20/firo-v014150</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://firo.org/firo-site/pr-preview/pr-543/2025/10/20/firo-v014150.html"><![CDATA[<p>As this is a <strong>mandatory release</strong>, all users including wallet, node, and masternode operators must update before <strong>block 1,205,100</strong> (approximately <strong>19 November 2025</strong>) to stay in sync with the network and prevent service disruption.</p>

<p>You can download the latest binaries here: <a href="https://github.com/firoorg/firo/releases/tag/v0.14.15.0">Firo v0.14.15.0 Release on GitHub</a></p>

<h2 id="key-highlights">Key Highlights</h2>

<h3 id="spark-name-transfers">Spark Name Transfers</h3>

<p><img src="/blog/assets/firo-v014150/Swap-Names.png" alt="Spark name transfer" /></p>

<p>This release introduces <strong>Spark Name Transfers</strong>, enabling users to transfer Spark Names directly between wallets. Spark Names serve as human-readable identifiers for Spark Addresses, making private transactions easier to manage while preserving full privacy. This update extends their flexibility when users want to change their Spark Names ownership to someone else or assign it to a different address. This also allows users to sell their Spark Names creating a more vibrant Spark Name economy. A guide will be published soon.</p>

<h3 id="gpu-memory-requirement-for-firopow">GPU memory requirement for FiroPOW</h3>

<p><img src="/blog/assets/firo-v014150/Mining-Upgrade.png" alt="GPU VRAM" /></p>

<p>As per the Firo community’s decision, the memory requirement to mine Firo using a GPU will be dropped to ensure that cards with 8GB of VRAM can still continue to mine Firo. The change supports broader accessibility and strengthens network decentralization by lowering the entry barrier for miners while keeping obsolete hardware out.</p>

<h3 id="additional-changes">Additional Changes</h3>

<p>This update also includes <strong>Sigma stripping</strong> which improves load times, increased <strong>Spark Spend limits</strong>, and a <strong>new loading screen</strong> that gives more details on what’s going in the background on startup, among other optimizations and minor improvements.</p>

<p>For a full list of technical details and changelog, please refer to the <a href="https://github.com/firoorg/firo/releases/tag/v0.14.15.0/">release page</a> on GitHub.</p>]]></content><author><name>Augustus Jong</name></author><category term="community" /><category term="news" /><category term="dev" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[As this is a mandatory release, all users including wallet, node, and masternode operators must update before block 1,205,100 (approximately 19 November 2025) to stay in sync with the network and prevent service disruption. You can download the latest binaries here: Firo v0.14.15.0 Release on GitHub Key Highlights Spark Name Transfers This release introduces Spark Name Transfers, enabling users to transfer Spark Names directly between wallets. Spark Names serve as human-readable identifiers for Spark Addresses, making private transactions easier to manage while preserving full privacy. This update extends their flexibility when users want to change their Spark Names ownership to someone else or assign it to a different address. This also allows users to sell their Spark Names creating a more vibrant Spark Name economy. A guide will be published soon. GPU memory requirement for FiroPOW As per the Firo community’s decision, the memory requirement to mine Firo using a GPU will be dropped to ensure that cards with 8GB of VRAM can still continue to mine Firo. The change supports broader accessibility and strengthens network decentralization by lowering the entry barrier for miners while keeping obsolete hardware out. Additional Changes This update also includes Sigma stripping which improves load times, increased Spark Spend limits, and a new loading screen that gives more details on what’s going in the background on startup, among other optimizations and minor improvements. For a full list of technical details and changelog, please refer to the release page on GitHub.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Power Up Privacy Donates 290 XMR to Support Firo’s Development</title><link href="https://firo.org/firo-site/pr-preview/pr-543/2025/10/16/pup-290-xmr-donation-firo.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Power Up Privacy Donates 290 XMR to Support Firo’s Development" /><published>2025-10-16T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-10-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://firo.org/firo-site/pr-preview/pr-543/2025/10/16/pup-290-xmr-donation-firo</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://firo.org/firo-site/pr-preview/pr-543/2025/10/16/pup-290-xmr-donation-firo.html"><![CDATA[<p>We’re deeply grateful to announce that <a href="https://powerupprivacy.com/">Power Up Privacy</a>, a long-time supporter of Firo and advocate for privacy rights, has made another generous contribution - <strong>290 XMR</strong>, equivalent to roughly <strong>USD 91,000</strong> as of this blog post, to the Firo’s core team.</p>

<p>This donation will directly support our ongoing development efforts, research into Firo’s privacy technology, and continued education around the importance of financial privacy.</p>

<h2 id="a-consistent-supporter-in-challenging-times">A Consistent Supporter in Challenging Times</h2>

<p>Power Up Privacy has been with us through both progress and challenges, consistently demonstrating belief in Firo’s mission. Their continued backing, even during difficult market periods, has helped us sustain core development, advance privacy research, and keep awareness efforts alive.</p>

<p>We are truly grateful for their ongoing commitment - their support fuels our ability to keep innovating and building tools that defend financial freedom and user sovereignty.</p>

<h2 id="acknowledging-our-infrastructure-partners">Acknowledging Our Infrastructure Partners</h2>

<p>We would also like to extend our heartfelt thanks to <a href="https://cypherstack.com/">Cypher Stack</a> for introducing us to Power Up Privacy and using part of their grant to continue maintaining and improving Firo’s infrastructure and Campfire/Stack wallets. Their expertise and reliability ensure that our system remains stable and in working order.</p>

<h2 id="moving-forward">Moving Forward</h2>

<p>With this donation, we’ll continue to strengthen Firo’s foundation, push privacy innovation further, and support the open-source work that benefits not only our project but the broader privacy ecosystem as a whole.</p>

<p>Once again, a huge thank you to <strong>Power Up Privacy</strong>, the <strong>Cypher Stack</strong> team - and to every member of the <strong>Firofam</strong> who believes in and supports our shared vision for a private, decentralized future.</p>]]></content><author><name>Augustus Jong</name></author><category term="community" /><category term="news" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[We’re deeply grateful to announce that Power Up Privacy, a long-time supporter of Firo and advocate for privacy rights, has made another generous contribution - 290 XMR, equivalent to roughly USD 91,000 as of this blog post, to the Firo’s core team. This donation will directly support our ongoing development efforts, research into Firo’s privacy technology, and continued education around the importance of financial privacy. A Consistent Supporter in Challenging Times Power Up Privacy has been with us through both progress and challenges, consistently demonstrating belief in Firo’s mission. Their continued backing, even during difficult market periods, has helped us sustain core development, advance privacy research, and keep awareness efforts alive. We are truly grateful for their ongoing commitment - their support fuels our ability to keep innovating and building tools that defend financial freedom and user sovereignty. Acknowledging Our Infrastructure Partners We would also like to extend our heartfelt thanks to Cypher Stack for introducing us to Power Up Privacy and using part of their grant to continue maintaining and improving Firo’s infrastructure and Campfire/Stack wallets. Their expertise and reliability ensure that our system remains stable and in working order. Moving Forward With this donation, we’ll continue to strengthen Firo’s foundation, push privacy innovation further, and support the open-source work that benefits not only our project but the broader privacy ecosystem as a whole. Once again, a huge thank you to Power Up Privacy, the Cypher Stack team - and to every member of the Firofam who believes in and supports our shared vision for a private, decentralized future.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Firo Turns 9!</title><link href="https://firo.org/firo-site/pr-preview/pr-543/2025/09/28/Firo-turns-9.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Firo Turns 9!" /><published>2025-09-28T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-09-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://firo.org/firo-site/pr-preview/pr-543/2025/09/28/Firo-turns-9</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://firo.org/firo-site/pr-preview/pr-543/2025/09/28/Firo-turns-9.html"><![CDATA[<p>As Firo turns 9 years old, we’re not just celebrating a birthday, we’re celebrating the dedication of the community, the resilience of the project, and the progress we’ve made together. From our early days as Zcoin to becoming Firo, we’ve stayed true to one mission: empowering people with financial privacy and building tools that put control back in their hands.</p>

<h2 id="looking-back-at-the-past-year">Looking Back at the Past Year</h2>

<p>This past year has been filled with milestones, innovations, and community-driven growth.</p>

<p><img src="/blog/assets/firo9/sparkname-activated.png" alt="Spark Name" /></p>

<p><strong><a href="/firo-site/pr-preview/pr-543/zh-cn/2025/05/28/sparknames-activated.html">Spark Names</a></strong> - One of the most exciting milestones this past year was the launch of Spark Names. This feature makes it easier for users to interact with Firo’s privacy ecosystem by allowing them to register simple, human-readable identifiers instead of relying on long, complex Spark addresses. Much like usernames, Spark Names improve accessibility and usability while still inheriting the full privacy protections of Lelantus Spark. By lowering the barrier for everyday use, Spark Names are helping to bridge the gap between powerful privacy technology and user-friendly digital cash.</p>

<p><img src="/blog/assets/firo9/pupdonation.png" alt="Power Up Privacy" /></p>

<p><strong><a href="/firo-site/pr-preview/pr-543/zh-cn/2025/04/10/firo-receive-574-xmr-donation-power-up-privacy.html">Power Up Privacy donated 574 XMR</a></strong> to the Firo Team to support our mission and is continuing to donate further funds. These funds will go directly towards strengthening Firo’s development, advancing privacy research, and driving awareness initiatives in the broader ecosystem. A heartfelt thank you to Power Up Privacy for believing in our work and contributing to the growth of privacy technologies. It is the commitment of supporters like you, along with the tireless efforts of the Firofam, that keeps us moving forward.</p>

<p><img src="/blog/assets/firo9/wizardswap-spark.png" alt="WizardSwap Spark Address" /></p>

<p><a href="https://www.wizardswap.io/"><strong>WizardSwap</strong></a> became the first swap provider to integrate Spark addresses and also Instant-Send. This means users can now swap privately and almost instantly with WizardSwap, enjoying Firo’s full privacy protections without needing extra steps. We are seeing strong swap volumes primarily people swapping from XMR into FIRO.</p>

<p><img src="/blog/assets/firo9/confidential-layer.png" alt="confidential layer" /></p>

<p>The partnership with <strong>Confidential Layer</strong>, a non-custodial bridge that enables seamless asset transfers between public blockchains and privacy-preserving blockchains, allows users to move assets securely across chains while retaining the option of privacy when they need it. This is significant because it opens the door to greater interoperability. By connecting Firo’s privacy layer with the broader blockchain ecosystem, this partnership strengthens our vision of making privacy not just a feature, but a standard. It bridges the gap between transparent and private economies, empowering users to choose confidentiality without sacrificing accessibility or usability.</p>

<p><img src="/blog/assets/firo9/firomonerokon2025.jpg" alt="Firo at Monerokon 2025" /></p>

<p>Firo attended <strong>Monerokon 2025 in Prague</strong>, where we were one of the few privacy projects with a dedicated booth. The reception was overwhelmingly positive, with many attendees from the Monero community recognizing Firo as “one of the legit ones.” It was encouraging to see so much interest at our booth, by far one of the most visited. and we look forward to fostering stronger relationships with the Monero community and beyond.</p>

<p>At <strong>ETHDam III</strong>, we explored how privacy coins like Firo can integrate into mainstream adoption without compromising their core values. The talk addressed common myths around privacy coins and highlighted practical solutions for shaping a more private future.
Watch here: <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Ty50kXR--Y8">https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Ty50kXR–Y8</a></p>

<p><strong>Biconomy Exchange listed Firo</strong> with support for Spark address withdrawals. This makes Biconomy the second centralized exchange (first being NonKYC.io with full Spark deposits and withdrawal support)  to enable users to withdraw directly to a Spark address, bringing the benefits of Firo’s cutting-edge privacy protocol to a wider audience.</p>

<p><img src="/blog/assets/firo9/firosyriaoffice.jpg" alt="Syria Firo Office" /></p>

<p>One of the most inspiring milestones this year comes directly from the community. A dedicated member in Syria has begun setting up an <strong>office to educate and onboard people to Firo</strong>, providing hands-on guidance about financial privacy and how to use cryptocurrency in their daily lives. In Syria, citizens are only allowed to withdraw around 500,000 Syrian Pounds (~38 USD) a week from their bank and still face a lot of stigma despite sanctions being lifted. Privacy crypto like Firo provides a practical solution to ease value transfer among ordinary Syrians.</p>

<p><img src="/blog/assets/firo9/Firosyria.png" alt="Syria Firo adoption" /></p>

<p>Beyond education, <strong>real-world adoption is taking shape on the ground</strong>. In Syria, one of the <strong>largest stores in Homs Governorate, Al Dhahik Commercial Complex</strong> that sells essential goods from solar panels to appliances, a <strong>household appliance store, a pharmacy, and a grocery shop</strong> are now accepting FIRO as payment. These businesses are helping to create a practical ecosystem where everyday needs can be met using private digital cash.</p>

<h2 id="a-community-that-makes-it-possible">A Community That Makes It Possible</h2>

<p>At the heart of Firo’s journey is the community. Whether it’s miners securing the network, masternodes operators, serving on the Community Fund Committee, testing new features, helping newcomers, creating Spark Names, or simply spreading the word, every contribution has strengthened the ecosystem. Firo also wouldn’t be here without the support of our partners, who have worked alongside us to advance privacy technology and adoption. To all who have stayed with us, believed in what we do, and contributed in countless ways, old and new, we thank you deeply.</p>

<h2 id="looking-forward">Looking Forward</h2>

<p>As we move into our 10th year, Firo’s mission remains clear: ensuring financial privacy is accessible to all. The road ahead is filled with exciting developments that will push Firo’s technology and usability even further.</p>

<p>Lelantus Spark remains at the core of Firo’s privacy technology, and we will continue to refine and strengthen it. This means ongoing upgrades for performance, security, and usability, ensuring it remains the gold standard in blockchain privacy.</p>

<p><strong>Spark Assets</strong> - Nearing completion, Spark Assets will allow users to issue their own privacy-preserving assets. These assets inherit the same protections as Lelantus Spark, including the ability to hide asset types ensuring full confidentiality. Importantly, all assets - including FIRO itself - contribute to a shared anonymity set, further strengthening privacy for everyone.</p>

<p><strong>Integration into Enkrypt</strong> - a multi-asset Web3 browser extension wallet, with full support for Spark features. This will make it even easier for users to access Firo’s privacy technology without installing or downloading an application.</p>

<p><strong>Curve Trees</strong> - An innovative technique for efficient membership proofs that supports a global anonymity set. This upgrade will substantially improve privacy, scalability, verification speed, and proof size, making Spark even more robust and efficient.</p>

<p>And these are just some of the improvements on the horizon. With community support and ongoing innovation, Firo will continue leading the way in financial privacy while expanding its reach and usability.</p>

<h2 id="closing-thoughts">Closing Thoughts</h2>

<p>Thank you to every member of the Firofam for being part of this journey. Nine years is a huge milestone in crypto, and it’s only possible because of the strength of this community and the vision we share. Here’s to the next chapter, and to building a future where financial privacy is the norm, not the exception.</p>

<p>Happy 9th Birthday, Firo!</p>]]></content><author><name>Augustus Jong</name></author><category term="community" /><category term="news" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[As Firo turns 9 years old, we’re not just celebrating a birthday, we’re celebrating the dedication of the community, the resilience of the project, and the progress we’ve made together. From our early days as Zcoin to becoming Firo, we’ve stayed true to one mission: empowering people with financial privacy and building tools that put control back in their hands. Looking Back at the Past Year This past year has been filled with milestones, innovations, and community-driven growth. Spark Names - One of the most exciting milestones this past year was the launch of Spark Names. This feature makes it easier for users to interact with Firo’s privacy ecosystem by allowing them to register simple, human-readable identifiers instead of relying on long, complex Spark addresses. Much like usernames, Spark Names improve accessibility and usability while still inheriting the full privacy protections of Lelantus Spark. By lowering the barrier for everyday use, Spark Names are helping to bridge the gap between powerful privacy technology and user-friendly digital cash. Power Up Privacy donated 574 XMR to the Firo Team to support our mission and is continuing to donate further funds. These funds will go directly towards strengthening Firo’s development, advancing privacy research, and driving awareness initiatives in the broader ecosystem. A heartfelt thank you to Power Up Privacy for believing in our work and contributing to the growth of privacy technologies. It is the commitment of supporters like you, along with the tireless efforts of the Firofam, that keeps us moving forward. WizardSwap became the first swap provider to integrate Spark addresses and also Instant-Send. This means users can now swap privately and almost instantly with WizardSwap, enjoying Firo’s full privacy protections without needing extra steps. We are seeing strong swap volumes primarily people swapping from XMR into FIRO. The partnership with Confidential Layer, a non-custodial bridge that enables seamless asset transfers between public blockchains and privacy-preserving blockchains, allows users to move assets securely across chains while retaining the option of privacy when they need it. This is significant because it opens the door to greater interoperability. By connecting Firo’s privacy layer with the broader blockchain ecosystem, this partnership strengthens our vision of making privacy not just a feature, but a standard. It bridges the gap between transparent and private economies, empowering users to choose confidentiality without sacrificing accessibility or usability. Firo attended Monerokon 2025 in Prague, where we were one of the few privacy projects with a dedicated booth. The reception was overwhelmingly positive, with many attendees from the Monero community recognizing Firo as “one of the legit ones.” It was encouraging to see so much interest at our booth, by far one of the most visited. and we look forward to fostering stronger relationships with the Monero community and beyond. At ETHDam III, we explored how privacy coins like Firo can integrate into mainstream adoption without compromising their core values. The talk addressed common myths around privacy coins and highlighted practical solutions for shaping a more private future. Watch here: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Ty50kXR–Y8 Biconomy Exchange listed Firo with support for Spark address withdrawals. This makes Biconomy the second centralized exchange (first being NonKYC.io with full Spark deposits and withdrawal support) to enable users to withdraw directly to a Spark address, bringing the benefits of Firo’s cutting-edge privacy protocol to a wider audience. One of the most inspiring milestones this year comes directly from the community. A dedicated member in Syria has begun setting up an office to educate and onboard people to Firo, providing hands-on guidance about financial privacy and how to use cryptocurrency in their daily lives. In Syria, citizens are only allowed to withdraw around 500,000 Syrian Pounds (~38 USD) a week from their bank and still face a lot of stigma despite sanctions being lifted. Privacy crypto like Firo provides a practical solution to ease value transfer among ordinary Syrians. Beyond education, real-world adoption is taking shape on the ground. In Syria, one of the largest stores in Homs Governorate, Al Dhahik Commercial Complex that sells essential goods from solar panels to appliances, a household appliance store, a pharmacy, and a grocery shop are now accepting FIRO as payment. These businesses are helping to create a practical ecosystem where everyday needs can be met using private digital cash. A Community That Makes It Possible At the heart of Firo’s journey is the community. Whether it’s miners securing the network, masternodes operators, serving on the Community Fund Committee, testing new features, helping newcomers, creating Spark Names, or simply spreading the word, every contribution has strengthened the ecosystem. Firo also wouldn’t be here without the support of our partners, who have worked alongside us to advance privacy technology and adoption. To all who have stayed with us, believed in what we do, and contributed in countless ways, old and new, we thank you deeply. Looking Forward As we move into our 10th year, Firo’s mission remains clear: ensuring financial privacy is accessible to all. The road ahead is filled with exciting developments that will push Firo’s technology and usability even further. Lelantus Spark remains at the core of Firo’s privacy technology, and we will continue to refine and strengthen it. This means ongoing upgrades for performance, security, and usability, ensuring it remains the gold standard in blockchain privacy. Spark Assets - Nearing completion, Spark Assets will allow users to issue their own privacy-preserving assets. These assets inherit the same protections as Lelantus Spark, including the ability to hide asset types ensuring full confidentiality. Importantly, all assets - including FIRO itself - contribute to a shared anonymity set, further strengthening privacy for everyone. Integration into Enkrypt - a multi-asset Web3 browser extension wallet, with full support for Spark features. This will make it even easier for users to access Firo’s privacy technology without installing or downloading an application. Curve Trees - An innovative technique for efficient membership proofs that supports a global anonymity set. This upgrade will substantially improve privacy, scalability, verification speed, and proof size, making Spark even more robust and efficient. And these are just some of the improvements on the horizon. With community support and ongoing innovation, Firo will continue leading the way in financial privacy while expanding its reach and usability. Closing Thoughts Thank you to every member of the Firofam for being part of this journey. Nine years is a huge milestone in crypto, and it’s only possible because of the strength of this community and the vision we share. Here’s to the next chapter, and to building a future where financial privacy is the norm, not the exception. Happy 9th Birthday, Firo!]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The 4th term of CFC members are formed!</title><link href="https://firo.org/firo-site/pr-preview/pr-543/2025/09/07/4th-term-cfc-members-formed.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The 4th term of CFC members are formed!" /><published>2025-09-07T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-09-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://firo.org/firo-site/pr-preview/pr-543/2025/09/07/4th-term-cfc-members-formed</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://firo.org/firo-site/pr-preview/pr-543/2025/09/07/4th-term-cfc-members-formed.html"><![CDATA[<p>The 7 member Community Fund Committee (“CFC”) is formed to oversee the Firo Community Fund (“FCF”) has been completed!</p>

<p>The following community members will serve as CFC members for a period of 1 year:</p>

<ul>
  <li>Firofan</li>
  <li>Rehrar</li>
  <li>Jagmot</li>
  <li>Fiendish</li>
  <li>Nrsimha</li>
  <li>Ddadybayo</li>
  <li>Centaurea</li>
</ul>

<p>The newly elected committee brings together long-standing community members, technical experts, and developers who have consistently participated in proposal reviews and guided the allocation of the Firo Community Fund.</p>

<p>We would like to extend our gratitude to the newly elected members for serving on the Firo Community Fund (FCF) and for contributing to the decentralization of funding decisions. We also sincerely thank the outgoing committee members for their dedication and service to the project.</p>

<h2 id="how-to-apply-for-funding-from-the-firo-community-fund">How to apply for funding from the Firo Community Fund</h2>

<p>Anyone is welcome to request funding from the FCF by submitting a proposal through the <a href="https://funding.firo.org/">Firo Crowdfunding System</a> and opening a <a href="https://forum.firo.org/c/fcs-proposals/16">forum thread</a> to invite community discussion. In addition, the Community Fund Committee has the authority to put forward proposals of their own for consideration.</p>

<h2 id="what-are-the-responsibilities-of-the-community-fund-committee">What are the responsibilities of the Community Fund Committee?</h2>

<ol>
  <li>To decide along with taking into account community feedback on how the Firo Community Fund should be utilised.</li>
  <li>To help evaluate community requests for funding, do due diligence of applicants applying for funding and obtain all necessary information to ensure sufficient detail for scope of work.</li>
  <li>To evaluate and approve payment of milestone requests.</li>
  <li>To make all reasonings of the CFC for approval/rejection public.</li>
  <li>CFC can request for the core team’s feedback and opinion on proposals.</li>
  <li>To always conduct themselves with professionalism without resorting to personal attacks or insults.</li>
</ol>

<h2 id="how-will-the-firo-community-fund-fcf-be-utilised">How will the Firo Community Fund (FCF) be utilised?</h2>

<ol>
  <li>FCF funds must always be utilised for the benefit of Firo. Research, development or promotional activities that do not directly benefit Firo should not be undertaken.</li>
  <li>All FCF expenditure has to be disclosed. Any proposal that does not allow this will not be able to be funded from the FCF.</li>
  <li>FCF funds should not be used for giveaways even for the purpose of promoting adoption or participation.</li>
  <li>FCF funds should not be used to host purely social events. Educational or awareness events are acceptable but must be the primary component of the event.</li>
  <li>FCF funds should be used and while there shouldn’t be a pressure to spend funds, the FCF should not be hoarded.</li>
  <li>CFC can choose to use the FCF to employ contractors to embark on specific tasks or roles that will report directly to the CFC.</li>
  <li>Should the CFC deem fit, FCF funds can be burnt by sending it to this <a href="https://explorer.firo.org/address/aFiroBurningAddressDoNotSendrPtjYA">burn address</a>.</li>
  <li>FCF funds address can be viewed <a href="https://explorer.firo.org/address/aFA2TbqG9cnhhzX5Yny2pBJRK5EaEqLCH7">here</a>.</li>
</ol>

<h2 id="where-can-i-see-the-deliberations-of-the-community-fund-committee">Where can I see the deliberations of the Community Fund Committee?</h2>

<p>All discussions of the CFC can be seen in our <a href="https://discord.gg/TGZPRbRT3Y">Discord</a> in the channel #communityfund or The <a href="https://t.me/firocfc">CFC telegram group</a> and is read-only. You will need to have verified status by passing the captcha to view the channel.</p>]]></content><author><name>Augustus Jong</name></author><category term="community" /><category term="news" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The 7 member Community Fund Committee (“CFC”) is formed to oversee the Firo Community Fund (“FCF”) has been completed! The following community members will serve as CFC members for a period of 1 year: Firofan Rehrar Jagmot Fiendish Nrsimha Ddadybayo Centaurea The newly elected committee brings together long-standing community members, technical experts, and developers who have consistently participated in proposal reviews and guided the allocation of the Firo Community Fund. We would like to extend our gratitude to the newly elected members for serving on the Firo Community Fund (FCF) and for contributing to the decentralization of funding decisions. We also sincerely thank the outgoing committee members for their dedication and service to the project. How to apply for funding from the Firo Community Fund Anyone is welcome to request funding from the FCF by submitting a proposal through the Firo Crowdfunding System and opening a forum thread to invite community discussion. In addition, the Community Fund Committee has the authority to put forward proposals of their own for consideration. What are the responsibilities of the Community Fund Committee? To decide along with taking into account community feedback on how the Firo Community Fund should be utilised. To help evaluate community requests for funding, do due diligence of applicants applying for funding and obtain all necessary information to ensure sufficient detail for scope of work. To evaluate and approve payment of milestone requests. To make all reasonings of the CFC for approval/rejection public. CFC can request for the core team’s feedback and opinion on proposals. To always conduct themselves with professionalism without resorting to personal attacks or insults. How will the Firo Community Fund (FCF) be utilised? FCF funds must always be utilised for the benefit of Firo. Research, development or promotional activities that do not directly benefit Firo should not be undertaken. All FCF expenditure has to be disclosed. Any proposal that does not allow this will not be able to be funded from the FCF. FCF funds should not be used for giveaways even for the purpose of promoting adoption or participation. FCF funds should not be used to host purely social events. Educational or awareness events are acceptable but must be the primary component of the event. FCF funds should be used and while there shouldn’t be a pressure to spend funds, the FCF should not be hoarded. CFC can choose to use the FCF to employ contractors to embark on specific tasks or roles that will report directly to the CFC. Should the CFC deem fit, FCF funds can be burnt by sending it to this burn address. FCF funds address can be viewed here. Where can I see the deliberations of the Community Fund Committee? All discussions of the CFC can be seen in our Discord in the channel #communityfund or The CFC telegram group and is read-only. You will need to have verified status by passing the captcha to view the channel.]]></summary></entry></feed>